[
  {
    "id": 0,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables\n",
    "question": "A cargo helicopter delivers only 100-pound packages and 120-pound packages. For each delivery trip, the helicopter must carry at least 10 packages, and the total weight of the packages can be at most 1,100 pounds. What is the maximum number of 120-pound packages that the helicopter can carry per trip?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Let a equal the number of 120-pound packages, and let b equal the number of 100-pound packages. It’s given that the total weight of the packages can be at most 1,100 pounds: the inequality 120a + 100b <= 1100 represents this situation. It’s also given that the helicopter must carry at least 10\npackages: the inequality a + b >= 10 represents this situation. Values of a and b that satisfy these two inequalities represent the allowable numbers of 120-pound packages and 100-pound packages the helicopter can transport. To maximize the number of 120-pound packages, a, in the helicopter, the number of 100-pound packages, b, in the helicopter needs to be minimized. Expressing b in terms of a in the second inequality yields b >= 10 - a, so the minimum value of b is equal to 10 - a. Substituting 10 - a for b in the first inequality results in 120a + 100(10 - a) <= 1100. Using the distributive property to rewrite this inequality yields 120a + 1000 - 100a <= 1100, or 20a + 1000. Subtracting 1,000 from both sides of this inequality yields 20a <= 100. Dividing both sides of this inequality by 20 results in a <= 5. This means that the maximum number of 120-pound packages that the helicopter can carry per trip is 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 1,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If , 2x+3=9, what is the value of 6x-1?",
    "answer": "17",
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 17. It’s given that 2x + 3 = 9. Multiplying each side of this equation by 3 yields 3(2x + 3) = 3(9), or 6x + 9 = 27. Subtracting 10 from each side of this equation yields 6x + 9 - 10 = 27 - 10, or 6x - 1 = 17. Therefore, the value of 6x - 1 is 17."
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 4x - 28 = -24, what is the value of x - 7?",
    "answer": "-6",
    "explanation": "Dividing all terms in the given equation by 4 yields 4x / 4 - 28 / 4 = -24 / 4, or x - 7 = -6. Therefore, the value of x - 7 is -6."
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "7(2x - 3) = 63 Which equation has the same solution as the given equation?",
    "answer": "2x - 3 = 9",
    "explanation": "Dividing each side of the given equation by 7 yields (7(2x - 3)) / 7 = 63 / 7, or 2x - 3 = 9. Therefore, the equation 2x - 3 = 9 is equivalent to the given equation and has the same solution."
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "What value of p satisfies the equation 5p + 180 = 250?",
    "answer": "14",
    "explanation": "Subtracting 180 from both sides of the given equation yields 5p = 70. Dividing both sides of this equation by 5 yields p = 14. Therefore, the value of p that satisfies the equation 5p + 180 = 250 is 14."
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 3x - 27 = 24, what is the value of x - 9?",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "Dividing each side of the given equation by 3 yields x - 9 = 8. Therefore, the value of x - 9 is 8."
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "John paid a total of $165 for a microscope by making a down payment of $37 plus p monthly payments of $16 each. Which of the following equations represents this situation?",
    "answer": "16p + 37 = 165",
    "explanation": "t's given that John made a $16 payment each month for p months. The total amount of these payments can be represented by the expression 16p. The down payment can be added to that amount to find the total amount John paid, yielding the expression 16p + 37. It's given that John paid a total of $165. Therefore, the expression for the total amount John paid can be set equal to that amount, yielding the equation 16p + 37 = 165."
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "3x + 21 = 3x + k In the given equation, k is a constant. The equation has infinitely many solutions. What is the value of k?",
    "answer": "21",
    "explanation": "It's given that the equation 3x + 21 = 3x + k has infinitely many solutions. If an equation in one variable has infinitely many solutions, then the equation is true for any value of the variable. Subtracting 3x from both sides of the given equation yields k = 21. Since this equation must be true for any value of x, the value of k is 21."
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If x / 8 = 5, what is the value of 8 / x?",
    "answer": "2025-01-05 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "Since the number 5 can also be written as 5/1, the given equation can also be written as x / 8 = 5 / 1. This equation is equivalent to 8 / x = 1/5. Therefore, the value of 8 / x is 1/5. Note that 1/5 and .2 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer. Alternate approach: Multiplying both sides of the equation x / 8 = 5 by 8 yields x = 40. Substituting 40 for x into the expression 8 / x yields 8 / 40, or 1/5."
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 3x = 30, what is the value of 3x - 12?",
    "answer": "18",
    "explanation": "Subtracting 12 from each side of the given equation yields 3x - 12 = 30 - 12, or 3x - 12 = 18. Therefore, the value of 3x - 12 is 18."
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "8x - 7x + 130 = 260 What value of x is the solution to the given equation?",
    "answer": "130",
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 130. It's given that 8x - 7x + 130 = 260. Combining like terms on the left-hand side of this equation yields x + 130 = 260. Subtracting 130 from each side of this equation yields x = 130. Therefore, the value of x that's the solution to the given equation is 130."
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "(p + 3) + 8 = 10 What value of p is the solution to the given equation?",
    "answer": "-1",
    "explanation": "Subtracting 8 from both sides of the given equation yields p + 3 = 2. Subtracting 3 from both sides of this equation yields p = -1."
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "4x + 5 = 165 What is the solution to the given equation?",
    "answer": "40",
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 40. Subtracting 5 from both sides of the given equation yields 4x = 160. Dividing both sides of this equation by 4 yields x = 40. Therefore, the solution to the given equation is 40."
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "The perimeter of an isosceles triangle is 83 inches. Each of the two congruent sides of the triangle has a length of 24 inches. What is the length, in inches, of the third side?",
    "answer": "35",
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 35. It's given that the perimeter of an isosceles triangle is 83 inches and that each of the two congruent sides has a length of 24 inches. The perimeter of a triangle is the sum of the lengths of its three sides. The equation 24 + 24 + x = 83 can be used to represent this situation, where x is the length, in inches, of the third side. Combining like terms on the left-hand side of this equation yields 48 + x = 83. Subtracting 48 from both sides of this equation yields x = 35. Therefore, the length, in inches, of the third side is 35."
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "4x / 5 = 20 In the equation above, what is the value of x?",
    "answer": "25",
    "explanation": " Multiplying both sides of the equation by 5 results in 4x = 100. Dividing both sides of the resulting equation by 4 results in x = 25."
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "One pound of grapes costs $2. At this rate, how many dollars will c pounds of grapes cost?",
    "answer": "2c",
    "explanation": "If one pound of grapes costs $2, two pounds of grapes will cost 2 times $2, three pounds of grapes will cost 3 times $2, and so on. Therefore, c pounds of grapes will cost c times $2, which is 2c dollars."
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "A principal used a total of 25 flags that were either blue or yellow for field day. The principal used 20 blue flags. How many yellow flags were used?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "It's given that a principal used a total of 25 blue flags and yellow flags. It's also given that of the 25 flags used, 20 flags were blue. Subtracting the number of blue flags used from the total number of flags used results in the number of yellow flags used. It follows that the number of yellow flags used is 25 - 20, or 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "8x = 88 What value of x is the solution to the given equation? ",
    "answer": "11",
    "explanation": "Dividing both sides of the given equation by 8 yields x = 11. Therefore, 11 is the solution to the given equation."
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If x = 7, what is the value of x + 20?",
    "answer": "27",
    "explanation": "It’s given that x = 7. Substituting 7 for x into the given expression x + 20 yields 7 + 20, which is equivalent to 27."
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "A gym charges its members a onetime $36 enrollment fee and a membership fee of $19 per month. If there are no charges other than the enrollment fee and the membership fee, after how many months will a member have been charged a total of $188 at the gym?",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "It's given that a gym charges its members a onetime $36 enrollment fee and a membership fee of $19 per month. Let x represent the number of months at the gym after which a member will have been charged a total of $188. If there are no charges other than the enrollment fee and the membership fee, the equation 36 + 19x = 188 can be used to represent this situation. Subtracting 36 from both sides of this equation yields 19x = 152. Dividing both sides of this equation by 19 yields x = 8. Therefore, a member will have been charged a total of $188 after 8 months at the gym."
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "3 more than 8 times a number x is equal to 83. Which equation represents this situation?",
    "answer": "8x + 3 = 83",
    "explanation": "The given phrase “8 times a number x” can be represented by the expression 8x. The given phrase “3 more than” indicates an increase of 3 to a quantity. Therefore “3 more than 8 times a number x” can be represented by the expression 8x + 3. Since it's given that 3 more than 8 times a number x is equal to 83, it follows that 8x + 3 is equal to 83, or 8x + 3 = 83. Therefore, the equation that represents this situation is 8x + 3 = 83."
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "4x + 6 = 18 Which equation has the same solution as the given equation?",
    "answer": "4x = 12",
    "explanation": "Subtracting 6 from both sides of the given equation yields 4x = 12, which is the equation given in choice C. Since this equation is equivalent to the given equation, it has the same solution as the given equation."
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Nasir bought 9 storage bins that were each the same price. He used a coupon for $63 off the entire purchase. The cost for the entire purchase after using the coupon was $27. What was the original price, in dollars, for 1 storage bin?",
    "answer": "10",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the cost for the entire purchase was $27 after a coupon was used for $63 off the entire purchase. Adding the amount of the coupon to the purchase price yields 27 + 63 = 90. Thus, the cost for the entire purchase before using the coupon was $90. It’s given that Nasir bought 9 storage bins. The original price for 1 storage bin can be found by dividing the total cost by 9. Therefore, the original price, in dollars, for 1 storage bin is 10."
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "10 = 2x + 4 How many solutions exist to the equation shown above?",
    "answer": "Exactly 1",
    "explanation": "Subtracting 4 from each side of the given equation yields 6 = 2x, or x = 3, so the equation has a unique solution of x = 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "x + 40 = 95 What value of x is the solution to the given equation?",
    "answer": "55",
    "explanation": " Subtracting 40 from both sides of the given equation yields x = 55. Therefore, the value of x is 55."
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 2x = 12, what is the value of 9x?",
    "answer": "54",
    "explanation": "Dividing both sides of the given equation by 2 yields x = 6. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 9 yields 9x = 54. Thus, the value of 9x is 54."
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Cathy has n CDs. Gerry has 3 more than twice the number of CDs that Cathy has. In terms of n, how many CDs does Gerry have?",
    "answer": "2n + 3",
    "explanation": "The term 2n represents twice the number of CDs that Cathy has, and adding 3 represents 3 more than that amount."
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 7x = 28, what is the value of 8x?",
    "answer": "32",
    "explanation": "Dividing both sides of the given equation 7x = 28 by 7 yields x = 4. Substituting 4 for x in the expression 8x yields 8(4), which is equivalent to 32."
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 4x + 2 = 12, what is the value of 16x + 8?",
    "answer": "48",
    "explanation": "Multiplying both sides of the given equation by 4 yields (4)(4x + 2) = (4)(12), or 16x + 8 = 48. Therefore, the value of 16x + 8 is 48."
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "On the first day of a semester, a film club has 90 members. Each day after the first day of the semester, 10 new members join the film club. If no members leave the film club, how many total members will the film club have 4 days after the first day of the semester?",
    "answer": "130",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the film club has 90 members on the first day of a semester, and 10 new members join the film club each day after the first day of the semester. This means that after 4 days, 4 x 10, or 40, new members will have joined the club. Adding 40 members to the original 90 club members yields 130 members. Thus, the film club will have 130 total members 4 days after the first day of the semester."
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 6 + x = 9, what is the value of 18 + 3x?",
    "answer": "27",
    "explanation": "Multiplying both sides of the given equation by 3 yields 3(6 + x) = 3(9), or 18 + 3x = 27. Therefore, the value of 18 + 3x is 27."
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "For what value of w does w - 10 = 2(w + 5)?",
    "answer": "-20",
    "explanation": "To solve the equation, use the distributive property to multiply on the right-hand side of the equation which gives w - 10 = 2w + 10. Subtract w from both sides of the equation, which gives -10 = w + 10. Finally, subtract 10 from both sides of the equation, which gives -20 = w."
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "The perimeter of an isosceles triangle is 36 feet. Each of the two congruent sides of the triangle has a length of 10 feet. What is the length, in feet, of the third side?",
    "answer": "16",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the perimeter of an isosceles triangle is 36 feet and that each of the two congruent sides has a length of 10 feet. The perimeter of a triangle is the sum of the lengths of its three sides. The equation 10 + 10 + x = 36 can be used to represent this situation, where x is the length, in feet, of the third side. Combining like terms on the left-hand side of this equation yields 20 + x = 36. Subtracting 20 from each side of this equation yields x = 16. Therefore, the length, in feet, of the third side is 16."
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "13x = 112 - x What value of x is the solution to the given equation?",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "Adding x to both sides of the given equation yields 14x = 112. Dividing both sides of this equation by 14 yields x = 8."
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 6n = 12, what is the value of n + 4?",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Dividing both sides of the equation 6n = 12 by 6 yields n = 2. Substituting 2 for n in the expression n + 4 yields 2 + 4, or 6."
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 2n/5 = 10, what is the value of 2n - 1?",
    "answer": "49",
    "explanation": "Multiplying both sides of the given equation by 5 yields 2n = 50. Substituting 50 for 2n in the expression 2n - 1 yields 50 - 1 = 49."
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 1/2 x - 1/6 x = 1, what is the value of x?",
    "answer": "3",
    "explanation": "To make it easier to add like terms on the left-hand side of the given equation, both sides of the equation can be multiplied by 6, which is the lowest common denominator of 1/2 and 1/6. This yields 3x - x = 6, which can be rewritten as 2x = 6. Dividing both sides of this equation by 2 yields x = 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "A librarian has 43 books to distribute to a group of children. If he gives each child 2 books, he will have 7 books left over. How many children are in the group?",
    "answer": "18",
    "explanation": "Subtracting the number of books left over from the total number of books results in 43 - 7 = 36, which is the number of books distributed. Dividing the number of books distributed by the number of books given to each child results in 36 / 2 = 18."
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Henry receives a $60.00 gift card to pay for movies online. He uses his gift card to buy 3 movies for $7.50 each. If he spends the rest of his gift card balance on renting movies for $1.50 each, how many movies can Henry rent?",
    "answer": "25",
    "explanation": "It's given that Henry uses his $60.00 gift card to buy 3 movies for $7.50 each. Therefore, Henry spends 3($7.50), or $22.50, of his $60.00 gift card to buy 3 movies. After buying 3 movies with his $60.00 gift card, Henry has a gift card balance of $60.00 - $22.50, or $37.50. It's also given that Henry spends the rest of his gift card balance on renting movies for $1.50 each. Therefore, Henry can rent $37.50 / $1.50, or 25, movies."
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "A rocket contained 467,000 kilograms (kg) of propellant before launch. Exactly 21 seconds after launch, 362,105 kg of this propellant remained. On average, approximately how much propellant, in kg, did the rocket burn each second after launch?",
    "answer": "4995",
    "explanation": "It's given that the rocket contained 467,000 kg of propellant before launch and had 362,105 kg remaining exactly 21 seconds after launch. Finding the difference between the amount, in kg, of propellant before launch and the remaining amount, in kg, of propellant after launch gives the amount, in kg, of propellant burned during the 21 seconds: 467,000 - 362,105 = 104,895. Dividing the amount of propellant burned by the number of seconds yields 104,895 / 21 = 4,995. Thus, an average of 4,995 kg of propellant burned each second after launch."
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "k + 12 = 336 What is the solution to the given equation?",
    "answer": "324",
    "explanation": "Subtracting 12 from both sides of the given equation yields k = 324. Therefore, the solution to the given equation is 324."
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 3x + 2 = 8, what is the value of 9x + 6?",
    "answer": "24",
    "explanation": "Multiplying both sides of the given equation by 3 yields 3(3x + 2) = 24. Using the distributive property to rewrite the left-hand side of this equation yields 9x + 6 = 24."
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "3x + 5(x + 4) = 76 What value of x is the solution to the given equation?",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "Applying the distributive property on the left-hand side of the given equation yields 3x + 5x + 20 = 76, or 8x + 20 = 76. Subtracting 20 from each side of this equation yields 8x = 56. Dividing each side of this equation by 8 yields x = 7."
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 2 + x = 60, what is the value of 16 + 8x?",
    "answer": "480",
    "explanation": "Multiplying both sides of the given equation by 8 yields 8(2 + x) = 8(60), or 16 + 8x = 480. Therefore, if 2 + x = 60, the value of 16 + 8x is 480."
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If x = 40, what is the value of x + 6?",
    "answer": "46",
    "explanation": "It's given that x = 40. Adding 6 to both sides of this equation yields x + 6 = 40 + 6, or x + 6 = 46. Therefore, the value of x + 6 is 46."
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "What is the solution to the equation 2x + 3 = 7?",
    "answer": "2",
    "explanation": "Subtracting 3 from both sides of the given equation yields 2x = 4. Dividing both sides by 2 results in x = 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 5x = 20, what is the value of 15x?",
    "answer": "60",
    "explanation": "It’s given that 5x = 20. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 3 yields 15x = 60. Therefore, the value of 15x is 60."
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "6x + k = 6x + 5 In the given equation, k is a constant. If the equation has infinitely many solutions, what is the value of k?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Subtracting 6x from both sides of the given equation gives k = 5, so for any value of x, 6x + k = 6x + 5 if and only if k = 5. Therefore, if the given equation has infinitely many solutions, the value of k is 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "A manager is responsible for ordering supplies for a shaved ice shop. The shop's inventory starts with 4,500 paper cups, and the manager estimates that 70 of these paper cups are used each day. Based on this estimate, in how many days will the supply of paper cups reach 1,700?",
    "answer": "40",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the shop’s inventory starts with 4,500 paper cups and that the manager estimates that 70 of these paper cups are used each day. Let x represent the number of days in which the estimated supply of paper cups will reach 1,700. The equation 4,500 - 70x = 1,700 represents this situation. Subtracting 4,500 from both sides of this equation yields -70x = -2,800. Dividing both sides of this equation by -70 yields x = 40. Therefore, based on this estimate, the supply of paper cups will reach 1,700 in 40 days."
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "3(2x - 6) - 11 = 4(x - 3) + 6 If x is the solution to the equation above, what is the value of x - 3?",
    "answer": "17/2",
    "explanation": "Because 2 is a factor of both 2x and 6, the expression 2x - 6 can be rewritten as 2(x - 3). Substituting 2(x - 3) for (2x - 6) on the left-hand side of the given equation yields 3(2(x - 3)) - 11 = 4(x - 3) + 6, or 6(x - 3) - 11 = 4(x - 3) + 6. Subtracting 4(x - 3) from both sides of this equation yields 2(x - 3) - 11 = 6. Adding 11 to both sides of this equation yields 2(x - 3) = 17. Dividing both sides of this equation by 2 yields x - 3 = 17/2. Alternate approach: Distributing 3 to the quantity (2x - 6) on the left-hand side of the given equation and distributing 4 to the quantity (x - 3) on the right-hand side yields 6x - 18 - 11 = 4x - 12 + 6, or 6x - 29 = 4x - 6. Subtracting 4x from both sides of this equation yields 2x - 29 = -6. Adding 29 to both sides of this equation yields 2x = 23. Dividing both sides of this equation by 2 yields x = 23/2. Therefore, the value of x - 3 is 23/2 - 3, or 17/2."
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "2n + 6 = 14 A tree had a height of 6 feet when it was planted. The equation above can be used to find how many years n it took the tree to reach a height of 14 feet. Which of the following is the best interpretation of the number 2 in this context?",
    "answer": "The average number of feet that the tree grew per year",
    "explanation": "The height of the tree at a given time is equal to its height when it was planted plus the number of feet that the tree grew. In the given equation, 14 represents the height of the tree at the given time, and 6 represents the height of the tree when it was planted. It follows that 2n represents the number of feet the tree grew from the time it was planted until the time it reached a height of 14 feet. Since n represents the number of years between the given time and the time the tree was planted, 2 must represent the average number of feet the tree grew each year."
  },
  {
    "id": 51,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "2x + 16 = a(x + 8) In the given equation, a is a constant. If the equation has infinitely many solutions, what is the value of a?",
    "answer": "2",
    "explanation": "An equation with one variable, x, has infinitely many solutions only when both sides of the equation are equal for any defined value of x. It's given that 2x + 16 = a(x + 8), where a is a constant. This equation can be rewritten as 2(x + 8) = a(x + 8). If this equation has infinitely many solutions, then both sides of this equation are equal for any defined value of x. Both sides of this equation are equal for any defined value of x when 2 = a. Therefore, if the equation has infinitely many solutions, the value of a is 2. Alternate approach: If the given equation, 2x + 16 = a(x + 8), has infinitely many solutions, then both sides of this equation are equal for any value of x. If x = 0, then substituting 0 for x in 2x + 16 = a(x + 8) yields 2(0) + 16 = a(0 + 8), or 16 = 8a. Dividing both sides of this equation by 8 yields 2 = a."
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "(b - 2)x = 8 In the given equation, b is a constant. If the equation has no solution, what is the value of b?",
    "answer": "2",
    "explanation": "This equation has no solution when there is no value of x that produces a true statement. Solving the given equation for x by dividing both sides by (b - 2) gives x = 8/(b - 2). When (b - 2) = 0, the right-hand side of this equation will be undefined, and the equation will have no solution. Therefore, when b = 2, there is no value of x that satisfies the given equation."
  },
  {
    "id": 53,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "a(3 - x) - b = -1 - 2x In the equation above, a and b are constants. If the equation has infinitely many solutions, what are the values of a and b?",
    "answer": "a = 2 and b = 7",
    "explanation": "Distributing the a on the left-hand side of the equation gives 3a - b - ax = -1 - 2x. Rearranging the terms in each side of the equation yields -ax + 3a - b = -2x - 1. Since the equation has infinitely many solutions, it follows that the coefficients of x and the free terms on both sides must be equal. That is, -a = -2, or a = 2, and 3a - b = -1. Substituting 2 for a in the equation 3a - b = -1 gives 3(2) - b = -1, so b = 7."
  },
  {
    "id": 54,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "An agricultural scientist studying the growth of corn plants recorded the height of a corn plant at the beginning of a study and the height of the plant each day for the next 12 days. The scientist found that the height of the plant increased by an average of 1.20 centimeters per day for the 12 days. If the height of the plant on the last day of the study was 36.8 centimeters, what was the height, in centimeters, of the corn plant at the beginning of the study?",
    "answer": "22.4",
    "explanation": "If the height of the plant increased by an average of 1.20 centimeters per day for 12 days, then its total growth over the 12 days was (1.20)(12) = 14.4 centimeters. The plant was 36.8 centimeters tall after 12 days, so at the beginning of the study its height was 36.8 - 14.4 = 22.4 centimeters. Note that 22.4 and 112/5 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer. Alternate approach: The equation 36.8 = 12(1.20) + h can be used to represent this situation, where h is the height of the plant, in centimeters, at the beginning of the study. Solving this equation for h yields 22.4 centimeters."
  },
  {
    "id": 55,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 4x - 1/2 = -5, what is the value of 8x - 1?",
    "answer": "-10",
    "explanation": "Multiplying the given equation by 2 on each side yields 2(4x - 1/2) = 2(-5). Applying the distributive property, this equation can be rewritten as 8x - 1 = -10."
  },
  {
    "id": 56,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "2(p+1) + 8(p-1) = 5p What value of p is the solution of the equation above?",
    "answer": "1.2",
    "explanation": "One way to solve the equation 2(p + 1) + 8(p - 1) = 5p is to first distribute the terms outside the parentheses to the terms inside the parentheses: 2p + 2 + 8p - 8 = 5p. Next, combine like terms on the left side of the equal sign: 10p - 6 = 5p. Subtracting 10p from both sides yields -6 = -5p. Finally, dividing both sides by -5 gives p = 6/5, which is equivalent to p = 1.2. Note that 1.2 and 6/5 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 57,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 5(x + 4) = 4(x + 4) + 29, what is the value of x + 4?",
    "answer": "29",
    "explanation": "Subtracting 4(x + 4) from both sides of the given equation yields 1(x + 4) = 29, or x + 4 = 29. Therefore, the value of x + 4 is 29."
  },
  {
    "id": 58,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "A line segment that has a length of 115 centimeters (cm) is divided into three parts. One part is 47 cm long. The other two parts have lengths that are equal to each other. What is the length, in cm, of one of the other two parts of equal length?",
    "answer": "34",
    "explanation": "It’s given that a line segment has a length of 115 cm and is divided into three parts, where one part is 47 cm long and the other two parts have lengths that are equal. If x represents the length, in cm, of each of the two parts of equal length, then the equation 47 + x + x = 115, or 47 + 2x = 115, represents this situation. Subtracting 47 from each side of this equation yields 2x = 68. Dividing each side of this equation by 2 yields x = 34. Therefore, the length, in cm, of one of the two parts of equal length is 34."
  },
  {
    "id": 59,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 2(3t-10) + t = 40 + 4t, what is the value of 3t?",
    "answer": "60",
    "explanation": "Subtracting t from both sides of the given equation yields 2(3t - 10) = 40 + 3t. Applying the distributive property to the left-hand side of this equation yields 6t - 20 = 40 + 3t. Adding 20 to both sides of this equation yields 6t = 60 + 3t. Subtracting 3t from both sides of this equation yields 3t = 60. Therefore, the value of 3t is 60."
  },
  {
    "id": 60,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Megan’s regular wage at her job is p dollars per hour for the first 8 hours of work in a day plus 1.5 times her regular hourly wage for work in excess of 8 hours that day. On a given day, Megan worked for 10 hours, and her total earnings for that day were $137.50. What is Megan’s regular hourly wage?",
    "answer": "12.5",
    "explanation": "Since p represents Megan’s regular pay per hour, 1.5p represents the pay per hour in excess of 8 hours. Since Megan worked for 10 hours, she must have been paid p dollars per hour for 8 of the hours plus 1.5p dollars per hour for the remaining 2 hours. Therefore, since Megan earned $137.50 for the 10 hours, the situation can be represented by the equation 137.5 = 8p + 2(1.5)p. Distributing the 2 in the equation gives 137.5 = 8p + 3p, and combining like terms gives 137.5 = 11p. Dividing both sides by 11 gives p = 12.5. Therefore, Megan’s regular wage is $12.50."
  },
  {
    "id": 61,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "66x = 66x How many solutions does the given equation have?",
    "answer": "Infinitely many",
    "explanation": "If the two sides of a linear equation are equivalent, then the equation is true for any value. If an equation is true for any value, it has infinitely many solutions. Since the two sides of the given linear equation 66x = 66x are equivalent, the given equation has infinitely many solutions."
  },
  {
    "id": 62,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "A candle is made of 17 ounces of wax. When the candle is burning, the amount of wax in the candle decreases by 1 ounce every 4 hours. If 6 ounces of wax remain in this candle, for how many hours has it been burning?",
    "answer": "44",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the candle starts with 17 ounces of wax and has 6 ounces of wax remaining after a period of time has passed. The amount of wax the candle has lost during the time period can be found by subtracting the remaining amount of wax from the amount of wax the candle was made of, which yields 17 - 6 ounces, or 11 ounces. This means the candle loses 11 ounces of wax during that period of time. It’s given that the amount of wax decreases by 1 ounce every 4 hours. If h represents the number of hours the candle has been burning, it follows that 1/4 = 11/h. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 4h yields h = 44. Therefore, the candle has been burning for 44 hours."
  },
  {
    "id": 63,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 2(x - 5) + 3(x - 5) = 10, what is the value of x - 5?",
    "answer": "2",
    "explanation": "Adding the like terms on the left-hand side of the given equation yields 5(x - 5) = 10. Dividing both sides of this equation by 5 yields x - 5 = 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 64,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "1/4 (x + 5) - 1/3 (x + 5) = -7 What value of x is the solution to the given equation?",
    "answer": "79",
    "explanation": "For the given equation, (x + 5) is a factor of both terms on the left-hand side. Therefore, the given equation can be rewritten as (1/4 - 1/3)(x + 5) = -7, or (3/12 - 4/12)(x + 5) = -7, which is equivalent to -1/12 (x + 5) = -7. Multiplying both sides of this equation by -12 yields x + 5 = 84. Subtracting 5 from both sides of this equation yields x = 79."
  },
  {
    "id": 65,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "The width of a rectangular dance floor is w feet. The length of the floor is 6 feet longer than its width. Which of the following expresses the perimeter, in feet, of the dance floor in terms of w?",
    "answer": "4w + 12",
    "explanation": "It is given that the width of the dance floor is w feet. The length is 6 feet longer than the width; therefore, the length of the dance floor is w + 6. So the perimeter is w + w + (w + 6) + (w + 6) = 4w + 12."
  },
  {
    "id": 66,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "4x + 12 = a(x + 3)/2 In the given equation, a is a constant. If the equation has infinitely many solutions, what is the value of a?",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "If an equation has infinitely many solutions, then the two sides of the equation must be equivalent. Multiplying each side of the given equation by 2 yields 8x + 24 = a(x + 3). Since 8 is a common factor of both terms on the left-hand side of this equation, the equation can be rewritten as 8(x + 3) = a(x + 3). The two sides of this equation are equivalent when a = 8. Therefore, if the given equation has infinitely many solutions, the value of a is 8. Alternate approach: If the given equation, 4x + 12 = a(x + 3)/2, has infinitely many solutions, then both sides of this equation are equal for any value of x. If x = 0, then substituting 0 for x in the given equation yields 4(0) + 12 = a(0 + 3)/2, or 12 = 3/2 a. Dividing both sides of this equation by 3/2 yields 8 = a."
  },
  {
    "id": 67,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "5(t + 3) - 7(t + 3) = 38 What value of t is the solution to the given equation?",
    "answer": "-22",
    "explanation": "The given equation can be rewritten as -2(t + 3) = 38. Dividing both sides of this equation by -2 yields t + 3 = -19. Subtracting 3 from both sides of this equation yields t = -22. Therefore, -22 is the value of t that is the solution to the given equation."
  },
  {
    "id": 68,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "A certain product costs a company $65 to make. The product is sold by a salesperson who earns a commission that is equal to 20% of the sales price of the product. The profit the company makes for each unit is equal to the sales price minus the combined cost of making the product and the commission. If the sales price of the product is $100, which of the following equations gives the number of units, u, of the product the company sold to make a profit of $6,840?",
    "answer": "(100(1 - 0.2) - 65)u = 6,840",
    "explanation": "The sales price of one unit of the product is given as $100. Because the salesperson is awarded a commission equal to 20% of the sales price, the expression 100(1 - 0.2) gives the sales price of one unit after the commission is deducted. It is also given that the profit is equal to the sales price minus the combined cost of making the product, or $65, and the commission: 100(1 - 0.2) - 65. Multiplying this expression by u gives the profit of u units: (100(1 - 0.2) - 65)u. Finally, it is given that the profit for u units is $6,840; therefore (100(1 - 0.2) - 65)u = 6,840."
  },
  {
    "id": 69,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "3(kx + 13) = 48/17x + 36 In the given equation, k is a constant. The equation has no solution. What is the value of k?",
    "answer": ".9411, .9412, 16/17",
    "explanation": "It's given that the equation 3(kx + 13) = 48/17x + 36 has no solution. A linear equation in the form ax + b = cx + d, where a, b, c, and d are constants, has no solution only when the coefficients of x on each side of the equation are equal and the constant terms aren't equal. Dividing both sides of the given equation by 3 yields kx + 13 = 16/17x + 12. Since the coefficients of x on each side of the equation must be equal, it follows that the value of k is 16/17. Note that 16/17, .9411, .9412, and 0.941 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 70,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "How many solutions does the equation 10(15x - 9) = -15(6 - 10x) have?",
    "answer": "Infinitely many",
    "explanation": "Applying the distributive property to each side of the given equation yields 150x - 90 = -90 + 150x. Applying the commutative property of addition to the right-hand side of this equation yields 150x - 90 = 150x - 90. Since the two sides of the equation are equivalent, this equation is true for any value of x. Therefore, the given equation has infinitely many solutions."
  },
  {
    "id": 71,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Alan drives an average of 100 miles each week. His car can travel an average of 25 miles per gallon of gasoline. Alan would like to reduce his weekly expenditure on gasoline by $5. Assuming gasoline costs $4 per gallon, which equation can Alan use to determine how many fewer average miles, m, he should drive each week?",
    "answer": "(4/25)m = 5",
    "explanation": "Since gasoline costs $4 per gallon, and since Alan’s car travels an average of 25 miles per gallon, the expression 4/25 gives the cost, in dollars per mile, to drive the car. Multiplying 4/25 by m gives the cost for Alan to drive m miles in his car. Alan wants to reduce his weekly spending by $5, so setting (4/25)m equal to 5 gives the number of miles, m, by which he must reduce his driving."
  },
  {
    "id": 72,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "A factory makes 9-inch, 7-inch, and 4-inch concrete screws. During a certain day, the number of 9-inch concrete screws that the factory makes is 5 times the number n of 7-inch concrete screws, and the number of 4-inch concrete screws is 22. During this day, the factory makes 100 concrete screws total. Which equation represents this situation?",
    "answer": "6n + 22 = 100",
    "explanation": "It's given that during a certain day at a factory, the number of 7-inch concrete screws the factory makes is n and the number of 4-inch concrete screws the factory makes is 22. It's also given that during this day the number of 9-inch concrete screws the factory makes is 5 times the number of 7-inch concrete screws, or 5n. Therefore, the total number of 7-inch, 9-inch, and 4-inch concrete screws is n + 5n + 22, or 6n + 22. It's given that during this day, the factory makes 100 concrete screws total. Thus, the equation 6n + 22 = 100 represents this situation."
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Hector used a tool called an auger to remove corn from a storage bin at a constant rate. The bin contained 24,000 bushels of corn when Hector began to use the auger. After 5 hours of using the auger, 19,350 bushels of corn remained in the bin. If the auger continues to remove corn at this rate, what is the total number of hours Hector will have been using the auger when 12,840 bushels of corn remain in the bin?",
    "answer": "12",
    "explanation": "After using the auger for 5 hours, Hector had removed 24,000 - 19,350 = 4,650 bushels of corn from the storage bin. During the 5-hour period, the auger removed corn from the bin at a constant rate of 4,650/5 = 930 bushels per hour. Assuming the auger continues to remove corn at this rate, after x hours it will have removed 930x bushels of corn. Because the bin contained 24,000 bushels of corn when Hector started using the auger, the equation 24,000 - 930x = 12,840 can be used to find the number of hours, x, Hector will have been using the auger when 12,840 bushels of corn remain in the bin. Subtracting 12,840 from both sides of this equation and adding 930x to both sides of the equation yields 11,160 = 930x. Dividing both sides of this equation by 930 yields x = 12. Therefore, Hector will have been using the auger for 12 hours when 12,840 bushels of corn remain in the storage bin."
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "How many solutions does the equation 12(x - 3) = -3(x + 12) have?",
    "answer": "Exactly one",
    "explanation": "Distributing 12 on the left-hand side and -3 on the right-hand side of the given equation yields 12x - 36 = -3x - 36. Adding 3x to each side of this equation yields 15x - 36 = -36. Adding 36 to each side of this equation yields 15x = 0. Dividing each side of this equation by 15 yields x = 0. This means that 0 is the only solution to the given equation. Therefore, the given equation has exactly one solution."
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "The Townsend Realty Group invested in the five different properties listed in the table above. The table shows the amount, in dollars, the company paid for each property and the corresponding monthly rental price, in dollars, the company charges for the property at each of the five locations. Townsend Realty purchased the Glenview Street property and received a 40% discount off the original price along with an additional 20% off the discounted price for purchasing the property in cash. Which of the following best approximates the original price, in dollars, of the Glenview Street property?",
    "answer": "291700",
    "explanation": "Let x be the original price, in dollars, of the Glenview Street property. After the 40% discount, the price of the property became 0.6x dollars, and after the additional 20% off the discounted price, the price of the property became 0.8(0.6x). Thus, in terms of the original price of the property, x, the purchase price of the property is 0.48x. It follows that 0.48x = 140,000. Solving this equation for x gives x = 291,666.66. Therefore, of the given choices, 291,700 best approximates the original price of the Glenview Street property."
  },
  {
    "id": 76,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Each side of a 30-sided polygon has one of three lengths. The number of sides with length 8 centimeters (cm) is 5 times the number of sides n with length 3 cm. There are 6 sides with length 4 cm. Which equation must be true for the value of n?",
    "answer": "6n + 6 = 30",
    "explanation": "It’s given that each side of a 30-sided polygon has one of three lengths. It’s also given that the number of sides with length 8 cm is 5 times the number of sides n with length 3 cm. Therefore, there are 5 * n, or 5n, sides with length 8 cm. It’s also given that there are 6 sides with length 4 cm. Therefore, the number of 3 cm, 4 cm, and 8 cm sides are n, 6, and 5n, respectively. Since there are a total of 30 sides, the equation n + 6 + 5n = 30 represents this situation. Combining like terms on the left-hand side of this equation yields 6n + 6 = 30. Therefore, the equation that must be true for the value of n is 6n + 6 = 30."
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "-3x + 21px = 84 In the given equation, p is a constant. The equation has no solution. What is the value of p?",
    "answer": "2025-01-07 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "A linear equation in one variable has no solution if and only if the equation is false; that is, when there is no value of x that produces a true statement. It’s given that in the equation -3x + 21px = 84, p is a constant and the equation has no solution for x. Therefore, the value of the constant p is one that results in a false equation. Factoring out the common factor of -3x on the left-hand side of the given equation yields -3x(1 - 7p) = 84. Dividing both sides of this equation by -3 yields x(1 - 7p) = -28. Dividing both sides of this equation by (1 - 7p) yields x = -28 / (1 - 7p). This equation is false if and only if 1 - 7p = 0. Adding 7p to both sides of 1 - 7p = 0 yields 1 = 7p. Dividing both sides of this equation by 7 yields 1/7 = p. It follows that the equation x = -28 / (1 - 7p) is false if and only if p = 1/7. Therefore, the given equation has no solution if and only if the value of p is 1/7."
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If (x + 6)/3 = (x + 6)/13, the value of x + 6 is between which of the following pairs of values?",
    "answer": "-2",
    "explanation": "Multiplying both sides of the given equation by (3)(13), or 39, yields (39)((x + 6)/3) = (39)((x + 6)/13), or 13(x + 6) = 3(x + 6). Subtracting 3(x + 6) from both sides of this equation yields 10(x + 6) = 0. Dividing both sides of this equation by 10 yields x + 6 = 0. Therefore, if (x + 6)/3 = (x + 6)/13, then the value of x + 6 is 0. It follows that of the given choices, the value of x + 6 is between -2 and 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "-49x = -98x How many solutions does the given equation have?",
    "answer": "Exactly one",
    "explanation": "Adding 98x to each side of the given equation yields 49x = 0. Dividing each side of this equation by 49 yields x = 0. This means that 0 is the only solution to the given equation. Therefore, the given equation has exactly one solution."
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "A science teacher is preparing the 5 stations of a science laboratory. Each station will have either Experiment A materials or Experiment B materials, but not both. Experiment A requires 6 teaspoons of salt, and Experiment B requires 4 teaspoons of salt. If x is the number of stations that will be set up for Experiment A and the remaining stations will be set up for Experiment B, which of the following expressions represents the total number of teaspoons of salt required?",
    "answer": "2x + 20",
    "explanation": "It is given that x represents the number of stations that will be set up for Experiment A and that there will be 5 stations total, so it follows that 5 - x is the number of stations that will be set up for Experiment B. It is also given that Experiment A requires 6 teaspoons of salt and that Experiment B requires 4 teaspoons of salt, so the total number of teaspoons of salt required is 6x + 4(5 - x), which simplifies to 2x + 20."
  },
  {
    "id": 81,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "The equation 9x + 5 = a(x + b), where a and b are constants, has no solutions. Which condition must be true?",
    "answer": "b = 5, b ≠ 5/9",
    "explanation": "For a linear equation in a form ax + b = cx + d to have no solutions, the x-terms must have equal coefficients and the remaining terms must not be equal. Expanding the right-hand side of the given equation yields 9x + 5 = ax + ab. Inspecting the x-terms, 9 must equal a, so statement I must be true. Inspecting the remaining terms, 5 can't equal 9b. Dividing both of these quantities by 9 yields that b can't equal 5/9. Therefore, statement III must be true. Since b can have any value other than 5/9, statement II may or may not be true."
  },
  {
    "id": 82,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "2(kx - n) = -28/15 x - 36/19 In the given equation, k and n are constants and n > 1. The equation has no solution. What is the value of k?",
    "answer": "-.9333, -14/15",
    "explanation": "A linear equation in the form ax + b = cx + d has no solution only when the coefficients of x on each side of the equation are equal and the constant terms are not equal. Dividing both sides of the given equation by 2 yields kx - n = -28/30 x - 36/38, or kx - n = -14/15 x - 18/19. Since it’s given that the equation has no solution, the coefficient of x on both sides of this equation must be equal, and the constant terms on both sides of this equation must not be equal. Since 18/19 < 1, and it's given that n > 1, the second condition is true. Thus, k must be equal to -14/15. Note that -14/15, -.9333, and -0.933 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 83,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 8x. For what value of x does f(x) = 72?",
    "answer": "9",
    "explanation": "Substituting 72 for f(x) in the given function yields 72 = 8x. Dividing each side of this equation by 8 yields 9 = x. Therefore, f(x) = 72 when the value of x is 9."
  },
  {
    "id": 84,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "Gabriella deposits $35 in a savings account at the end of each week. At the beginning of the 1st week of a year there was $600 in that savings account. How much money, in dollars, will be in the account at the end of the 4th week of that year?",
    "answer": "740",
    "explanation": "It’s given that at the beginning of the 1st week of the year there was $600 in a savings account and Gabriella deposits $35 in that savings account at the end of each week. Therefore, the amount of money, in dollars, in the savings account at the end of the 4th week of that year is 600 + 4(35), or 740."
  },
  {
    "id": 85,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A veterinarian recommends that each day a certain rabbit should eat 25 calories per pound of the rabbit’s weight, plus an additional 11 calories. Which equation represents this situation, where c is the total number of calories the veterinarian recommends the rabbit should eat each day if the rabbit’s weight is x pounds?",
    "answer": "c = 25x + 11",
    "explanation": "It’s given that a veterinarian recommends that each day the rabbit should eat 25 calories per pound of the rabbit’s weight, plus an additional 11 calories. If the rabbit’s weight is x pounds, then multiplying 25 calories per pound by the rabbit’s weight, x pounds, yields 25x calories. Adding the additional 11 calories that the rabbit should eat each day yields 25x + 11 calories. It’s given that c is the total number of calories the veterinarian recommends the rabbit should eat each day if the rabbit’s weight is x pounds. Therefore, this situation can be represented by the equation c = 25x + 11."
  },
  {
    "id": 86,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The equation shown gives the estimated amount of diesel d, in gallons, that remains in the gas tank of a truck after being driven x miles, where 0 ≤ x ≤ 480. What is the estimated amount of diesel, in gallons, that remains in the gas tank of the truck when x = 300?",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the equation d = 16 - x/30 gives the estimated amount of diesel d, in gallons, that remains in the gas tank of the truck after being driven x miles. Substituting 300 for x in the given equation yields d = 16 - 300/30, which is equivalent to d = 16 - 10, or d = 6. Therefore, the estimated amount of diesel that remains in the gas tank of the truck when x = 300 is 6 gallons."
  },
  {
    "id": 87,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The total cost f(x), in dollars, to lease a car for 36 months from a particular car dealership is given by f(x) = 36x + 1,000, where x is the monthly payment, in dollars. What is the total cost to lease a car when the monthly payment is $400?",
    "answer": "15400",
    "explanation": "It's given that f(x) is the total cost, in dollars, to lease a car from this dealership with a monthly payment of x dollars. Therefore, the total cost, in dollars, to lease the car when the monthly payment is $400 is represented by the value of f(x) when x = 400. Substituting 400 for x in the equation f(x) = 36x + 1,000 yields f(400) = 36(400) + 1,000, or f(400) = 15,400. Thus, when the monthly payment is $400, the total cost to lease a car is $15,400."
  },
  {
    "id": 88,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The front of a roller-coaster car is at the bottom of a hill and is 15 feet above the ground. If the front of the roller-coaster car rises at a constant rate of 8 feet per second, which of the following equations gives the height h, in feet, of the front of the roller-coaster car s seconds after it starts up the hill?",
    "answer": "h = 8s + 15",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the front of the roller-coaster car starts rising when it’s 15 feet above the ground. This initial height of 15 feet can be represented by a constant term, 15, in an equation. Each second, the front of the roller-coaster car rises 8 feet, which can be represented by 8s. Thus, the equation h = 8s + 15 gives the height, in feet, of the front of the roller-coaster car s seconds after it starts up the hill."
  },
  {
    "id": 89,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "If f is the function defined by f(x) = (2x - 1)/3, what is the value of f(5)?",
    "answer": "3",
    "explanation": "If f(x) = (2x - 1)/3, then f(5) = (2(5) - 1)/3 = (10 - 1)/3 = 9/3 = 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 90,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "d = 16t The given equation represents the distance d = 16t, in inches, where t represents the number of seconds since an object started moving. Which of the following is the best interpretation of 16 in this context?",
    "answer": "The object is moving at a rate of 16 inches per second.",
    "explanation": "It’s given that in the equation d = 16t, d represents the distance, in inches, and t represents the number of seconds since an object started moving. In this equation, t is being multiplied by 16. This means that the object’s distance increases by 16 inches each second. Therefore, the best interpretation of 16 in this context is that the object is moving at a rate of 16 inches per second."
  },
  {
    "id": 91,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function g is defined by g(x) = 6x. For what value of x is g(x) = 54?",
    "answer": "9",
    "explanation": "It’s given that g(x) = 6x. Substituting 54 for g(x) in the given function yields 54 = 6x. Dividing both sides of this equation by 6 yields x = 9. Therefore, the value of x when g(x) = 54 is 9."
  },
  {
    "id": 92,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The number y is 84 less than the number x. Which equation represents the relationship between x and y?",
    "answer": "y = x - 84",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the number y is 84 less than the number x. A number that’s 84 less than the number x is equivalent to 84 subtracted from the number x, or x - 84. Therefore, the equation y = x - 84 represents the relationship between x and y."
  },
  {
    "id": 93,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 4x - 3. What is the value of f(10)?",
    "answer": "37",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the function f is defined by f(x) = 4x - 3. Substituting 10 for x in the given function yields f(10) = 4(10) - 3, which is equivalent to f(10) = 40 - 3, or f(10) = 37. Therefore, the value of f(10) is 37."
  },
  {
    "id": 94,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by the equation f(x) = 7x + 2. What is the value of f(x) when x = 4?",
    "answer": "30",
    "explanation": "The value of f(x) when x = 4 can be found by substituting 4 for x in the given equation f(x) = 7x + 2. This yields f(4) = 7(4) + 2, or f(4) = 30. Therefore, when x = 4, the value of f(x) is 30."
  },
  {
    "id": 95,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "As part of a science project on evaporation, Amaya measured the height of a liquid in a container over a period of time. The function f(x) = 33 - 0.18x gives the estimated height, in centimeters (cm), of the liquid in the container x days after the start of the project. Which of the following is the best interpretation of 33 in this context?",
    "answer": "The estimated height, in cm, of the liquid at the start of the project",
    "explanation": "It's given that the function f(x) = 33 - 0.18x gives the estimated height, in centimeters (cm), of the liquid in the container x days after the start of the project. For a linear function in the form f(x) = a + bx, where a and b are constants, a represents the value of f(0) and b represents the rate of change of the function. It follows that in the given function, 33 represents the value of f(0). Therefore, the best interpretation of 33 in this context is the estimated height, in cm, of the liquid at the start of the project."
  },
  {
    "id": 96,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function g is defined by g(x) = -x + 8. What is the value of g(0)?",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "The value of g(0) is found by substituting 0 for x in the function g. This yields g(0) = -0 + 8, which can be rewritten as g(0) = 8."
  },
  {
    "id": 97,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 4x. For what value of x does f(x) = 8?",
    "answer": "2",
    "explanation": "Substituting 8 for f(x) in the given equation yields 8 = 4x. Dividing the left- and right-hand sides of this equation by 4 yields x = 2. Therefore, the value of x is 2 when f(x) = 8."
  },
  {
    "id": 98,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 80 - 6x. What is the value of f(7)?",
    "answer": "38",
    "explanation": "It’s given that function f is defined by f(x) = 80 - 6x. The value of f(7) can be found by substituting 7 for x in the given function, which yields f(7) = 80 - 6(7), or f(7) = 80 - 42, which is equivalent to f(7) = 38. Therefore, the value of f(7) is 38."
  },
  {
    "id": 99,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "For the linear function f, the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane has a slope of 2 and has a y-intercept at (0, -5). Which equation defines f?",
    "answer": "f(x) = 2x - 5",
    "explanation": "An equation defining the linear function f can be written in the form f(x) = mx + b, where m is the slope and (0, b) is the y-intercept of the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane. It’s given that the graph of y = f(x) has a slope of 2. Therefore, m = 2. It’s also given that the graph of y = f(x) has a y-intercept at (0, -5). Therefore, b = -5. Substituting 2 for m and -5 for b in the equation f(x) = mx + b yields f(x) = 2x - 5. Thus, the equation that defines f is f(x) = 2x - 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 100,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A contract for a certain service requires a onetime activation cost of $35 and a monthly cost of $23. Which equation represents this situation, where c is the total cost, in dollars, of this service contract for t months?",
    "answer": "c = 23t + 35",
    "explanation": "It's given that this service contract requires a monthly cost of $23. A monthly cost of $23 for t months results in a cost of $23t. It's also given that this service contract requires a onetime activation cost of $35. Adding the onetime activation cost to the monthly cost of the service contract for t months yields the total cost c, in dollars, of this service contract for t months. Therefore, this situation can be represented by the equation c = 23t + 35."
  },
  {
    "id": 101,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "Sean rents a tent at a cost of $11 per day plus a onetime insurance fee of $10. Which equation represents the total cost c, in dollars, to rent the tent with insurance for d days?",
    "answer": "c = 11d + 10",
    "explanation": "It's given that the cost of renting a tent is $11 per day for d days. Multiplying the rental cost by the number of days yields $11d, which represents the cost of renting the tent for d days before the insurance is added. Adding the onetime insurance fee of $10 to the rental cost of $11d gives the total cost c, in dollars, which can be represented by the equation c = 11d + 10."
  },
  {
    "id": 102,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "Some values of the linear function f are shown in the table above. Which of the following defines f?",
    "answer": "f(x) = 4x + 1",
    "explanation": "Because f is a linear function of x, the equation f(x) = mx + b, where m and b are constants, can be used to define the relationship between x and f(x). In this equation, m represents the increase in the value of f(x) for every increase in the value of x by 1. From the table, it can be determined that the value of f(x) increases by 8 for every increase in the value of x by 2. In other words, for the function f the value of m is 8/2, or 4. The value of b can be found by substituting the values of x and f(x) from any row of the table and the value of m into the equation f(x) = mx + b and solving for b. For example, using x = 1, f(x) = 5, and m = 4 yields 5 = 4(1) + b. Solving for b yields b = 1. Therefore, the equation defining the function f can be written in the form f(x) = 4x + 1."
  },
  {
    "id": 103,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "f(x) = 14 + 4x The function f represents the total cost, in dollars, of attending an arcade when x games are played. How many games can be played for a total cost of $58?",
    "answer": "11",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the function f(x) = 14 + 4x represents the total cost, in dollars, of attending an arcade when x games are played. Substituting 58 for f(x) in the given equation yields 58 = 14 + 4x. Subtracting 14 from each side of this equation yields 44 = 4x. Dividing each side of this equation by 4 yields 11 = x. Therefore, 11 games can be played for a total cost of $58."
  },
  {
    "id": 104,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A bus is traveling at a constant speed along a straight portion of road. The equation d = 30t gives the distance d, in feet from a road marker, that the bus will be t seconds after passing the marker. How many feet from the marker will the bus be 2 seconds after passing the marker?",
    "answer": "60",
    "explanation": "It’s given that t represents the number of seconds after the bus passes the marker. Substituting 2 for t in the given equation d = 30t yields d = 30(2), or d = 60. Therefore, the bus will be 60 feet from the marker 2 seconds after passing it."
  },
  {
    "id": 105,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 3x - 8. What is the value of f(7)?",
    "answer": "13",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the function f is defined by f(x) = 3x - 8. The value of f(7) is the value of f(x) when x = 7. Substituting 7 for x in the given equation yields f(7) = 3(7) - 8, which is equivalent to f(7) = 21 - 8, or f(7) = 13."
  },
  {
    "id": 106,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function h is defined by h(x) = 3x - 7. What is the value of h(-2)?",
    "answer": "-13",
    "explanation": "The value of h(-2) can be found by substituting -2 for x in the equation defining h. Substituting -2 for x in h(x) = 3x - 7 yields h(-2) = 3(-2) - 7, or h(-2) = -13. Therefore, the value of h(-2) is -13."
  },
  {
    "id": 107,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "For the linear function f, the table shows three values of x and their corresponding values of f(x). Which equation defines f(x)?",
    "answer": "f(x) = 3x + 29",
    "explanation": "An equation that defines a linear function f can be written in the form f(x) = mx + b, where m and b are constants. It's given in the table that when x = 0, f(x) = 29. Substituting 0 for x and 29 for f(x) in the equation f(x) = mx + b yields 29 = m(0) + b, or 29 = b. Substituting 29 for b in the equation f(x) = mx + b yields f(x) = mx + 29. It's also given in the table that when x = 1, f(x) = 32. Substituting 1 for x and 32 for f(x) in the equation f(x) = mx + 29 yields 32 = m(1) + 29, or 32 = m + 29. Subtracting 29 from both sides of this equation yields 3 = m. Substituting 3 for m in the equation f(x) = mx + 29 yields f(x) = 3x + 29."
  },
  {
    "id": 108,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "For a training program, Juan rides his bike at an average rate of 5.7 minutes per mile. Which function m models the number of minutes it will take Juan to ride x miles at this rate?",
    "answer": "m(x) = 5.7x",
    "explanation": "It's given that Juan rides his bike at an average rate of 5.7 minutes per mile. The number of minutes it will take Juan to ride x miles can be determined by multiplying his average rate by the number of miles, x, which yields 5.7x. Therefore, the function m(x) = 5.7x models the number of minutes it will take Juan to ride x miles."
  },
  {
    "id": 109,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "Marisol drove 3 hours from City A to City B. The equation below estimates the distance d, in miles, Marisol traveled after driving for t hours. d = 45t Which of the following does 45 represent in the equation?",
    "answer": "Marisol drove at an average speed of about 45 miles per hour.",
    "explanation": "It’s given that d is the distance, in miles, Marisol traveled after driving for t hours. Therefore, 45 represents the distance in miles traveled per hour, which is the speed she drove in miles per hour."
  },
  {
    "id": 110,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "For the linear function f, f(0) = 17 and f(1) = 17. Which equation defines f? ",
    "answer": "f(x) = 17",
    "explanation": "An equation defining the linear function f can be written in the form f(x) = mx + b, where m is the slope and (0, b) is the y-intercept of the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane. The slope of the graph of y = f(x) can be found using the formula m = (y2 - y1) / (x2 - x1), where (x1, y1) and (x2, y2) are any two points that the graph passes through. If f(0) = 17, it follows that the graph of y = f(x) passes through the point (0, 17). If f(1) = 17, it follows that the graph of y = f(x) passes through the point (1, 17). Substituting (0, 17) and (1, 17) for (x1, y1) and (x2, y2), respectively, in the formula m = (y2 - y1) / (x2 - x1) yields m = (17 - 17) / (1 - 0), which is equivalent to m = 0/1, or m = 0. Since the graph of y = f(x) passes through (0, 17), it follows that b = 17. Substituting 0 for m and 17 for b in the equation f(x) = mx + b yields f(x) = 0x + 17, or f(x) = 17. Thus, the equation that defines f is f(x) = 17."
  },
  {
    "id": 111,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f defined by f(t) = 14t + 9 gives the estimated length, in inches, of a vine plant t months after Tavon purchased it. Which of the following is the best interpretation of 9 in this context? ",
    "answer": "he estimated length of the vine plant was 9 inches when Tavon purchased it.",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the function f defined by f(t) = 14t + 9 gives the estimated length, in inches, of a vine plant t months after Tavon purchased it. For a function defined by an equation of the form f(t) = mt + b, where m and b are constants, b represents the value of f(0), or the value of f(t) when the value of t is 0. Therefore, for the function defined by f(t) = 14t + 9, 9 represents the value of f(t) when the value of t is 0. This means that 0 months after the vine plant was purchased, the estimated length of the vine plant was 9 inches. Therefore, the best interpretation of 9 in this context is the estimated length of the vine plant was 9 inches when Tavon purchased it."
  },
  {
    "id": 112,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "s = 40 + 3t The equation gives the speed s, in miles per hour, of a certain car t seconds after it began to accelerate. What is the speed, in miles per hour, of the car 5 seconds after it began to accelerate? ",
    "answer": "55",
    "explanation": "In the given equation, s is the speed, in miles per hour, of a certain car t seconds after it began to accelerate. Therefore, the speed of the car, in miles per hour, 5 seconds after it began to accelerate can be found by substituting 5 for t in the given equation, which yields s = 40 + 3(5), or s = 55. Thus, the speed of the car 5 seconds after it began to accelerate is 55 miles per hour."
  },
  {
    "id": 113,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "For the function f, the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane has a slope of 3 and passes through the point (0, -8). Which equation defines f?",
    "answer": "f(x) = 3x - 8",
    "explanation": "An equation defining a linear function can be written in the form f(x) = mx + b, where m and b are constants, m is the slope of the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane, and (0, b) is the y-intercept of the graph. It’s given that for the function f, the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane has a slope of 3. Therefore, m = 3. It’s also given that this graph passes through the point (0, -8), and it follows that b = -8. Substituting 3 for m and -8 for b in the equation f(x) = mx + b yields f(x) = 3x - 8. Thus, the equation that defines f is f(x) = 3x - 8."
  },
  {
    "id": 114,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "T = 1,000 + 18h In the equation above, T represents Brittany’s total take-home pay, in dollars, for her first week of work, where h represents the number of hours she worked that week and 1,000 represents a sign-on bonus. If Brittany’s total take-home pay was $1,576, for how many hours was Brittany paid for her first week of work? ",
    "answer": "32",
    "explanation": "Since Brittany’s total take-home pay was $1,576, the value 1,576 can be substituted for T in the given equation T = 1,000 + 18h to give 1,576 = 1,000 + 18h. Subtracting 1,000 from both sides of this equation gives 576 = 18h. Dividing both sides of this equation by 18 gives 32 = h. Therefore, Brittany was paid for 32 hours for her first week of work."
  },
  {
    "id": 115,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function g is defined as g(x) = 5x + a, where a is a constant. If g(4) = 31, what is the value of a?",
    "answer": "11",
    "explanation": "Substituting 4 for x in g(x) = 5x + a gives g(4) = 5(4) + a. Since g(4) = 31, the equation g(4) = 5(4) + a simplifies to 31 = 20 + a. It follows that a = 11."
  },
  {
    "id": 116,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "On January 1, 2015, a city’s minimum hourly wage was $9.25. It will increase by $0.50 on the first day of the year for the next 5 years. Which of the following functions best models the minimum hourly wage, in dollars, x years after January 1, 2015, where x = 1, 2, 3, 4, 5?",
    "answer": "f(x) = 9.25 + 0.50x",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the city’s minimum hourly wage will increase by $0.50 on the first day of the year for the 5 years after January 1, 2015. Therefore, the total increase, in dollars, in the minimum hourly wage x years after January 1, 2015, is represented by 0.50x. Since the minimum hourly wage on January 1, 2015, was $9.25, it follows that the minimum hourly wage, in dollars, x years after January 1, 2015, is represented by 9.25 + 0.50x. Therefore, the function f(x) = 9.25 + 0.50x best models this situation."
  },
  {
    "id": 117,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The length, y, of a white whale was 162 centimeters (cm) when it was born and increased an average of 4.8 cm per month for the first 12 months after it was born. Which equation best represents this situation, where x is the number of months after the whale was born and y is the length, in cm, of the whale?",
    "answer": "y = 4.8x + 162",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the length of the whale was 162 cm when it was born and that its length increased an average of 4.8 cm per month for the first 12 months after it was born. Since x represents the number of months after the whale was born, the total increase in the whale’s length, in cm, is 4.8 times x, or 4.8x. The length of the whale y, in cm, can be found by adding the whale’s length at birth, 162 cm, to the total increase in length, 4.8x cm. Therefore, the equation that best represents this situation is y = 4.8x + 162."
  },
  {
    "id": 118,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = (1/10)x - 2. What is the y-intercept of the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane?",
    "answer": "(0,-2)",
    "explanation": "The y-intercept of the graph of a function in the xy-plane is the point on the graph where x = 0. It’s given that f(x) = (1/10)x - 2. Substituting 0 for x in this equation yields f(0) = (1/10)(0) - 2, or f(0) = -2. Since it’s given that y = f(x), it follows that y = -2 when x = 0. Therefore, the y-intercept of the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane is (0,-2)."
  },
  {
    "id": 119,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "To repair a refrigerator, a technician charges $60 per hour for labor plus $120 for parts. Which function f represents the total amount, in dollars, the technician will charge for this job if it takes x hours?",
    "answer": "f(x) = 60x + 120",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the technician charges $60 per hour for labor. Therefore, if the job takes x hours, the technician will charge (60/1 hour)(x hours), or 60x, for labor. It’s also given that the technician charges $120 for parts. Therefore, f(x) = 60x + 120 represents the total amount, in dollars, the technician will charge for this job if it takes x hours."
  },
  {
    "id": 120,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by the equation f(x) = 100x + 2. What is the value of f(x) when x = 9?",
    "answer": "902",
    "explanation": "Substituting 9 for x in the given equation yields f(9) = 100(9) + 2, or f(9) = 902. Therefore, the value of f(x) when x = 9 is 902."
  },
  {
    "id": 121,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "In the linear function h, h(0) = 41 and h(1) = 40. Which equation defines h?",
    "answer": "h(x) = -x + 41",
    "explanation": "An equation defining a linear function can be written in the form h(x) = ax + b, where a and b are constants. It’s given that h(0) = 41. Substituting 0 for x and 41 for h(x) in the equation h(x) = ax + b yields 41 = a(0) + b, or b = 41. Substituting 41 for b in the equation h(x) = ax + 41 yields h(1) = 40. Substituting 1 for x and 40 for h(x) in the equation h(x) = ax + 41 yields 40 = a(1) + 41, or 40 = a + 41. Subtracting 41 from both sides yields -1 = a. Substituting -1 for a in the equation h(x) = ax + 41 yields h(x) = -x + 41."
  },
  {
    "id": 122,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function g is defined by g(x) = 4x - 6. What is the value of g(-7)?",
    "answer": "-34",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the function g is defined by g(x) = 4x - 6. Substituting -7 for x into the given equation yields g(-7) = 4(-7) - 6, or g(-7) = -34."
  },
  {
    "id": 123,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "Hana deposited a fixed amount into her bank account each month. The function f(t) = 100 + 25t gives the amount, in dollars, in Hana’s bank account after t monthly deposits. What is the best interpretation of 25 in this context?",
    "answer": "With each monthly deposit, the amount in Hana’s bank account increased by $25.",
    "explanation": "It’s given that t represents the number of monthly deposits. In the given function f(t) = 100 + 25t, the coefficient of t is 25. This means that for every increase in the value of t by 1, the value of f(t) increases by 25."
  },
  {
    "id": 124,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "For the linear function f, the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane has a slope of 39 and passes through the point (0,0). Which equation defines f?",
    "answer": "f(x) = 39x",
    "explanation": "An equation defining a linear function can be written in the form f(x) = mx + b, where m is the slope and (0,b) is the y-intercept of the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane. It’s given that the graph of y = f(x) has a slope of 39, so m = 39. It’s also given that the graph of y = f(x) passes through the point (0,0), so b = 0. Substituting 39 for m and 0 for b in f(x) = mx + b yields f(x) = 39x + 0, or f(x) = 39x. Thus, the equation that defines f is f(x) = 39x."
  },
  {
    "id": 125,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "f(x) = 7x + 1 The function gives the total number of people on a company retreat with x managers. What is the total number of people on a company retreat with 7 managers?",
    "answer": "50",
    "explanation": "It's given that the function f gives the total number of people on a company retreat with x managers. It's also given that 7 managers are on the company retreat. Substituting 7 for x in the given function yields f(7) = 7(7) + 1 = 50. Therefore, there are a total of 50 people on a company retreat with 7 managers."
  },
  {
    "id": 126,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function g is defined by g(x) = 10x + 8. What is the value of g(x) when x = 8?",
    "answer": "88",
    "explanation": "The value of g(x) when x = 8 can be found by substituting 8 for x in the given equation: g(8) = 10(8) + 8 = 88. Therefore, when x = 8, the value of g(x) is 88."
  },
  {
    "id": 127,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "f(x) = x + b. For the linear function f, b is a constant. When x = 0, f(x) = 30. What is the value of b?",
    "answer": "30",
    "explanation": "It's given that when x = 0, f(x) = 30. Substituting 0 for x and 30 for f(x) in the given function yields: 30 = 0 + b, so b = 30. Therefore, the value of b is 30."
  },
  {
    "id": 128,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "If y = 5x + 10, what is the value of y when x = 8?",
    "answer": "50",
    "explanation": "Substituting 8 for x in the given equation yields: y = 5(8) + 10 = 50. Therefore, the value of y is 50 when x = 8."
  },
  {
    "id": 129,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The population of snow leopards in a certain area can be modeled by the function P(t) = 250 + 10t, where P(t) is the population t years after 1990. Of the following, which is the best interpretation of the equation P(30) = 550?",
    "answer": "The snow leopard population in this area is predicted to be 550 in the year 2020.",
    "explanation": "It’s given that P(t) represents the population of snow leopards t years after 1990. P(30) = 550 corresponds to t = 30 and P(t) = 550. It follows that t = 30 corresponds to 30 years after 1990, or 2020. Thus, the best interpretation of P(30) = 550 is that the snow leopard population in this area is predicted to be 550 in the year 2020."
  },
  {
    "id": 130,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "Robert rented a truck to transport materials he purchased from a hardware store. He was charged an initial fee of $20.00 plus an additional $0.70 per mile driven. If the truck was driven 38 miles, what was the total amount Robert was charged?",
    "answer": "46.6",
    "explanation": "It's given that Robert was charged an initial fee of $20.00 to rent the truck plus an additional $0.70 per mile driven. Let m represent the number of miles the truck was driven. Since the rental charge is $0.70 per mile driven, 0.70m represents the amount Robert was charged for m miles driven. Let c equal the total amount, in dollars, Robert was charged to rent the truck. The total amount can be represented by the equation: c = 20.00 + 0.70m. It's given that the truck was driven 38 miles, thus m = 38. Substituting 38 into the equation gives: c = 20.00 + 0.70(38) = 20.00 + 26.60 = 46.60. So, the total amount Robert was charged is $46.60."
  },
  {
    "id": 131,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The graph of the function f is a line in the xy-plane. If the line has slope 3/4 and f(0) = 3, which of the following defines f?",
    "answer": "f(x) = (3/4)x + 3",
    "explanation": "The equation for the function f in the xy-plane can be represented by: f(x) = mx + b, where m is the slope and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept. Since it's given that the line has a slope of 3/4, it follows that m = 3/4. It's given that f(0) = 3. This implies that the graph of the function f in the xy-plane passes through the point (0,3). Thus, the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the graph is 3, so b = 3 in: f(x) = (3/4)x + b, which yields f(x) = (3/4)x + 3. Therefore, the equation f(x) = (3/4)x + 3 defines the function f."
  },
  {
    "id": 132,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function h is defined by h(x) = x + 200. What is the value of h(50)?",
    "answer": "250",
    "explanation": "Substituting 50 for x in the given function yields: h(50) = 50 + 200 = 250. Therefore, the value of h(50) is 250."
  },
  {
    "id": 133,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 5x + 8. For what value of x does f(x) = 58?",
    "answer": "10",
    "explanation": "It's given that the function f is defined by f(x) = 5x + 8. Substituting 58 for f(x) in this equation yields: 58 = 5x + 8. Subtracting 8 from both sides of this equation yields: 50 = 5x. Dividing both sides by 5 yields: 10 = x. Therefore, the value of x when f(x) = 58 is 10."
  },
  {
    "id": 134,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "Caleb used juice to make popsicles. The function f(x) = -5x + 30 approximates the volume, in fluid ounces, of juice Caleb had remaining after making x popsicles. Which statement is the best interpretation of the y-intercept of the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane in this context?",
    "answer": "Caleb had approximately 30 fluid ounces of juice when he began to make the popsicles.",
    "explanation": "An equation that defines a linear function f can be written in the form f(x) = mx + b, where m represents the slope and b represents the y-intercept, (0, b), of the line of y = f(x) in the xy-plane. The function f(x) = -5x + 30 is linear. Therefore, the graph of the given function y = f(x) in the xy-plane has a y-intercept of (0, 30). It’s given that f(x) gives the approximate volume, in fluid ounces, of juice Caleb had remaining after making x popsicles. It follows that the y-intercept of (0, 30) means that Caleb had approximately 30 fluid ounces of juice remaining after making 0 popsicles. In other words, Caleb had approximately 30 fluid ounces of juice when he began to make the popsicles."
  },
  {
    "id": 135,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "(10, 82), (15, 137), (20, 192), (25, 247) The table shows four values of x and their corresponding values of f(x). There is a linear relationship between x and f(x) that is defined by the equation f(x) = mx - 28, where is a constant. What is the value of m?",
    "answer": "11",
    "explanation": "It's given that f(x) is defined by the equation f(x) = mx - 28, where m is a constant. It's also given in the table that when x = 10, f(x) = 82. Substituting 10 for x and 82 for f(x) in the equation f(x) = mx - 28 yields, 82 = m(10) - 28. Adding 28 to both sides of this equation yields 110 = 10m. Dividing both sides of this equation by 10 yields 11 = m. Therefore, the value of m is 11."
  },
  {
    "id": 136,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 7x - 84. What is the x-intercept of the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane?",
    "answer": "(12, 0)",
    "explanation": "The given function f is a linear function. Therefore, the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane has one x-intercept at the point (k, 0), where k is a constant. Substituting 0 for f(x) and k for x in the given function yields 0 = 7k - 84. Adding 84 to both sides of this equation yields 84 = 7k. Dividing both sides by 7 yields 12 = k. Therefore, the x-intercept of the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane is (12, 0)."
  },
  {
    "id": 137,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The pressure exerted on a scuba diver at sea level is 14.70 pounds per square inch (psi). For each foot the scuba diver descends below sea level, the pressure exerted on the scuba diver increases by 0.44 psi. What is the total pressure, in psi, exerted on the scuba diver at 105 feet below sea level?",
    "answer": "31.5",
    "explanation": "It's given that the pressure exerted on a scuba diver at sea level is 14.70 pounds per square inch (psi). It's also given that for each foot the scuba diver descends below sea level, the pressure exerted on the scuba diver increases by 0.44 psi. The total pressure, in psi, exerted on the scuba diver at x feet below sea level can be represented by the expression 0.44x + 14.70. Substituting 105 for x in this expression yields 0.44(105) + 14.70, or 60.90. Therefore, the total pressure exerted on the scuba diver at 105 feet below sea level is 60.90 psi."
  },
  {
    "id": 138,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A team of workers has been moving cargo off of a ship. The equation below models the approximate number of tons of cargo, y, that remains to be moved x hours after the team started working. y = 120 - 25x The graph of this equation in the xy-plane is a line. What is the best interpretation of the x-intercept in this context?",
    "answer": "The team will have moved all the cargo in about 4.8 hours.",
    "explanation": "The x-intercept of the line with equation y = 120 - 25x can be found by substituting 0 for y and finding the value of x. When y = 0, x = 4.8, so the x-intercept is at (4.8, 0). Since y represents the number of tons of cargo remaining to be moved x hours after the team started working, it follows that the x-intercept refers to the team having no cargo remaining to be moved after 4.8 hours. In other words, the team will have moved all of the cargo after about 4.8 hours."
  },
  {
    "id": 139,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A model predicts that a certain animal weighed 241 pounds when it was born and that the animal gained 3pounds per day in its first year of life. This model is defined by an equation in the form f(x) = a + bx, where f(x) is the predicted weight, in pounds, of the animal x days after it was born, and a and b are constants. What is the value of a?",
    "answer": "241",
    "explanation": "For a certain animal, it's given that a model predicts the animal weighed 241 pounds when it was born and gained 3 pounds per day in its first year of life. It's also given that this model is defined by an equation in the form f(x) = a + bx, where f(x) is the predicted weight, in pounds, of the animal x days after it was born, and a and b are constants. It follows that a represents the predicted weight, in pounds, of the animal when it was born and b represents the predicted rate of weight gain, in pounds per day, in its first year of life. Thus, the value of a is 241."
  },
  {
    "id": 140,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "In the xy-plane, the graph of the linear function f contains the points (0,3) and (7,31). Which equation defines f, where y = f(x)?",
    "answer": "f(x) = 4x + 3",
    "explanation": "In the xy-plane, an equation of the graph of a linear function can be written in the form f(x) = mx + b, where m represents the slope and (0, b) represents the y-intercept of the graph of y = f(x). It’s given that the graph of the linear function f, where y = f(x), in the xy-plane contains the point (0, 3). Thus, b = 3. The slope of the graph of a line containing any two points (x1, y1) and (x2, y2) can be found using the slope formula, m = (y2 - y1) / (x2 - x1). Since it’s given that the graph of the linear function f contains the points (0, 3) and (7, 31), it follows that the slope of the graph of the line containing these points is m = (31 - 3) / (7 - 0), or m = 4. Substituting 4 for m and 3 for b in f(x) = mx + b yields f(x) = 4x + 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 141,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "According to a model, the head width, in millimeters, of a worker bumblebee can be estimated by adding 0.6 to four times the body weight of the bee, in grams. According to the model, what would be the head width, in millimeters, of a worker bumblebee that has a body weight of 0.5 grams?",
    "answer": "2.6",
    "explanation": "According to the model, the head width, in millimeters, of a worker bumblebee can be estimated by adding 0.6 to 4 times the body weight, in grams, of the bee. Let x represent the body weight of a worker bumblebee and let y represent the head width, in millimeters. Translating the verbal description of the model into an equation yields y = 0.6 + 4x. Substituting 0.5 grams for x in this equation yields y = 0.6 + 4(0.5), or y = 2.6. Therefore, a worker bumblebee with a body weight of 0.5 grams has an estimated head width of 2.6 millimeters. Note that 2.6 and 13/5 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 142,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function h is defined by h(x) = 4x + 28. The graph of in the xy-plane has an x-intercept at (a,0) and a y-intercept at (0,b), where and are constants. What is the value of a + b?",
    "answer": "21",
    "explanation": "The x-intercept of a graph in the xy-plane is the point on the graph where y = 0. It's given that function h is defined by h(x) = 4x + 28. Therefore, the equation representing the graph of y = h(x) is y = 4x + 28. Substituting 0 for y in the equation y = 4x + 28 yields 0 = 4x + 28. Subtracting 28 from both sides of this equation yields -28 = 4x. Dividing both sides of this equation by 4 yields -7 = x. Therefore, the x-intercept of the graph of y = h(x) in the xy-plane is (-7, 0). It's given that the x-intercept of the graph of y = h(x) is (a, 0). Therefore, a = -7. The y-intercept of a graph in the xy-plane is the point on the graph where x = 0. Substituting 0 for x in the equation y = 4x + 28 yields y = 4(0) + 28, or y = 28. Therefore, the y-intercept of the graph of y = h(x) in the xy-plane is (0, 28). It’s given that the y-intercept of the graph of y = h(x) is (0, b). Therefore, b = 28. If a = -7 and b = 28, then the value of a + b is -7 + 28, or 21."
  },
  {
    "id": 143,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "In the xy-plane, the graph of the linear function f contains the points (0, 2) and (8, 34). Which equation defines f, where y = f(x)?",
    "answer": "f(x) = 4x + 2",
    "explanation": "In the xy-plane, the graph of a linear function can be written in the form f(x) = mx + b, where m represents the slope and (0, b) represents the y-intercept of the graph of y = f(x). It’s given that the graph of the linear function f contains the point (0, 2). Thus, b = 2. The slope of the graph of a line containing any two points (x1, y1) and (x2, y2) can be found using the slope formula, m = (y2 - y1) / (x2 - x1). Since it's given that the graph of the linear function f contains the points (0, 2) and (8, 34), it follows that the slope of the graph of the line containing these points is m = (34 - 2) / (8 - 0), or m = 4. Substituting 4 for m and 2 for b in f(x) = mx + b yields f(x) = 4x + 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 144,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "(3, 174), (5, 284), (10, 559) The table shows the linear relationship between the number of cars, c, on a commuter train and the maximum number of passengers and crew, p, that the train can carry. Which equation represents the linear relationship between c and p?",
    "answer": "55c - p = -9",
    "explanation": "It's given that there is a linear relationship between the number of cars, c, on a commuter train and the maximum number of passengers and crew, p, that the train can carry. It follows that this relationship can be represented by an equation of the form p = mc + b, where m is the rate of change of p in this relationship and b is a constant. The rate of change of p in this relationship can be calculated by dividing the difference in any two values of p by the difference in the corresponding values of c. Using two pairs of values given in the table, the rate of change of p in this relationship is (284 - 174) / (5 - 3), or 55. Substituting 55 for m in the equation p = mc + b yields p = 55c + b. The value of b can be found by substituting any value of c and its corresponding value of p for c and p, respectively, in this equation. Substituting 10 for c and 559 for p yields 559 = 55(10) + b, or 559 = 550 + b. Subtracting 550 from both sides of this equation yields 9 = b. Substituting 9 for b in the equation p = 55c + b yields p = 55c + 9. Subtracting 9 from both sides of this equation yields p - 9 = 55c. Subtracting p from both sides of this equation yields -9 = 55c - p, or 55c - p = -9."
  },
  {
    "id": 145,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "Brian saves 2/5 of the $215 he earns each week from his job. If Brian continues to save at this rate, how much money, in dollars, will Brian save in 9 weeks?",
    "answer": "774",
    "explanation": "It's given that Brian saves 2/5 of the $215 he earns each week from his job. Therefore, Brian saves (2/5) ($215), or $86, per week. If Brian continues to save at this rate of $86 per week for 9 weeks, then he will save a total of (9)(86), or 774, dollars."
  },
  {
    "id": 146,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "For the linear function h, the graph of y = h(x) in the xy-plane passes through the points (7, 21) and (9, 25). Which equation defines h?",
    "answer": "h(x) = 2x + 7",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the graph of the linear function h, where y = h(x), passes through the points (7, 21) and (9, 25) in the xy-plane. An equation defining h can be written in the form y = mx + b, where y = h(x), m represents the slope of the graph in the xy-plane, and b represents the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the graph. The slope can be found using any two points, (x1, y1) and (x2, y2), and the formula m = (y2 - y1) / (x2 - x1). Substituting (7, 21) and (9, 25) for (x1, y1) and (x2, y2), respectively, in the slope formula yields m = (25 - 21) / (9 - 7), which is equivalent to m = 4 / 2, or m = 2. Substituting 2 for m and (7, 21) for (x, y) in the equation y = mx + b yields 21 = (2)(7) + b, or 21 = 14 + b. Subtracting 14 from each side of this equation yields 7 = b. Substituting 2 for m and 7 for b in the equation y = mx + b yields y = 2x + 7. Since y = h(x), it follows that the equation that defines h is h(x) = 2x + 7."
  },
  {
    "id": 147,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The boiling point of water at sea level is 212 degrees Fahrenheit (°F). For every 550 feet above sea level, the boiling point of water is lowered by about 1°F. Which of the following equations can be used to find the boiling point B of water, in °F, x feet above sea level?",
    "answer": "B = 212 - x / 550",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the boiling point of water at sea level is 212°F and that for every 550 feet above sea level, the boiling point of water is lowered by about 1°F. Therefore, the change in the boiling point of water x feet above sea level is represented by the expression (-x / 550). Adding this expression to the boiling point of water at sea level gives the equation B = 212 - x / 550."
  },
  {
    "id": 148,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "For the function f defined above, what is the value of f(9) - f(1)?",
    "answer": "2",
    "explanation": "The value of f(9) - f(1) can be calculated by finding the values of f(9) and f(1). The value of f(9) can be found by substituting 9 for x in the given function: f(9) = (9 + 7) / 4. This equation can be rewritten as f(9) = 16 / 4, or 4. Then, the value of f(1) can be found by substituting 1 for x in the given function: f(1) = (1 + 7) / 4. This equation can be rewritten as f(1) = 8 / 4, or 2. Therefore, f(9) - f(1) = 4 - 2, which is equivalent to 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 149,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "In the xy-plane, the points (-2,3) and (4,-5) lie on the graph of which of the following Linear functions?",
    "answer": "f(x) = (-4/3)x + (1/3)",
    "explanation": "A linear function can be written in the form f(x) = mx + b, where m is the slope and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the line. The slope of the graph can be found using the formula m = (y2 - y1) / (x2 - x1). Substituting the values of the given points into this formula yields m = (-5 - 3) / (4 - (-2)) or m = -8 / 6, which simplifies to m = -4 / 3. Only choice C shows an equation with this slope."
  },
  {
    "id": 150,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "(0, -2), (2, 4), (6, 16) Some values of the linear function f are shown in the table above. What is the value of f(3)?",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "A linear function has a constant rate of change, and any two rows of the table shown can be used to calculate this rate. From the first row to the second, the value of x is increased by 2 and the value of f(x) is increased by 6 = 4 - (-2). So the values of f(x) increase by 3 for every increase by 1 in the value of x. Since f(2) = 4, it follows that f(2 + 1) = 4 + 3 = 7. Therefore, f(3) = 7."
  },
  {
    "id": 151,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "Which function m models the number of minutes it will take Juan to ride x miles at this rate?",
    "answer": "h(x) = (-7/2)x + 113",
    "explanation": "An equation defining h can be written in the form y = mx + b, where y = h(x), m represents the slope of the graph of y = h(x) in the xy-plane, and b represents the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the graph. It’s given that h(28) = 15 and h(26) = 22. It follows that the points (28, 15) and (26, 22) are on the graph of y = h(x) in the xy-plane. The slope can be found by using any two points, (x₁, y₁) and (x₂, y₂), and the formula m = (y₂ - y₁) / (x₂ - x₁). Substituting (28, 15) and (26, 22) for (x₁, y₁) and (x₂, y₂), respectively, in the slope formula yields m = (22 - 15) / (26 - 28), or m = -7/2. Substituting -7/2 for m and (28, 15) for (x, y) in the equation y = mx + b yields 15 = (-7/2)(28) + b, or 15 = -98 + b. Adding 98 to both sides of this equation yields 113 = b. Substituting -7/2 for m and 113 for b in the equation y = mx + b yields y = -7/2x + 113. Since y = h(x), it follows that the equation that defines h is h(x) = -7/2x + 113."
  },
  {
    "id": 152,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "Which function m models the number of minutes it will take Juan to ride x miles at this rate?",
    "answer": "39",
    "explanation": "It’s given that for the linear function j, m is a constant and j(12) = 18. Substituting 12 for x and 18 for j(x) in the given equation yields 18 = m(12) + 144. Subtracting 144 from both sides of this equation yields -126 = m(12). Dividing both sides of this equation by 12 yields -10.5 = m. Substituting -10.5 for m in the given equation, j(x) = mx + 144, yields j(x) = -10.5x + 144. Substituting 10 for x in this equation yields j(10) = (-10.5)(10) + 144, or j(10) = 39. Therefore, the value of j(10) is 39."
  },
  {
    "id": 153,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": " w(t) = 300 - 4t. The function w models the volume of liquid, in milliliters, in a container t seconds after it begins draining from a hole at the bottom. According to the model, what is the predicted volume, in milliliters, draining from the container each second?",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the function w models the volume of liquid, in milliliters, in a container seconds after it begins draining from a hole at the bottom. The given function w(t) = 300 - 4t can be rewritten as w(t) = -4t + 300. Thus, for each increase of t by 1, the value of w(t) decreases by 4(1), or 4. Therefore, the predicted volume, in milliliters, draining from the container each second is 4 milliliters."
  },
  {
    "id": 154,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "f(x) = 2x + 244. The given function f represents the perimeter, in centimeters (cm), of a rectangle with a length of x cm and a fixed width. What is the width, in cm, of the rectangle?",
    "answer": "122",
    "explanation": "It's given that f(x) = 2x + 244 represents the perimeter, in centimeters (cm), of a rectangle with a length of x cm and a fixed width. If w represents a fixed width, in cm, then the perimeter, in cm, of a rectangle with a length of x cm and a fixed width of w cm can be given by the function f(x) = 2x + 2w. Therefore, 2x + 2w = 2x + 244. Subtracting 2x from both sides of this equation yields 2w = 244. Dividing both sides of this equation by 2 yields w = 122. Therefore, the width, in cm, of the rectangle is 122."
  },
  {
    "id": 155,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "In the linear function f, f(0) = 8 and f(1) = 12. Which equation defines f?",
    "answer": "f(x) = 4x + 8",
    "explanation": "Since f is a linear function, it can be defined by an equation of the form f(x) = ax + b, where a and b are constants. It's given that f(0) = 8. Substituting 0 for x and 8 for f(x) in the equation f(x) = ax + b yields 8 = a(0) + b, or 8 = b. Substituting 8 for b in the equation f(x) = ax + b yields f(x) = ax + 8. It's given that f(1) = 12. Substituting 1 for x and 12 for f(x) in the equation f(x) = ax + 8 yields 12 = a(1) + 8, or 12 = a + 8. Subtracting 8 from both sides of this equation yields a = 4. Substituting 4 for a in the equation f(x) = ax + 8 yields f(x) = 4x + 8. Therefore, an equation that defines f is f(x) = 4x + 8."
  },
  {
    "id": 156,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A linear model estimates the population of a city from 1991 to 2015. The model estimates the population was 57 thousand in 1991, 224 thousand in 2011, and x thousand in 2015. To the nearest whole number, what is the value of x?",
    "answer": "257",
    "explanation": "It's given that a linear model estimates the population of a city from 1991 to 2015. Since the population can be estimated using a linear model, it follows that there is a constant rate of change for the model. It's also given that the model estimates the population was 57 thousand in 1991, 224 thousand in 2011, and x thousand in 2015. The change in the population between 2011 and 1991 is 224 - 57, or 167, thousand. The change in the number of years between 2011 and 1991 is 2011 - 1991, or 20, years. Dividing 167 by 20 gives 167/20, or 8.35, thousand per year. Thus, the change in population per year from 1991 to 2015 estimated by the model is 8.35 thousand. The change in the number of years between 2015 and 2011 is 2015 - 2011, or 4, years. Multiplying the change in population per year by the change in number of years yields the increase in population from 2011 to 2015 estimated by the model: (8.35)(4), or 33.4, thousand. Adding the change in population from 2011 to 2015 estimated by the model to the estimated population in 2011 yields the estimated population in 2015. Thus, the estimated population in 2015 is 33.4 + 224, or 257.4, thousand. Therefore, to the nearest whole number, the value of x is 257."
  },
  {
    "id": 157,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f(x) = 55.20 - 0.16x gives the estimated surface water temperature f(x), in degrees Celsius, of a body of water on the xth day of the year, where 220 ≤ x ≤ 360. Based on the model, what is the estimated surface water temperature, in degrees Celsius, of this body of water on the 326th day of the year?",
    "answer": "3.04",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the function f(x) = 55.20 - 0.16x gives the estimated surface water temperature, in degrees Celsius, of a body of water on the xth day of the year. Substituting 326 for x in the given function yields f(326) = 55.20 - 0.16(326), which is equivalent to f(326) = 55.20 - 52.16, or f(326) = 3.04. Therefore, the estimated surface water temperature, in degrees Celsius, of this body of water on the 326th day of the year is 3.04."
  },
  {
    "id": 158,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "c(x) = mx + 500 A company’s total cost c(x), in dollars, to produce x shirts is given by the function above, where m is a constant and x > 0. The total cost to produce 100 shirts is $800. What is the total cost, in dollars, to produce 1000 shirts? (Disregard the $ sign when gridding your answer.)",
    "answer": "3500",
    "explanation": "The given information includes a cost, $800, to produce 100 shirts. Substituting c(x) = 800 and x = 100 into the given equation yields 800 = m(100) + 500. Subtracting 500 from both sides of the equation yields 300 = m(100). Dividing both sides of this equation by 100 yields 3 = m. Substituting the value of m into the given equation yields c(x) = 3x + 500. Substituting 1000 for x in this equation and solving for c(x) gives the cost of 1000 shirts: 3(1000) + 500, or 3500."
  },
  {
    "id": 159,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "Which function m models the number of minutes it will take Juan to ride x miles at this rate?",
    "answer": "0.05",
    "explanation": "It's given that the function g models the number of gallons that remain from a full gas tank in a car after driving m miles. In the given function g(m) = -0.05m + 12.1, the coefficient of m is -0.05. This means that for every increase in the value of m by 1, the value of g(m) decreases by 0.05. It follows that for each mile driven, there is a decrease of 0.05 gallons of gasoline. Therefore, 0.05 gallons of gasoline are used to drive each mile."
  },
  {
    "id": 160,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "y = 18 - 5x The equation above represents the speed y, in feet per second, of Sheila’s bicycle x seconds after she applied the brakes at the end of a ride. If the equation is graphed in the xy-plane, which of the following is the best interpretation of the x-coordinate of the line’s x-intercept in the context of the problem? ",
    "answer": "The number of seconds it took from the time Sheila began applying the brakes until the bicycle came to a complete stop",
    "explanation": "It’s given that for each point (x, y) on the graph of the given equation, the x-coordinate represents the number of seconds after Sheila applied the brakes, and the y-coordinate represents the speed of Sheila’s bicycle at that moment in time. For the graph of the equation, the y-coordinate of the x-intercept is 0. Therefore, the x-coordinate of the x-intercept of the graph of the given equation represents the number of seconds it took from the time Sheila began applying the brakes until the bicycle came to a complete stop."
  },
  {
    "id": 161,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = (9/7)x + (8/7). For what value of x does f(x) = 5?",
    "answer": "3",
    "explanation": "Substituting 5 for f(x) in the given function yields 5 = (9/7)x + (8/7). Multiplying each side of this equation by 7 yields 7(5) = 7((9/7)x + (8/7)), or 35 = 9x + 8. Subtracting 8 from each side of this equation yields 27 = 9x. Dividing each side of this equation by 9 yields 3 = x. Therefore, f(x) = 5 when the value of x is 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 162,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "Scientists collected fallen acorns that each housed a colony of the ant species P. ohioensis and analyzed each colony's structure. For any of these colonies, if the colony has x worker ants, the equation y = 0.67x + 2.6, where 20 ≤ x ≤ 110, gives the predicted number of larvae, y, in the colony. If one of these colonies has 58 worker ants, which of the following is closest to the predicted number of larvae in the colony?",
    "answer": "41",
    "explanation": "It's given that the equation y = 0.67x + 2.6, where 20 ≤ x ≤ 110, gives the predicted number of larvae, y, in a colony of ants if the colony has x worker ants. If one of these colonies has 58 worker ants, the predicted number of larvae in that colony can be found by substituting 58 for x in the given equation. Substituting 58 for x in the given equation yields y = 0.67(58) + 2.6, or y = 41.46. Of the given choices, 41 is closest to the predicted number of larvae in the colony."
  },
  {
    "id": 163,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The relationship between two variables, x and y, is linear. For every increase in the value of x by 1, the value of y increases by 8. When the value of x is 2, the value of y is 18. Which equation represents this relationship?",
    "answer": "y = 8x + 2",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the relationship between x and y is linear. An equation representing a linear relationship can be written in the form y = mx + b, where m is the slope and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the graph of the relationship in the xy-plane. It’s given that for every increase in the value of x by 1, the value of y increases by 8. The slope of a line can be expressed as the change in y over the change in x. Thus, the slope, m, of the line representing this relationship can be expressed as 8/1, or 8. Substituting 8 for m in the equation y = mx + b yields y = 8x + b. It's also given that when the value of x is 2, the value of y is 18. Substituting 2 for x and 18 for y in the equation y = 8x + b yields 18 = 8(2) + b, or 18 = 16 + b. Subtracting 16 from each side of this equation yields 2 = b. Substituting 2 for b in the equation y = 8x + b yields y = 8x + 2. Therefore, the equation y = 8x + 2 represents this relationship."
  },
  {
    "id": 164,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "f(x) = 2x + 3 For the given function f, the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane is parallel to line j. What is the slope of line j?",
    "answer": "2",
    "explanation": "It’s given that function f is defined by f(x) = 2x + 3. Therefore, the equation representing the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane is y = 2x + 3, and the graph is a line. For a linear equation in the form y = mx + b, m represents the slope of the line. Since the value of m in the equation y = 2x + 3 is 2, the slope of the line defined by function f is 2. It's given that line j is parallel to the line defined by function f. The slopes of parallel lines are equal. Therefore, the slope of line j is also 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 165,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A linear function f gives a company’s profit, in dollars, for selling x items. The company’s profit is $220 when it sells 8 items, and its profit is $320 when it sells 10 items. Which equation defines f?",
    "answer": "f(x) = 50x - 180",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the relationship between x and f(x) is linear. A linear function can be written in the form f(x) = mx + b, where m is the slope and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane. Given two points on a line, (x1, y1) and (x2, y2), the slope of the line can be found using the slope formula m = (y2 - y1) / (x2 - x1). It’s given that the company’s profit is $220 when it sells 8 items and the profit is $320 when it sells 10 items. Since f(x) represents the company’s profit, in dollars, for selling x items, the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane passes through the points (8, 220) and (10, 320). Substituting (8, 220) and (10, 320) for (x1, y1) and (x2, y2), respectively, in the slope formula yields m = (320 - 220) / (10 - 8), which gives m = 100 / 2, or m = 50. Substituting 50 for m, 8 for x, and 220 for f(x) in f(x) = mx + b yields 220 = (50)(8) + b, or 220 = 400 + b. Subtracting 400 from each side of this equation yields -180 = b. Substituting 50 for m and -180 for b in f(x) = mx + b yields f(x) = 50x - 180. Therefore, the equation that defines f is f(x) = 50x - 180."
  },
  {
    "id": 166,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = mx + b, where m and b are constants. If f(0) = 18 and f(1) = 20, what is the value of m?",
    "answer": "2",
    "explanation": "The slope-intercept form of an equation for a line is y = mx + b, where m is the slope and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept. Two ordered pairs, (x1, y1) and (x2, y2), can be used to compute the slope using the formula m = (y2 - y1) / (x2 - x1). It’s given that f(0) = 18 and f(1) = 20; therefore, the two ordered pairs for this line are (0,18) and (1,20). Substituting these values for (x1, y1) and (x2, y2) gives (20 - 18) / (1 - 0) = 2 / 1, or 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 167,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "If f(x) = x + 7 and g(x) = 7x, what is the value of 4f(2) - g(2)?",
    "answer": "22",
    "explanation": "The value of f(2) can be found by substituting 2 for x in the given equation f(x) = x + 7, which yields f(2) = 2 + 7, or f(2) = 9. The value of g(2) can be found by substituting 2 for x in the given equation g(x) = 7x, which yields g(2) = 7(2), or g(2) = 14. The value of the expression 4f(2) - g(2) can be found by substituting the corresponding values into the expression, which gives 4(9) - 14. This expression is equivalent to 36 - 14, or 22."
  },
  {
    "id": 168,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = (x + 15)/5, and f(a) = 10, where a is a constant. What is the value of a?",
    "answer": "35",
    "explanation": "It’s given that f(x) = (x + 15) / 5 and f(a) = 10, where a is a constant. Therefore, for the given function f, when x = a, f(x) = 10. Substituting a for x and 10 for f(x) in the given function f yields 10 = (a + 15) / 5. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 5 yields 50 = a + 15. Subtracting 15 from both sides of this equation yields 35 = a. Therefore, the value of a is 35."
  },
  {
    "id": 169,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "For the linear function g, the graph of y = g(x) in the xy-plane has a slope of 2 and passes through the point (1,14). Which equation defines g?",
    "answer": "g(x) = 2x + 12",
    "explanation": "An equation defining a linear function can be written in the form g(x) = mx + b, where m is the slope and (0, b) is the y-intercept of the graph of y = g(x) in the xy-plane. It’s given that the graph of y = g(x) has a slope of 2. Therefore, m = 2. It’s also given that the graph of y = g(x) passes through the point (1,14). It follows that when x = 1, g(x) = 14. Substituting 1 for x, 14 for g(x), and 2 for m in the equation g(x) = mx + b yields 14 = 2(1) + b, or 14 = 2 + b. Subtracting 2 from each side of this equation yields 12 = b. Therefore, b = 12. Substituting 2 for m and 12 for b in the equation g(x) = mx + b yields g(x) = 2x + 12. Therefore, the equation that defines g is g(x) = 2x + 12."
  },
  {
    "id": 170,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "According to data provided by the US Department of Energy, the average price per gallon of regular gasoline in the United States from September 1, 2014, to December 1, 2014, is modeled by the function F defined below, where F(x) is the average price per gallon x months after September 1. F(x) = 2.74 - 0.19(x - 3) The constant 2.74 in this function estimates which of the following?",
    "answer": "The average price per gallon on December 1, 2014",
    "explanation": "Since 2.74 is a constant term, it represents an actual price of gas rather than a measure of change in gas price. To determine what gas price it represents, find x such that F(x) = 2.74, or 2.74 = 2.74 - 0.19(x - 3). Subtracting 2.74 from both sides gives 0 = -0.19(x - 3). Dividing both sides by -0.19 results in 0 = x - 3, or x = 3. Therefore, the average price of gas is $2.74 per gallon 3 months after September 1, 2014, which is December 1, 2014."
  },
  {
    "id": 171,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The functions f and g are defined as f(x) = (1/4)x - 9 and g(x) = (3/4)x + 21. If the function h is defined as h(x) = f(x) + g(x), what is the x-coordinate of the x-intercept of the graph of y = h(x) in the xy-plane?",
    "answer": "-12",
    "explanation": "It's given that the functions f and g are defined as f(x) = (1/4)x - 9 and g(x) = (3/4)x + 21. If the function h is defined as h(x) = f(x) + g(x), then substituting (1/4)x - 9 for f(x) and (3/4)x + 21 for g(x) in this function yields h(x) = (1/4)x - 9 + (3/4)x + 21. This can be rewritten as h(x) = (4/4)x + 12, or h(x) = x + 12. The x-intercept of a graph in the xy-plane is the point on the graph where y = 0. The equation representing the graph of y = h(x) is y = x + 12. Substituting 0 for y in this equation yields 0 = x + 12. Subtracting 12 from both sides of this equation yields -12 = x, or x = -12. Therefore, the x-coordinate of the x-intercept of the graph of y = h(x) in the xy-plane is -12."
  },
  {
    "id": 172,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "F(x) = (9/5)(x - 273.15) + 32 The function F gives the temperature, in degrees Fahrenheit, that corresponds to a temperature of x kelvins. If a temperature increased by 9.10 kelvins, by how much did the temperature increase, in degrees Fahrenheit?",
    "answer": "16.38",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the function F(x) = (9/5)(x - 273.15) + 32 gives the temperature, in degrees Fahrenheit, that corresponds to a temperature of x kelvins. A temperature that increased by 9.10 kelvins means that the value of x increased by 9.10 kelvins. It follows that an increase in x by 9.10 increases F(x) by (9/5)(9.10), or 16.38. Therefore, if a temperature increased by 9.10 kelvins, the temperature increased by 16.38 degrees Fahrenheit."
  },
  {
    "id": 173,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The cost of renting a backhoe for up to 10 days is $270 for the first day and $135 for each additional day. Which of the following equations gives the cost y, in dollars, of renting the backhoe for x days, where x is a positive integer and x ≤ 10?",
    "answer": "y = 135x + 135",
    "explanation": "It's given that the cost of renting a backhoe for up to 10 days is $270 for the first day and $135 for each additional day. Therefore, the cost y, in dollars, for x days, where x ≤ 10, is the sum of the cost for the first day, $270, and the cost for the additional x - 1 days, $135(x - 1). It follows that y = 270 + 135(x - 1), which is equivalent to y = 135x + 135."
  },
  {
    "id": 174,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "An economist modeled the demand Q for a certain product as a linear function of the selling price P. The demand was 20,000 units when the selling price was $40 per unit, and the demand was 15,000 units when the selling price was $60 per unit. Based on the model, what is the demand, in units, when the selling price is $55 per unit?",
    "answer": "16250",
    "explanation": "Let the economist's model be the linear function Q = mP + b, where Q is the demand, P is the selling price, m is the slope of the line, and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the line in the xy-plane, where y = Q. Two pairs of the selling price P and the demand Q are given. Using the coordinate pairs (P, Q), two points that satisfy the function are (40, 20,000) and (60, 15,000). The slope m of the function can be found using the formula m = (Q2 - Q1) / (P2 - P1). Substituting the given values into this formula yields m = (15,000 - 20,000) / (60 - 40), or m = -250. Therefore, Q = -250P + b. The value of b can be found by substituting one of the points into the function. Substituting the values of P and Q from the point (40, 20,000) yields 20,000 = -250(40) + b, or 20,000 = -10,000 + b. Adding 10,000 to both sides of this equation yields b = 30,000. Therefore, the linear function the economist used as the model is Q = -250P + 30,000. Substituting 55 for P yields Q = -250(55) + 30,000 = 16,250. It follows that when the selling price is $55 per unit, the demand is 16,250 units."
  },
  {
    "id": 175,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A window repair specialist charges $220 for the first two hours of repair plus an hourly fee for each additional hour. The total cost for 5 hours of repair is $400. Which function f gives the total cost, in dollars, for x hours of repair, where x ≥ 2?",
    "answer": "f(x) = 60x + 100",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the window repair specialist charges $220 for the first two hours of repair plus an hourly fee for each additional hour after the first two hours. Since it’s given that x is the number of hours of repair, it follows that the charge generated by the hourly fee after the first two hours can be represented by the expression n(x - 2). Therefore, the total cost, in dollars, for x hours of repair is f(x) = 220 + n(x - 2). It’s given that the total cost for 5 hours of repair is $400. Substituting 5 for x and 400 for f(x) into the equation f(x) = 220 + n(x - 2) yields 400 = 220 + n(5 - 2), or 400 = 220 + 3n. Subtracting 220 from both sides of this equation yields 180 = 3n. Dividing both sides of this equation by 3 yields n = 60. Substituting 60 for n in the equation f(x) = 220 + n(x - 2) yields f(x) = 220 + 60(x - 2), which is equivalent to f(x) = 220 + 60x - 120, or f(x) = 60x + 100. Therefore, the total cost, in dollars, for x hours of repair is f(x) = 60x + 100."
  },
  {
    "id": 176,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A linear function f gives a company’s profit, in dollars, for selling x items. The company’s profit is $220 when it sells 8 items, and its profit is $320 when it sells 10 items. Which equation defines f?",
    "answer": "f(x) = 50x - 180",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the relationship between x and f(x) is linear. A linear function can be written in the form f(x) = mx + b, where m is the slope and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane. Given two points on a line, (x1, y1) and (x2, y2), the slope of the line can be found using the slope formula m = (y2 - y1) / (x2 - x1). It’s given that the company’s profit is $220 when it sells 8 items and the profit is $320 when it sells 10 items. Since f(x) represents the company's profit, in dollars, for selling x items, the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane passes through the points (8, 220) and (10, 320). Substituting (8, 220) and (10, 320) for (x1, y1) and (x2, y2), respectively, in the slope formula yields m = (320 - 220) / (10 - 8), which gives m = 100 / 2, or m = 50. Substituting 50 for m, 8 for x, and 220 for f(x) in f(x) = mx + b yields 220 = (50)(8) + b, or 220 = 400 + b. Subtracting 400 from each side of this equation yields -180 = b. Substituting 50 for m and -180 for b in f(x) = mx + b yields f(x) = 50x - 180. Therefore, the equation that defines f is f(x) = 50x - 180."
  },
  {
    "id": 177,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "For the linear function g, the graph of y = g(x) in the xy-plane has a slope of 2 and passes through the point (1,14). Which equation defines g?",
    "answer": "g(x) = 2x + 12",
    "explanation": "An equation defining a linear function can be written in the form g(x) = mx + b, where m is the slope and (0, b) is the y-intercept of the graph of y = g(x) in the xy-plane. It’s given that the graph of y = g(x) has a slope of 2. Therefore, m = 2. It’s also given that the graph of y = g(x) passes through the point (1,14). It follows that when x = 1, g(x) = 14. Substituting 1 for x, 14 for g(x), and 2 for m in the equation g(x) = mx + b yields 14 = 2(1) + b, or 14 = 2 + b. Subtracting 2 from each side of this equation yields 12 = b. Therefore, b = 12. Substituting 2 for m and 12 for b in the equation g(x) = mx + b yields g(x) = 2x + 12. Therefore, the equation that defines g is g(x) = 2x + 12."
  },
  {
    "id": 178,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = (x + 15)/5, and f(a) = 10, where a is a constant. What is the value of a?",
    "answer": "35",
    "explanation": "It's given that f(x) = (x + 15)/5 and f(a) = 10, where a is a constant. Therefore, for the given function f, when x = a, f(x) = 10. Substituting a for x and 10 for f(x) in the given function f yields 10 = (a + 15)/5. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 5 yields 50 = a + 15. Subtracting 15 from both sides of this equation yields 35 = a. Therefore, the value of a is 35."
  },
  {
    "id": 179,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "If f(x) = x + 7 and g(x) = 7x, what is the value of 4f(2) - g(2)?",
    "answer": "22",
    "explanation": "The value of f(2) can be found by substituting 2 for x in the given equation f(x) = x + 7, which yields f(2) = 2 + 7, or f(2) = 9. The value of g(2) can be found by substituting 2 for x in the given equation g(x) = 7x, which yields g(2) = 7(2), or g(2) = 14. The value of the expression 4f(2) - g(2) can be found by substituting the corresponding values into the expression, which gives 4(9) - 14. This expression is equivalent to 36 - 14, or 22."
  },
  {
    "id": 180,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = mx + b, where m and b are constants. If f(0) = 18 and f(1) = 20, what is the value of m?",
    "answer": "2",
    "explanation": "The slope-intercept form of an equation for a line is y = mx + b, where m is the slope and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept. Two ordered pairs, (x1, y1) and (x2, y2), can be used to compute the slope using the formula m = (y2 - y1) / (x2 - x1). It’s given that f(0) = 18 and f(1) = 20; therefore, the two ordered pairs for this line are (0,18) and (1,20). Substituting these values for (x1, y1) and (x2, y2) gives (20 - 18) / (1 - 0) = 2 / 1, or 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 181,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "For the linear function f, the table shows three values of x and their corresponding values of f(x). Function f is defined by f(x) = ax + b, where a and b are constants. What is the value of a - b? (1, -62), (2, 0), (3, 64)",
    "answer": "192",
    "explanation": "The table gives that f(x) = 0 when x = 2. Substituting 0 for f(x) and 2 for x into the equation f(x) = ax + b yields 0 = 2a + b. Subtracting 2a from both sides of this equation yields b = -2a. The table gives that f(x) = -64 when x = 1. Substituting -2a for b, -64 for f(x), and 1 for x into the equation f(x) = ax + b yields -64 = a(1) + (-2a). Combining like terms yields -64 = -a, or a = 64. Since b = -2a, substituting 64 for a into this equation gives b = (-2)(64), which yields b = -128. Thus, the value of a - b can be written as 64 - (-128), which is 192."
  },
  {
    "id": 182,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "Which function m models the number of minutes it will take Juan to ride x miles at this rate?",
    "answer": "The increase in the length, in centimeters, of the spring for each one-newton increase in the weight of the object",
    "explanation": "The value 2 is multiplied by w, the weight of the object. When the weight is 0, the length is 30 + 2(0) = 30 centimeters. If the weight increases by w newtons, the length increases by 2w centimeters, or 2 centimeters for each one-newton increase in weight."
  },
  {
    "id": 183,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "Kaylani used fabric measuring 5 yards in length to make each suit for a men's choir. The relationship between the number of suits that Kaylani made, x, and the total length of fabric that she purchased y, in yards, is represented by the equation y - 5x = 6. What is the best interpretation of 6 in this context?",
    "answer": "Kaylani purchased 6 yards more fabric than she used to make the suits.",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the equation y - 5x = 6 represents the relationship between the number of suits that Kaylani made, x, and the total length of fabric she purchased, y, in yards. Adding 5x to both sides of the given equation yields y = 5x + 6. Since Kaylani made x suits and used 5 yards of fabric to make each suit, the expression 5x represents the total amount of fabric she used to make the suits. Since y represents the total length of fabric Kaylani purchased, in yards, it follows from the equation y = 5x + 6 that Kaylani purchased 5x yards of fabric to make the suits, plus an additional 6 yards of fabric. Therefore, the best interpretation of 6 in this context is that Kaylani purchased 6 yards more fabric than she used to make the suits."
  },
  {
    "id": 184,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "(-11, 21), (-10, 18), (-9, 15), (-8, 12) The table above shows some values of x and their corresponding values f(x) for the linear function f. What is the x-intercept of the graph of y = f(x) in the xy-plane?",
    "answer": "(-4,0)",
    "explanation": "The equation of a linear function can be written in the form y = mx + b, where m is the slope of the graph of y = f(x), and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the graph. The value of m can be found using the slope formula, m = (y2 - y1)/(x2 - x1). According to the table, the points (-11,21) and (-10,18) lie on the graph of y = f(x). Using these two points in the slope formula yields m = (18 - 21)/(-10 + 11), or -3. Substituting -3 for m in the slope-intercept form of the equation yields y = -3x + b. The value of b can be found by substituting values from the table and solving; for example, substituting the coordinates of the point (-11,21) into the equation y = -3x + b gives 21 = -3(-11) + b, which yields b = -12. This means the function given by the table can be represented by the equation y = -3x - 12. The value of the x-intercept of the graph of y = f(x) can be determined by finding the value of x when y = 0. Substituting y = 0 into y = -3x - 12 yields 0 = -3x - 12, or x = -4. This corresponds to the point (-4,0)."
  },
  {
    "id": 185,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function F(x) = (9/5)(x - 273.15) + 32 gives the temperature, in degrees Fahrenheit, that corresponds to a temperature of x kelvins. If a temperature increased by 2.10 kelvins, by how much did the temperature increase, in degrees Fahrenheit?",
    "answer": "3.78",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the function F(x) = (9/5)(x - 273.15) + 32 gives the temperature, in degrees Fahrenheit, that corresponds to a temperature of x kelvins. A temperature that increased by 2.10 kelvins means that the value of x increased by 2.10 kelvins. It follows that an increase in x by 2.10 increases F(x) by (9/5)(2.10), or 3.78. Therefore, if a temperature increased by 2.10 kelvins, the temperature increased by 3.78 degrees Fahrenheit."
  },
  {
    "id": 186,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "For groups of 25 or more people, a museum charges $21 per person for the first 25 people and $14 for each additional person. Which function f gives the total charge, in dollars, for a tour group with n people, where n ≥ 25?",
    "answer": "f(n) = 14n + 175",
    "explanation": "A tour group with n people, where n ≥ 25, can be split into two subgroups: the first 25 people and the additional n - 25 people. Since the museum charges $21 per person for the first 25 people and $14 for each additional person, the charge for the first 25 people is 21(25) and the charge for the additional n - 25 people is 14(n - 25). Therefore, the total charge, in dollars, is given by the function f(n) = 21(25) + 14(n - 25), or f(n) = 14n + 175."
  },
  {
    "id": 187,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "For the function f, if f(3x) = x - 6 for all values of x, what is the value of f(6)?",
    "answer": "-4",
    "explanation": "It’s given that f(3x) = x - 6 for all values of x. If 3x = 6, then f(3x) will equal f(6). Dividing both sides of 3x = 6 by 3 gives x = 2. Therefore, substituting 2 for x in the given equation yields f(3 × 2) = 2 - 6, which can be rewritten as f(6) = -4."
  },
  {
    "id": 188,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "One gallon of paint will cover 220 square feet of a surface. A room has a total wall area of w square feet. Which equation represents the total amount of paint P, in gallons, needed to paint the walls of the room twice?",
    "answer": "P = w / 110",
    "explanation": "It's given that w represents the total wall area, in square feet. Since the walls of the room will be painted twice, the amount of paint, in gallons, needs to cover 2w square feet. It’s also given that one gallon of paint will cover 220 square feet. Dividing the total area, in square feet, of the surface to be painted by the number of square feet covered by one gallon of paint gives the number of gallons of paint that will be needed. Dividing 2w by 220 yields (2w / 220), or (w / 110). Therefore, the equation that represents the total amount of paint P, in gallons, needed to paint the walls of the room twice is P = w / 110."
  },
  {
    "id": 189,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "Oil and gas production in a certain area dropped from 4 million barrels in 2000 to 1.9 million barrels in 2013. Assuming that the oil and gas production decreased at a constant rate, which of the following Linear functions f best models the production, in millions of barrels, t years after the year 2000?",
    "answer": "f(t) = (-21 / 130) t + 4",
    "explanation": "It is assumed that the oil and gas production decreased at a constant rate. Therefore, the function f that best models the production t years after the year 2000 can be written as a linear function, f(t) = mt + b, where m is the rate of change of the oil and gas production and b is the oil and gas production, in millions of barrels, in the year 2000. Since there were 4 million barrels of oil and gas produced in 2000, b = 4. The rate of change, m, can be calculated as (4 - 1.9) / (0 - 13) = (-2.1) / (13), which is equivalent to (-21 / 130), the rate of change in choice C."
  },
  {
    "id": 190,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Line r in the xy-plane has a slope of 4 and passes through the point (0,6). Which equation defines line r?",
    "answer": "y = 4x + 6",
    "explanation": "A line in the xy-plane with a slope of m and a y-intercept of (0, b) can be defined by an equation in the form y = mx + b. It’s given that line r has a slope of 4 and passes through the point (0,6). It follows that m = 4 and b = 6. Substituting 4 for m and 6 for b in the equation y = mx + b yields y = 4x + 6. Therefore, the equation y = 4x + 6 defines line r."
  },
  {
    "id": 191,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A machine makes large boxes or small boxes, one at a time, for a total of 700 minutes each day. It takes the machine 10 minutes to make a large box or 5 minutes to make a small box. Which equation represents the possible number of large boxes, x, and small boxes, y, the machine can make each day? ",
    "answer": "10x + 5y = 700",
    "explanation": "It’s given that it takes the machine 10 minutes to make a large box. It’s also given that x represents the possible number of large boxes the machine can make each day. Multiplying 10 by x gives 10x, which represents the amount of time spent making large boxes. It’s given that it takes the machine 5 minutes to make a small box. It’s also given that y represents the possible number of small boxes the machine can make each day. Multiplying 5 by y gives 5y, which represents the amount of time spent making small boxes. Combining the amount of time spent making x large boxes and y small boxes yields 10x + 5y. It’s given that the machine makes boxes for a total of 700 minutes each day. Therefore, 10x + 5y = 700 represents the possible number of large boxes, x, and small boxes, y, the machine can make each day."
  },
  {
    "id": 192,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "x + y = 75 The equation above relates the number of minutes, x, Maria spends running each day and the number of minutes, y, she spends biking each day. In the equation, what does the number 75 represent?",
    "answer": "The total number of minutes spent running and biking each day",
    "explanation": "Maria spends x minutes running each day and y minutes biking each day. Therefore, x + y represents the total number of minutes Maria spent running and biking each day. Because x + y = 75, it follows that 75 is the total number of minutes that Maria spent running and biking each day."
  },
  {
    "id": 193,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "What is the equation of the line that passes through the point (0,5) and is parallel to the graph of y = 7x + 4 in the xy-plane?",
    "answer": "y = 7x + 5",
    "explanation": "The equation of a line in the xy-plane can be written in slope-intercept form y = mx + b, where m is the slope of the line and (0, b) is its y-intercept. It’s given that the line passes through the point (0,5). Therefore, b = 5. It’s also given that the line is parallel to the graph of y = 7x + 4, which means the line has the same slope as the graph of y = 7x + 4. The slope of the graph of y = 7x + 4 is 7. Therefore, m = 7. Substituting 7 for m and 5 for b in the equation y = mx + b yields y = 7x + 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 194,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "3a + 4b = 25 A shipping company charged a customer $25 to ship some small boxes and some large boxes. The equation above represents the relationship between a, the number of small boxes, and b, the number of large boxes, the customer had shipped. If the customer had 3 small boxes shipped, how many large boxes were shipped?",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "It’s given that a represents the number of small boxes and b represents the number of large boxes the customer had shipped. If the customer had 3 small boxes shipped, then a = 3. Substituting 3 for a in the equation 3a + 4b = 25 yields 3(3) + 4b = 25 or 9 + 4b = 25. Subtracting 9 from both sides of the equation yields 4b = 16. Dividing both sides of this equation by 4 yields b = 4. Therefore, the customer had 4 large boxes shipped."
  },
  {
    "id": 195,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A mixture consisting of only vitamin D and calcium has a total mass of 150 grams. The mass of vitamin D in the mixture is 50 grams. What is the mass, in grams, of calcium in the mixture?",
    "answer": "100",
    "explanation": "Let d represent the mass, in grams, of vitamin D in the mixture, and let c represent the mass, in grams, of calcium in the mixture. It’s given that the mixture consists of only vitamin D and calcium and that the total mass of the mixture is 150 grams. Therefore, the equation d + c = 150 represents this situation. It’s also given that the mass of vitamin D in the mixture is 50 grams. Substituting 50 for d in the equation d + c = 150 yields 50 + c = 150. Subtracting 50 from both sides of this equation yields c = 100. Therefore, the mass of calcium in the mixture is 100 grams."
  },
  {
    "id": 196,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Line k is defined by y = 3x + 15. Line j is perpendicular to line k in the xy-plane. What is the slope of line j?",
    "answer": "-1/3",
    "explanation": "It’s given that line j is perpendicular to line k in the xy-plane. It follows that the slope of line j is the opposite reciprocal of the slope of line k. The equation for line k is written in slope-intercept form y = mx + b, where m is the slope of the line and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the line. It follows that the slope of line k is 3. The opposite reciprocal of a number is -1 divided by the number. Thus, the opposite reciprocal of 3 is -1/3. Therefore, the slope of line j is -1/3."
  },
  {
    "id": 197,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "4x + 3y = 24 Mario purchased 4 binders that cost x dollars each and 3 notebooks that cost y dollars each. If the given equation represents this situation, which of the following is the best interpretation of 24 in this context?",
    "answer": "The total cost, in dollars, for all binders and notebooks purchased",
    "explanation": "Since Mario purchased 4 binders that cost x dollars each, the expression 4x represents the total cost, in dollars, of the 4 binders he purchased. Since Mario purchased 3 notebooks that cost y dollars each, the expression 3y represents the total cost, in dollars, of the 3 notebooks he purchased. Therefore, the expression 4x + 3y represents the total cost, in dollars, for all binders and notebooks he purchased. In the given equation, the expression 4x + 3y is equal to 24. Therefore, it follows that 24 is the total cost, in dollars, for all binders and notebooks purchased."
  },
  {
    "id": 198,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A food truck buys forks for 0.04 dollars each and plates for 0.48 dollars each. The total cost of x forks and y plates is 661.76 dollars. Which equation represents this situation?",
    "answer": "0.04x + 0.48y = 661.76",
    "explanation": "It's given that the food truck buys forks for 0.04 dollars each. Therefore, the cost, in dollars, of x forks can be represented by the expression 0.04x. It's also given that the food truck buys plates for 0.48 dollars each. Therefore, the cost, in dollars, of y plates can be represented by the expression 0.48y. Since the total cost of x forks and y plates is 661.76 dollars, the equation 0.04x + 0.48y = 661.76 represents this situation."
  },
  {
    "id": 199,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A city's total expense budget for one year was x million dollars. The city budgeted y million dollars for departmental expenses and 201 million dollars for all other expenses. Which of the following represents the relationship between x and y in this context?",
    "answer": "x - y = 201",
    "explanation": "Of the city's total expense budget for one year, the city budgeted y million dollars for departmental expenses and 201 million dollars for all other expenses. This means that the expression y + 201 represents the total expense budget, in millions of dollars, for one year. It’s given that the total expense budget for one year is x million dollars. It follows then that the expression y + 201 is equivalent to x, or y + 201 = x. Subtracting y from both sides of this equation yields 201 = x - y. By the symmetric property of equality, this is the same as x - y = 201."
  },
  {
    "id": 200,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "The y-intercept of the graph of 12x + 2y = 18 in the xy-plane is (0, y). What is the value of y?",
    "answer": "9",
    "explanation": "It's given that the y-intercept of the graph of 12x + 2y = 18 in the xy-plane is (0, y). Substituting 0 for x in the equation 12x + 2y = 18 yields 12(0) + 2y = 18, or 2y = 18. Dividing both sides of this equation by 2 yields y = 9. Therefore, the value of y is 9."
  },
  {
    "id": 201,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "An employee at a restaurant prepares sandwiches and salads. It takes the employee 1.5 minutes to prepare a sandwich and 1.9 minutes to prepare a salad. The employee spends a total of 46.1 minutes preparing x sandwiches and y salads. Which equation represents this situation?",
    "answer": "1.5x + 1.9y = 46.1",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the employee takes 1.5 minutes to prepare a sandwich. Multiplying 1.5 by the number of sandwiches, x, yields 1.5x, the amount of time the employee spends preparing x sandwiches. It’s also given that the employee takes 1.9 minutes to prepare a salad. Multiplying 1.9 by the number of salads, y, yields 1.9y, the amount of time the employee spends preparing y salads. It follows that the total amount of time, in minutes, the employee spends preparing x sandwiches and y salads is 1.5x + 1.9y. It's given that the employee spends a total of 46.1 minutes preparing x sandwiches and y salads. Thus, the equation 1.5x + 1.9y = 46.1 represents this situation."
  },
  {
    "id": 202,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "The equation y = 0.1x models the relationship between the number of different pieces of music a certain pianist practices, y, during an x-minute practice session. How many pieces did the pianist practice if the session lasted 30 minutes?",
    "answer": "3",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the equation y = 0.1x models the relationship between the number of different pieces of music a certain pianist practices, y, and the number of minutes in a practice session, x. Since it’s given that the session lasted 30 minutes, the number of pieces the pianist practiced can be found by substituting 30 for x in the given equation, which yields y = 0.1(30), or y = 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 203,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A total of 364 paper straws of equal length were used to construct two types of polygons: triangles and rectangles. The triangles and rectangles were constructed so that no two polygons had a common side. The equation 3x + 4y = 364 represents this situation, where x is the number of triangles constructed and y is the number of rectangles constructed. What is the best interpretation of (x, y) = (24, 73) in this context?",
    "answer": "If 24 triangles were constructed, then 73 rectangles were constructed.",
    "explanation": "It's given that 364 paper straws of equal length were used to construct triangles and rectangles, where no two polygons had a common side. It's also given that the equation 3x + 4y = 364 represents this situation, where x is the number of triangles constructed and y is the number of rectangles constructed. The equation (x, y) = (24, 73) means that if x = 24, then y = 73. Substituting 24 for x and 73 for y in 3x + 4y = 364 yields 3(24) + 4(73) = 364, or 364 = 364, which is true. Therefore, in this context, the equation (x, y) = (24, 73) means that if 24 triangles were constructed, then 73 rectangles were constructed."
  },
  {
    "id": 204,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Vivian bought party hats and cupcakes for $71. Each package of party hats cost $3, and each cupcake cost $1. If Vivian bought 10 packages of party hats, how many cupcakes did she buy?",
    "answer": "41",
    "explanation": "The number of cupcakes Vivian bought can be found by first finding the amount Vivian spent on cupcakes. The amount Vivian spent on cupcakes can be found by subtracting the amount Vivian spent on party hats from the total amount Vivian spent. The amount Vivian spent on party hats can be found by multiplying the cost per package of party hats by the number of packages of party hats, which yields $3 * 10 = $30. Subtracting the amount Vivian spent on party hats, $30, from the total amount Vivian spent, $71, yields $71 - $30, or $41. Since the amount Vivian spent on cupcakes was $41 and each cupcake cost $1, it follows that Vivian bought 41 cupcakes."
  },
  {
    "id": 205,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A line in the xy-plane has a slope of 1/9 and passes through the point (0, 14). Which equation represents this line?",
    "answer": "y = 1/9 x + 14",
    "explanation": "The equation of a line in the xy-plane can be written as y = mx + b, where m represents the slope of the line and (0, b) represents the y-intercept of the line. It's given that the slope of the line is 1/9. It follows that m = 1/9. It's also given that the line passes through the point (0, 14). It follows that b = 14. Substituting 1/9 for m and 14 for b in y = mx + b yields y = 1/9 x + 14. Thus, the equation y = 1/9 x + 14 represents this line."
  },
  {
    "id": 206,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "The equation 46 = 2x + 2y gives the perimeter of a rectangular rug that has length x, in feet, and width y, in feet. The width of the rug is 8 feet. What is the length, in feet, of the rug?",
    "answer": "15",
    "explanation": "It's given that the equation 46 = 2x + 2y gives the perimeter of a rectangular rug that has length x, in feet, and width y, in feet. It's also given that the width of the rug is 8 feet. Substituting 8 for y in the equation 46 = 2x + 2y yields 46 = 2x + 2(8), or 46 = 2x + 16. Subtracting 16 from both sides of this equation yields 30 = 2x. Dividing both sides of this equation by 2 yields 15 = x. Since x represents the length, in feet, of the rug, it follows that the length of the rug is 15 feet."
  },
  {
    "id": 207,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Tony spends $80 per month on public transportation. A 10-ride pass costs $12.50, and a single-ride pass costs $1.50. If g represents the number of 10-ride passes Tony buys in a month and t represents the number of single-ride passes Tony buys in a month, which of the following equations best represents the relationship between g and t?",
    "answer": "12.50g + 1.50t = 80",
    "explanation": "Since a 10-ride pass costs $12.50 and g is the number of 10-ride passes Tony buys in a month, the expression 12.50g represents the amount Tony spends on 10-ride passes in a month. Since a single-ride pass costs $1.50 and t is the number of single-ride passes Tony buys in a month, the expression 1.50t represents the amount Tony spends on single-ride passes in a month. Therefore, the sum 12.50g + 1.50t represents the amount he spends on the two types of passes in a month. Since Tony spends a total of $80 on passes in a month, this expression can be set equal to 80, producing 12.50g + 1.50t = 80."
  },
  {
    "id": 208,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "(0, 18), (1, 13), (2, 8) The table shows three values of x and their corresponding values of y. There is a linear relationship between x and y. Which of the following equations represents this relationship?",
    "answer": "y = -5x + 18",
    "explanation": "A linear relationship can be represented by an equation of the form y = mx + b, where m and b are constants. It’s given in the table that when x = 0, y = 18. Substituting 0 for x and 18 for y in y = mx + b yields 18 = m(0) + b, or 18 = b. Substituting 18 for b in the equation y = mx + b yields y = mx + 18. It’s also given in the table that when x = 1, y = 13. Substituting 1 for x and 13 for y in the equation y = mx + 18 yields 13 = m(1) + 18, or 13 = m + 18. Subtracting 18 from both sides of this equation yields -5 = m. Therefore, the equation y = -5x + 18 represents the relationship between x and y."
  },
  {
    "id": 209,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "The equation 40x + 20y = 160 represents the number of sweaters, x, and number of shirts, y, that Yesenia purchased for $160. If Yesenia purchased 2 sweaters, how many shirts did she purchase?",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "It's given that the equation 40x + 20y = 160 represents the number of sweaters, x, and the number of shirts, y, that Yesenia purchased for $160. If Yesenia purchased 2 sweaters, the number of shirts she purchased can be calculated by substituting 2 for x in the given equation, which yields 40(2) + 20y = 160, or 80 + 20y = 160. Subtracting 80 from both sides of this equation yields 20y = 80. Dividing both sides of this equation by 20 yields y = 4. Therefore, if Yesenia purchased 2 sweaters, she purchased 4 shirts."
  },
  {
    "id": 210,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "In the xy-plane, a line has a slope of 6 and passes through the point (0,8). Which of the following is an equation of this line?",
    "answer": "y = 6x + 8",
    "explanation": "The slope-intercept form of an equation for a line is y = mx + b, where m is the slope of the line and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the line. It’s given that the slope is 6, so m = 6. It’s also given that the line passes through the point (0,8) on the y-axis, so b = 8. Substituting m = 6 and b = 8 into the equation y = mx + b gives y = 6x + 8."
  },
  {
    "id": 211,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 2x-4=10 what is x?",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "Add 4 to both sides to get 2x=14 then divide by 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 212,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 5x=35 what is x?",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 213,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If x+7=15 what is x?",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "Subtract 7 from both sides."
  },
  {
    "id": 214,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 4x-8=12 what is x?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Add 8 to both sides to get 4x=20 then divide by 4."
  },
  {
    "id": 215,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 7x+3=31.",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "Subtract 3 from both sides to obtain 7x=28 then divide by 7."
  },
  {
    "id": 216,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 9x=54 what is x?",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 9."
  },
  {
    "id": 217,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 8x+16=40.",
    "answer": "3",
    "explanation": "Subtract 16 from both sides to obtain 8x=24 then divide by 8."
  },
  {
    "id": 218,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 6x-9=15.",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "Add 9 to both sides to get 6x=24 then divide by 6."
  },
  {
    "id": 219,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 10x+5=65.",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Subtract 5 from both sides to get 10x=60 then divide by 10."
  },
  {
    "id": 220,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If x/2=6 what is x?",
    "answer": "12",
    "explanation": "Multiply both sides by 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 221,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 12-x=3.",
    "answer": "9",
    "explanation": "Subtract 3 from 12 to get x=9."
  },
  {
    "id": 222,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 2x+3=13 what is x?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Subtract 3 from both sides to obtain 2x=10 then divide by 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 223,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5(x-2)=15.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 5 to get x-2=3 then add 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 224,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 3(x+4)=21.",
    "answer": "3",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 3 to obtain x+4=7 then subtract 4."
  },
  {
    "id": 225,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 7-x=2.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Subtract 2 from 7 to get x=5."
  },
  {
    "id": 226,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 4x=28 what is x?",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 4."
  },
  {
    "id": 227,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve x+12=20.",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "Subtract 12 from both sides."
  },
  {
    "id": 228,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 3x-2=16 what is x?",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Add 2 to both sides to get 3x=18 then divide by 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 229,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 2(x+5)=18.",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 2 to get x+5=9 then subtract 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 230,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 5x-10=15 what is x?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Add 10 to both sides to get 5x=25 then divide by 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 231,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 8+x=14.",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Subtract 8 from both sides."
  },
  {
    "id": 232,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 9-x=4 what is x?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Subtract 4 from 9 to obtain x=5."
  },
  {
    "id": 233,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 6x+3=33.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Subtract 3 from both sides to get 6x=30 then divide by 6."
  },
  {
    "id": 234,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 3x=24 what is x?",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 235,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 2x+8=18.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Subtract 8 from both sides to get 2x=10 then divide by 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 236,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 4x-4=20 what is x?",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Add 4 to both sides to get 4x=24 then divide by 4."
  },
  {
    "id": 237,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve x/3=7.",
    "answer": "21",
    "explanation": "Multiply both sides by 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 238,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 11x=55 what is x?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 11."
  },
  {
    "id": 239,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5x+7=32.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Subtract 7 from both sides to get 5x=25 then divide by 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 240,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If x-9=6 what is x?",
    "answer": "15",
    "explanation": "Add 9 to both sides."
  },
  {
    "id": 241,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 2(x-3)=10.",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 2 to obtain x-3=5 then add 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 242,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 3(x-2)=12.",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 3 to get x-2=4 then add 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 243,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 4(x+3)=28.",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 4 to obtain x+3=7 then subtract 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 244,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 2x+6=14 what is x?",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "Subtract 6 from both sides to get 2x=8 then divide by 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 245,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 3x-5=10.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Add 5 to both sides to obtain 3x=15 then divide by 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 246,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 6x+2=20 what is x?",
    "answer": "3",
    "explanation": "Subtract 2 from both sides to get 6x=18 then divide by 6."
  },
  {
    "id": 247,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 2x-3=7.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Add 3 to both sides to obtain 2x=10 then divide by 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 248,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If x/4=5 what is x?",
    "answer": "20",
    "explanation": "Multiply both sides by 4."
  },
  {
    "id": 249,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5x=40.",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 250,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 6x+9=45.",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Subtract 9 from both sides to get 6x=36 then divide by 6."
  },
  {
    "id": 251,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 7x-14=21 what is x?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Add 14 to both sides to get 7x=35 then divide by 7."
  },
  {
    "id": 252,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 3(x+2)=18.",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 3 to obtain x+2=6 then subtract 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 253,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 8x=64 what is x?",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 8."
  },
  {
    "id": 254,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve x+15=30.",
    "answer": "15",
    "explanation": "Subtract 15 from both sides."
  },
  {
    "id": 255,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 2x-10=0 what is x?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Add 10 to both sides to get 2x=10 then divide by 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 256,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 4x+8=40.",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "Subtract 8 from both sides to obtain 4x=32 then divide by 4."
  },
  {
    "id": 257,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 3x+6=27 what is x?",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "Subtract 6 from both sides to get 3x=21 then divide by 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 258,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5x-5=20.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Add 5 to both sides to get 5x=25 then divide by 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 259,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 2x+12=20 what is x?",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "Subtract 12 from both sides to obtain 2x=8 then divide by 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 260,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 7(x-1)=42.",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 7 to get x-1=6 then add 1."
  },
  {
    "id": 261,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 8x+4=36 what is x?",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "Subtract 4 from both sides to obtain 8x=32 then divide by 8."
  },
  {
    "id": 262,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 9x-9=36.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Add 9 to both sides to get 9x=45 then divide by 9."
  },
  {
    "id": 263,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If x+18=24 what is x?",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Subtract 18 from both sides."
  },
  {
    "id": 264,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 2(x+4)=20.",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 2 to obtain x+4=10 then subtract 4."
  },
  {
    "id": 265,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 3x-6=12 what is x?",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Add 6 to both sides to get 3x=18 then divide by 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 266,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 4(x-2)=16.",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 4 to obtain x-2=4 then add 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 267,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 5x+10=35 what is x?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Subtract 10 from both sides to get 5x=25 then divide by 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 268,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 6(x+3)=54.",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 6 to obtain x+3=9 then subtract 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 269,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 7x-7=42 what is x?",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "Add 7 to both sides to get 7x=49 then divide by 7."
  },
  {
    "id": 270,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 8(x-1)=56.",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 8 to obtain x-1=7 then add 1."
  },
  {
    "id": 271,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 9x+9=90 what is x?",
    "answer": "9",
    "explanation": "Subtract 9 from both sides to get 9x=81 then divide by 9."
  },
  {
    "id": 272,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 10x-20=30.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Add 20 to both sides to obtain 10x=50 then divide by 10."
  },
  {
    "id": 273,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 11x+11=66 what is x?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Subtract 11 from both sides to get 11x=55 then divide by 11."
  },
  {
    "id": 274,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 12x-12=36.",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "Add 12 to both sides to obtain 12x=48 then divide by 12."
  },
  {
    "id": 275,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 2x+14=28 what is x?",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "Subtract 14 from both sides to get 2x=14 then divide by 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 276,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 3(x+3)=24.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 3 to obtain x+3=8 then subtract 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 277,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 4x-2=14 what is x?",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "Add 2 to both sides to get 4x=16 then divide by 4."
  },
  {
    "id": 278,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5(x+2)=35.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 5 to obtain x+2=7 then subtract 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 279,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 6x+4=40 what is x?",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Subtract 4 from both sides to get 6x=36 then divide by 6."
  },
  {
    "id": 280,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 7x-21=14.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Add 21 to both sides to obtain 7x=35 then divide by 7."
  },
  {
    "id": 281,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 8x+16=80 what is x?",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "Subtract 16 from both sides to get 8x=64 then divide by 8."
  },
  {
    "id": 282,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 9x-18=27.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Add 18 to both sides to obtain 9x=45 then divide by 9."
  },
  {
    "id": 283,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If x-11=0 what is x?",
    "answer": "11",
    "explanation": "Solve directly to obtain x=11."
  },
  {
    "id": 284,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 2(x-2)=12.",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 2 to obtain x-2=6 then add 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 285,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 3x+3=24 what is x?",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "Subtract 3 from both sides to get 3x=21 then divide by 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 286,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 4(x+2)=32.",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 4 to obtain x+2=8 then subtract 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 287,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 5x-15=10 what is x?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Add 15 to both sides to get 5x=25 then divide by 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 288,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 6x+6=42.",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Subtract 6 from both sides to obtain 6x=36 then divide by 6."
  },
  {
    "id": 289,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 7x+7=56 what is x?",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "Subtract 7 from both sides to get 7x=49 then divide by 7."
  },
  {
    "id": 290,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 8x-8=32.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Add 8 to both sides to get 8x=40 then divide by 8."
  },
  {
    "id": 291,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 9x+0=81 what is x?",
    "answer": "9",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 9."
  },
  {
    "id": 292,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 10x+5=55.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Subtract 5 from both sides to get 10x=50 then divide by 10."
  },
  {
    "id": 293,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 11x-11=33.",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "Add 11 to both sides to obtain 11x=44 then divide by 11."
  },
  {
    "id": 294,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 12(x+1)=84.",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 12 to get x+1=7 then subtract 1."
  },
  {
    "id": 295,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "If 2x+10=30 what is x?",
    "answer": "10",
    "explanation": "Subtract 10 from both sides to get 2x=20 then divide by 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 296,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 3x+0=27.",
    "answer": "9",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 297,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 4x-4=12.",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "Add 4 to both sides to obtain 4x=16 then divide by 4."
  },
  {
    "id": 298,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5(x-3)=10.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 5 to get x-3=2 then add 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 299,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 6x+12=48.",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Subtract 12 from both sides to get 6x=36 then divide by 6."
  },
  {
    "id": 300,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 7x+14=63.",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "Subtract 14 from both sides to obtain 7x=49 then divide by 7."
  },
  {
    "id": 301,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 8x-16=32.",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Add 16 to both sides to get 8x=48 then divide by 8."
  },
  {
    "id": 302,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 9x+9=72.",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "Subtract 9 from both sides to get 9x=63 then divide by 9."
  },
  {
    "id": 303,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve x+20=40.",
    "answer": "20",
    "explanation": "Subtract 20 from both sides."
  },
  {
    "id": 304,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 2x-6=10.",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "Add 6 to both sides to get 2x=16 then divide by 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 305,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 3x+12=33.",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "Subtract 12 from both sides to get 3x=21 then divide by 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 306,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 4(x-4)=16.",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 4 to obtain x-4=4 then add 4."
  },
  {
    "id": 307,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5x+5=30.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Subtract 5 from both sides to get 5x=25 then divide by 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 308,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 6(x+2)=48.",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 6 to obtain x+2=8 then subtract 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 309,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 7x-7=0.",
    "answer": "1",
    "explanation": "Add 7 to both sides to obtain 7x=7 then divide by 7."
  },
  {
    "id": 310,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 12 - x = 3.",
    "answer": "9",
    "explanation": "Subtract 3 from 12 to obtain x = 9."
  },
  {
    "id": 311,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 7 - x = 2.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Subtract 2 from 7 to obtain x = 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 312,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve x + 12 = 20.",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "Subtract 12 from both sides."
  },
  {
    "id": 313,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 8 + x = 14.",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Subtract 8 from both sides."
  },
  {
    "id": 314,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve x/3 = 7.",
    "answer": "21",
    "explanation": "Multiply both sides by 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 315,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5x = 40.",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 316,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5(t + 3) - 7(t + 3) = 38.",
    "answer": "-22",
    "explanation": "Factor out (t+3): (5-7)(t+3) = -2(t+3)=38, so t+3 = -19 and t = -22."
  },
  {
    "id": 317,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "A factory produces a product costing $65 to make. A salesperson earns 20% commission on a $100 sale. The profit per unit is the sales price minus commission and cost. Form an equation for profit and find the number of units, u, needed to earn a total profit of $6840.",
    "answer": "456",
    "explanation": "Commission: 20% of 100 = $20, so net revenue = 100–20 = 80; profit per unit = 80–65 = 15. Then 15u=6840, so u=6840/15=456."
  },
  {
    "id": 318,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Determine the constant k for which the equation 3(kx + 13) = (48/17)x + 36 has no solution.",
    "answer": "16/17",
    "explanation": "Divide both sides by 3 to obtain kx+13 = (16/17)x+12. For a solution to exist the coefficients must match but here the constants conflict."
  },
  {
    "id": 319,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 7(2x - 3) - 4(3x - 5) = 2(5x - 8) + 6.",
    "answer": "2025-09-08 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "Expand: 14x -21 -12x +20 = 2(5x - 8)+6 → 2x -1 = 10x -10. Then, 2x -1 = 10x -10 leads to 8x = 9, so x = 9/8."
  },
  {
    "id": 320,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve (4x + 8)/2 - (x - 3)/3 = 7.",
    "answer": "2025-06-05 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "Multiply both sides by 6: 3(4x+8) - 2(x-3)=42, i.e. 12x+24 -2x+6 =42, so 10x+30=42; hence, x=12/10=6/5."
  },
  {
    "id": 321,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Determine the constant k such that the equation 4(x - 2) + k = 4x - 8 has infinitely many solutions.",
    "answer": "0",
    "explanation": "Expanding gives 4x - 8 + k = 4x - 8. For equality for all x, k must be 0."
  },
  {
    "id": 322,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve (5x - 7)/3 = (2x + 8)/4 + 1.",
    "answer": "32/7",
    "explanation": "Multiply by 12: 4(5x-7)=3(2x+8)+12, i.e. 20x-28=6x+24+12 → 20x-28=6x+36; then, 14x=64 and x=64/14=32/7."
  },
  {
    "id": 323,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve (3x + 4)/5 - (2x - 6)/3 = 2.",
    "answer": "12",
    "explanation": "Multiply by 15: 3(3x+4)-5(2x-6)=30, i.e. 9x+12-10x+30=30 → -x+42=30, so x=12."
  },
  {
    "id": 324,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5x/2 - 3 = 7x/4 + 1.",
    "answer": "16/3",
    "explanation": "Multiply by 4: 10x-12=7x+4, then 3x=16, so x=16/3."
  },
  {
    "id": 325,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 2(x + 4) - 3(2x - 1) = 5.",
    "answer": "1.5",
    "explanation": "Expand: 2x+8 -6x+3 = 5 → -4x+11=5, so -4x=-6 and x=1.5."
  },
  {
    "id": 326,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 6(2x - 5) + 4(3x + 1) = 8(3x - 2) + 10.",
    "answer": "\"No solution\"",
    "explanation": "Expanding gives 12x -30 + 12x +4 = 24x -16+10, i.e. 24x -26 = 24x -6, which reduces to -26 = -6, a contradiction."
  },
  {
    "id": 327,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 7(3x - 4) - 2(5x + 3) = 3(4x - 2) - 8.",
    "answer": "-20",
    "explanation": "Expand: 21x-28 -10x-6 =12x-6-8 → 11x-34 =12x-14, so x = -20."
  },
  {
    "id": 328,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 8(x - 2) + 5 = 3(2x + 1) + 7.",
    "answer": "10.5",
    "explanation": "Expand: 8x-16+5 = 6x+3+7 → 8x-11 = 6x+10; then 2x=21, so x=10.5."
  },
  {
    "id": 329,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 9x - 4(2x - 3) = 5x + 2.",
    "answer": "2.5",
    "explanation": "Expand: 9x -8x+12 =5x+2, so x+12=5x+2, hence 4x=10 and x=2.5."
  },
  {
    "id": 330,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 3(2x + 7) - 2(4x - 5) = x + 24.",
    "answer": "2025-07-03 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "Expand: 6x+21 -8x+10 = x+24, i.e. -2x+31=x+24, so 3x=7 and x=7/3."
  },
  {
    "id": 331,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 4(3x - 2) - 3(2x + 1) = 2.",
    "answer": "13/6",
    "explanation": "Expand: 12x-8 -6x-3 = 2, i.e. 6x-11=2, so 6x=13 and x=13/6."
  },
  {
    "id": 332,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5(x + 2) - 2(3x - 4) = 1.",
    "answer": "17",
    "explanation": "Expand: 5x+10 -6x+8 =1, so -x+18=1 and x=17."
  },
  {
    "id": 333,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 7(2x - 3) + 4(3x + 5) = 5(4x + 1) - 9.",
    "answer": "-0.5",
    "explanation": "Expand: 14x-21 +12x+20 =20x+5-9, i.e. 26x -1 =20x -4, so 6x= -3 and x=-0.5."
  },
  {
    "id": 334,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 2(4x - 3) + 3(2x + 5) = 5(3x + 2) - 7.",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Expand: 8x-6+6x+15 =15x+10-7, i.e. 14x+9=15x+3, so x=6."
  },
  {
    "id": 335,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 3(x - 4) + 4(2x + 1) = 5x + 7.",
    "answer": "2.5",
    "explanation": "Expand: 3x-12+8x+4 =5x+7, i.e. 11x-8=5x+7, so 6x=15 and x=2.5."
  },
  {
    "id": 336,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 4(2x + 3) - 5(x - 1) = 3x + 13.",
    "answer": "\"No solution\"",
    "explanation": "Expand: 8x+12 -5x+5 =3x+13, i.e. 3x+17=3x+13, which simplifies to 17=13."
  },
  {
    "id": 337,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 6(3x - 1) - 2(4x + 5) = 5(2x + 3) - 8.",
    "answer": "\"No solution\"",
    "explanation": "Expand: 18x-6 -8x-10 =10x+15-8, i.e. 10x-16=10x+7, so -16=7, a contradiction."
  },
  {
    "id": 338,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 2(x+5) - 3(x-2) = x + k. Determine k so that the equation has infinitely many solutions.",
    "answer": "\"No value of k exists\"",
    "explanation": "Expanding: 2x+10 -3x+6 = -x+16; equate with x+k gives -x+16=x+k, which forces -2x=k-16 – impossible for all x."
  },
  {
    "id": 339,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Determine the constant k such that the equation 3(x+2) + k = 3x + 8 has infinitely many solutions.",
    "answer": "2",
    "explanation": "Expand: 3x+6+k = 3x+8, so k = 8-6 = 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 340,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve (2x-3)/4 = (x+5)/3 + 1.",
    "answer": "41/2",
    "explanation": "Multiply both sides by 12: 3(2x-3)=4(x+5)+12 → 6x-9=4x+20+12, so 2x=41 and x=41/2."
  },
  {
    "id": 341,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 7(x-3) + 2(4x+1) = 5(2x+4) - 6.",
    "answer": "33/5",
    "explanation": "Expand: 7x-21+8x+2 =10x+20-6, i.e. 15x-19=10x+14, so 5x=33 and x=33/5."
  },
  {
    "id": 342,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 8(2x+1) - 3(3x-2) = 4(3x+5) - 7.",
    "answer": "2025-01-05 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "Expand: 16x+8-9x+6 =12x+20-7, i.e. 7x+14=12x+13, so 5x=1 and x=1/5."
  },
  {
    "id": 343,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5(3x-2) - 2(2x+7) = x - 12.",
    "answer": "31/3",
    "explanation": "Expand: 15x-10-4x-14 = x-12, i.e. 11x-24=x-12, so 10x=12 and x=12/10=6/5; check calculation: actually 11x-24 = x-12 gives 10x=12, so x=6/5 (or 1.2)."
  },
  {
    "id": 344,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 6(2x+5) - 4(3x-2) = 3(4x-1) + k, and find k such that x=5 is a solution.",
    "answer": "20",
    "explanation": "For x=5: LHS = 6(10+5)-4(15-2)=6×15-4×13=90-52=38; RHS = 3(20-1)+k=3×19+k=57+k. Setting 38=57+k gives k=-19."
  },
  {
    "id": 345,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 2(4x-5) - 3(2x+1) = k. Find k such that x=3 is a solution.",
    "answer": "-7",
    "explanation": "For x=3: LHS = 2(12-5)-3(6+1)=2×7-3×7=14-21=-7, so k = -7."
  },
  {
    "id": 346,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 3(x-2)=3x+k. Determine k such that the equation has no solution.",
    "answer": "\"No solution for any k ≠ -6\"",
    "explanation": "Expanding gives 3x-6=3x+k, so k must equal -6 for equality; if k≠ -6, then -6≠k and no solution exists."
  },
  {
    "id": 347,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 2(3x+1)=2(3x+1)+k. Determine k such that the equation is an identity.",
    "answer": "0",
    "explanation": "Both sides are equal if and only if k=0."
  },
  {
    "id": 348,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 3(4x-5) - 2(2x+3) = 4x + k. Find k for which x=3 is a solution.",
    "answer": "-9",
    "explanation": "For x=3: LHS = 3(12-5)-2(6+3)=3×7-2×9=21-18=3; RHS = 4×3+k=12+k, so 3=12+k, hence k=-9."
  },
  {
    "id": 349,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve (x+2)/3 + (x-1)/4 = (3x+1)/6.",
    "answer": "-3",
    "explanation": "Multiply by 12: 4(x+2)+3(x-1)=2(3x+1) → 4x+8+3x-3=6x+2 → 7x+5=6x+2, so x=-3."
  },
  {
    "id": 350,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5x + 2 - (3x - 4) = 2x + 10.",
    "answer": "\"No solution\"",
    "explanation": "Simplify: 5x+2-3x+4 = 2x+6, so 2x+6 =2x+10, implying 6=10, a contradiction."
  },
  {
    "id": 351,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 7x - 3(2x + 4) = 5x - k. Determine k for which x=2 is a solution.",
    "answer": "20",
    "explanation": "LHS: 7x-6x-12 = x-12; for x=2, LHS = 2-12 = -10; RHS: 5×2-k=10-k; equate -10=10-k, so k=20."
  },
  {
    "id": 352,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 2(3x+1) - 4(x-2) = 3(2x-1) + k. Find k if x=4 is a solution.",
    "answer": "-20",
    "explanation": "For x=4: LHS = 2(12+1)-4(4-2)=2×13-4×2=26-8=18; RHS = 3(8-1)+k=3×7+k=21+k; equate 18=21+k, so k=-3. (Recalculate: 18=21+k gives k=-3.)"
  },
  {
    "id": 353,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 3(5x-2) - 4(2x+3) = 3x + k. Find k if x=-1 is a solution.",
    "answer": "-8",
    "explanation": "For x=-1: LHS = 3(-5-2)-4(-2+3)=3(-7)-4(1)=-21-4=-25; RHS = 3(-1)+k=-3+k; equate -25=-3+k, so k=-22."
  },
  {
    "id": 354,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 4(3x+2) - 2(2x-3) = 5x + k. Find k if x=2 is a solution.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "For x=2: LHS = 4(6+2)-2(4-3)=4×8-2×1=32-2=30; RHS = 5×2+k=10+k; equate 30=10+k, so k=20."
  },
  {
    "id": 355,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5(3x-2) - 3(2x+1) = 9x - 27.",
    "answer": "-3",
    "explanation": "Expand: 15x-10-6x-3=9x-13, so 9x-13=9x-27, leading to -13=-27, which is false; hence, no solution."
  },
  {
    "id": 356,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 6(2x+3) - 4(3x-2) = 3(4x-1) + k, and find k such that x=5 is a solution.",
    "answer": "-19",
    "explanation": "(Repeat similar to an earlier problem) For x=5, k must equal -19."
  },
  {
    "id": 357,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 2(4x-5) - 3(2x+1) = k. Find k such that x=3 is a solution.",
    "answer": "-7",
    "explanation": "(Same as before) For x=3, k = -7."
  },
  {
    "id": 358,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 3(x-2)=3x+k. Determine k such that there is no solution.",
    "answer": "\"No solution for any k ≠ -6\"",
    "explanation": "Expanding gives 3x-6=3x+k; subtracting 3x yields -6=k, so if k≠ -6, the equation is inconsistent."
  },
  {
    "id": 359,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 2(3x+1)=2(3x+1)+k. Determine k such that the equation is an identity.",
    "answer": "0",
    "explanation": "Both sides are identical if and only if k=0."
  },
  {
    "id": 360,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 3(4x-5)-2(2x+3)=4x+k. Find k for which x=3 is a solution.",
    "answer": "-9",
    "explanation": "For x=3: LHS = 3(12-5)-2(6+3)=3×7-2×9=21-18=3; RHS = 12+ k; so 3=12+k, hence k=-9."
  },
  {
    "id": 361,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 7(2x+4)-5(x+2)=3x+ k. Find k for which x=6 is a solution.",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "Expand: 14x+28-5x-10=9x+18; simplifies to 9x+18=9x+ k; for x=6, 9×6+18=54+18=72, so k=72-54=18? (Recompute: 14x+28-5x-10 =9x+18 always; for any x, constants: 28-10=18, so equation becomes 9x+18=9x+ k, hence k=18.)"
  },
  {
    "id": 362,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 3(2x+5)-4(x-2)=5x+ k. Find k if x=3.",
    "answer": "21",
    "explanation": "Expand: 6x+15-4x+8=2x+23; for x=3: 2×3+23=6+23=29; RHS = 5×3+k=15+k; equate 29=15+k, so k=14."
  },
  {
    "id": 363,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 4(3x-2)-3(2x+1)=2x+ k. Find k if x=5.",
    "answer": "23",
    "explanation": "Expand: 12x-8-6x-3=6x-11; for x=5: 30-11=19; RHS = 2×5+k=10+k; so k=9."
  },
  {
    "id": 364,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5(2x+3)-6(x-2)=4x+ k. Find k if x=0.",
    "answer": "27",
    "explanation": "Expand: 10x+15-6x+12=4x+27; for x=0, LHS = 27, RHS = 27+k, so k=0."
  },
  {
    "id": 365,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 6(3x-1)-7(x+4)=5x+ k. Find k if x=3.",
    "answer": "-16",
    "explanation": "Expand: 18x-6-7x-28=11x-34; for x=3: 33-34=-1; RHS = 15+k; so k=-16."
  },
  {
    "id": 366,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 7(2x-3)-8(x+2)=3x+ k. Find k if x=4.",
    "answer": "-17",
    "explanation": "Expand: 14x-21-8x-16=6x-37; for x=4: 24-37=-13; RHS = 12+k; so k=-25? (Recalculate: 14(4)=56, 8(4)=32, then LHS=56-21-32-16=-13; RHS: 3(4)=12, so 12+k=-13, k=-25.)"
  },
  {
    "id": 367,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 8(3x-2)-9(x-3)=3x+ k. Find k if x=2.",
    "answer": "43",
    "explanation": "Expand: 24x-16-9x+27=15x+11; for x=2: 30+11=41; RHS=6+k, so k=35? (Recalculate: 24(2)=48, 9(2)=18, so LHS=48-16-18+27=41; RHS: 3(2)+k=6+k, so k=35.)"
  },
  {
    "id": 368,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 2(5x-3)-4(x+2)= x+ k. Find k if x=1.",
    "answer": "-9",
    "explanation": "Expand: 10x-6-4x-8=6x-14; for x=1: 10-6-4-8= -8; RHS = 1+k, so k=-9."
  },
  {
    "id": 369,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 3(4x+5)-5(x-1)=2x+ k. Find k if x=2.",
    "answer": "30",
    "explanation": "Expand: 12x+15-5x+5=7x+20; for x=2: 14+20=34; RHS = 4+k, so k=30."
  },
  {
    "id": 370,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 4(3x-2)-6(x+4)=2x+ k. Find k if x=-1.",
    "answer": "-36",
    "explanation": "Expand: 12x-8-6x-24=6x-32; for x=-1: -6-32=-38; RHS = -2+k, so k=-36."
  },
  {
    "id": 371,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5(2x+3)-7(x-2)=3x+ k. Find k if x=5.",
    "answer": "29",
    "explanation": "Expand: 10x+15-7x+14=3x+29; for x=5: 50+15-35+14=44; RHS =15+k, so k=29."
  },
  {
    "id": 372,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 6(3x+2)-8(2x-1)=4x+ k. Find k if x=4.",
    "answer": "12",
    "explanation": "Expand: 18x+12-16x+8=2x+20; for x=4: 8+20=28; RHS=16+k, so k=12."
  },
  {
    "id": 373,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 7(2x-1)-5(x+3)=3x+ k. Find k if x=2.",
    "answer": "-10",
    "explanation": "Expand: 14x-7-5x-15=9x-22; for x=2: 18-22=-4; RHS=6+k, so k=-10."
  },
  {
    "id": 374,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "A car dealer sells a car with a 25% discount followed by an additional 10% discount for cash payment. If the final price is $27,000, what was the original price?",
    "answer": "40000",
    "explanation": "Let the original price be x. After a 25% discount, the price becomes 0.75x. Then a further 10% discount gives 0.90(0.75x)=0.675x. Setting 0.675x=27000 yields x=27000/0.675=40000."
  },
  {
    "id": 375,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "A 30‐sided polygon has sides of lengths 3 cm, 5 cm, and 7 cm. The number of sides of length 7 cm is three times the number of sides of length 3 cm, and there are 6 sides of length 5 cm. Which equation represents the total number of sides?",
    "answer": "4n+6=30",
    "explanation": "Let n be the number of 3 cm sides; then 3n are 7 cm sides and 6 are 5 cm sides. Total: n + 3n + 6 = 4n + 6 = 30."
  },
  {
    "id": 376,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Determine the condition on the constant k such that the equation 2(4x – 5) + k = 8x – 9 has no solution.",
    "answer": "k≠1",
    "explanation": "Expanding gives 8x – 10 + k = 8x – 9. Subtracting 8x from both sides yields k – 10 = –9, so k = 1 is the unique solution for equality. Therefore, if k ≠ 1 the equation is inconsistent (has no solution)."
  },
  {
    "id": 377,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve (x + 4)/2 = (x + 4)/5. What is the value of x + 4?",
    "answer": "0",
    "explanation": "Multiplying both sides by 10 yields 5(x + 4) = 2(x + 4). Subtracting 2(x + 4) gives 3(x + 4) = 0, so x + 4 = 0."
  },
  {
    "id": 378,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "How many solutions does the equation 6x + 7 = 6x + 4 have?",
    "answer": "No solution",
    "explanation": "Subtracting 6x from both sides gives 7 = 4, which is false; therefore, no value of x satisfies the equation."
  },
  {
    "id": 379,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 5x – 3 = 2x + 9.",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "Subtract 2x from both sides: 3x – 3 = 9. Then add 3 to get 3x = 12, so x = 4."
  },
  {
    "id": 380,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in one variable",
    "question": "Solve 4x – 7 = 2x + 3.",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Subtract 2x from both sides: 2x – 7 = 3, then add 7 to obtain 2x = 10 and x = 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 381,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 6x + 12. What is the value of f(8)?",
    "answer": "60",
    "explanation": "Substitute x = 8: f(8) = 6(8) + 12 = 48 + 12 = 60."
  },
  {
    "id": 382,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "If the function g(x) = 5x – 4, what is g(0)?",
    "answer": "-4",
    "explanation": "Substitute x = 0: g(0) = 5(0) – 4 = –4."
  },
  {
    "id": 383,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A phone plan charges a fixed fee of $15 plus $0.10 per minute. Which equation represents the total cost C for m minutes?",
    "answer": "C = 0.10m + 15",
    "explanation": "The total cost is the fixed fee plus the per-minute charge: C = 15 + 0.10m."
  },
  {
    "id": 384,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function h(x) = 2x + b passes through the point (4, 11). What is the value of b?",
    "answer": "3",
    "explanation": "Substitute x = 4: 2(4) + b = 11 → 8 + b = 11, so b = 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 385,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A contractor estimates the cost to paint a house as C = 50A + 200, where A is the area in square feet. If the final cost is $3,700, what is the area A?",
    "answer": "70",
    "explanation": "Solve 50A + 200 = 3700. Subtract 200 to get 50A = 3500, then A = 3500/50 = 70."
  },
  {
    "id": 386,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function p(t) = 0.5t + 5 gives the price, in dollars, of a product t years after its launch. What is the price 8 years after launch?",
    "answer": "9",
    "explanation": "p(8) = 0.5(8) + 5 = 4 + 5 = 9."
  },
  {
    "id": 387,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A cell phone company charges a fixed fee plus a per-minute rate. If a customer pays $80 for 50 minutes and $110 for 100 minutes, find the per-minute rate.",
    "answer": "0.6",
    "explanation": "Let fixed fee = F and rate = r. Then F + 50r = 80 and F + 100r = 110. Subtracting gives 50r = 30, so r = 0.6."
  },
  {
    "id": 388,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "If the function f(x) = 3x + 2 and f(x) = 17, what is x?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Solve 3x + 2 = 17. Subtract 2 to get 3x = 15, then x = 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 389,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function m(x) = 4x – 8 represents the net profit (in dollars) from selling x items. For what value of x is the net profit zero?",
    "answer": "2",
    "explanation": "Set 4x – 8 = 0, so 4x = 8 and x = 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 390,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A store sells T‑shirts at a price given by P(n) = 20 – 0.5n, where n is the number of T‑shirts bought in bulk. What is the price per shirt if 12 shirts are purchased?",
    "answer": "14",
    "explanation": "P(12) = 20 – 0.5(12) = 20 – 6 = 14."
  },
  {
    "id": 391,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A taxi company charges a base fare of $3 plus $2 per mile. Which function represents the total fare F for m miles?",
    "answer": "F = 2m + 3",
    "explanation": "Total fare = base fee + per-mile rate: F = 3 + 2m."
  },
  {
    "id": 392,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "If f(x) = 7x + 5, what is f(3)?",
    "answer": "26",
    "explanation": "f(3) = 7(3) + 5 = 21 + 5 = 26."
  },
  {
    "id": 393,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function s(t) = 60 – 2t gives the speed (in mph) of a car t seconds after the brakes are applied. How long does it take for the car to come to a complete stop?",
    "answer": "30",
    "explanation": "Set 60 – 2t = 0, so 2t = 60 and t = 30 seconds."
  },
  {
    "id": 394,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A water tank leaks water at a rate modeled by L(t) = 100 – 3t (in gallons), where t is in hours. If after 20 hours, 40 gallons remain, is the model consistent?",
    "answer": "Yes",
    "explanation": "L(20) = 100 – 3(20) = 100 – 60 = 40, which matches the given data."
  },
  {
    "id": 395,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "If the function f(x) = ax + b passes through (2, 10) and (6, 26), find a and b.",
    "answer": "a = 4, b = 2",
    "explanation": "Slope a = (26 – 10)/(6 – 2) = 16/4 = 4. Then 10 = 4(2) + b, so b = 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 396,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A phone plan’s cost is modeled by C(x) = mx + 25, where x is the number of minutes used. If a customer pays $70 for 50 minutes, find m.",
    "answer": "0.9",
    "explanation": "Set m(50) + 25 = 70, so 50m = 45, and m = 45/50 = 0.9."
  },
  {
    "id": 397,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f(x) = 12 – 0.2x models the temperature (°C) in a room after x minutes of cooling. What is the temperature after 30 minutes?",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "f(30) = 12 – 0.2(30) = 12 – 6 = 6°C."
  },
  {
    "id": 398,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A car’s fuel consumption is modeled by F(d) = 5 + 0.08d (in gallons), where d is the distance in miles. How much fuel is used in 150 miles?",
    "answer": "17",
    "explanation": "F(150) = 5 + 0.08(150) = 5 + 12 = 17 gallons."
  },
  {
    "id": 399,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function f(x) = 3x – 7. For what value of x is f(x) equal to zero?",
    "answer": "2025-07-03 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "Set 3x – 7 = 0, so 3x = 7 and x = 7/3."
  },
  {
    "id": 400,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "If g(x) = 2x + 10, what is g(–3)?",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "g(–3) = 2(–3) + 10 = –6 + 10 = 4."
  },
  {
    "id": 401,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function p(x) = 0.5x + 15 represents the price (in dollars) of x pounds of apples. What is the price for 20 pounds?",
    "answer": "25",
    "explanation": "p(20) = 0.5(20) + 15 = 10 + 15 = 25 dollars."
  },
  {
    "id": 402,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A manufacturer’s cost to produce x units is given by C(x) = 25x + 300. What is the average cost per unit when 50 units are produced?",
    "answer": "31",
    "explanation": "Average cost = (25×50 + 300)/50 = (1250 + 300)/50 = 1550/50 = 31 dollars."
  },
  {
    "id": 403,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "If the function f(x) = 8x – 4 represents the number of pages read in x hours, how many pages are read in 3 hours?",
    "answer": "20",
    "explanation": "f(3) = 8(3) – 4 = 24 – 4 = 20 pages."
  },
  {
    "id": 404,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function T(x) = 15 – 0.5x represents the minutes remaining on a timer after x minutes. For what value of x will the timer reach 0 minutes?",
    "answer": "30",
    "explanation": "Set 15 – 0.5x = 0, so 0.5x = 15 and x = 30."
  },
  {
    "id": 405,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A company's revenue is modeled by R(x) = 200x – 150, where x is the number of units sold. What is the revenue when 10 units are sold?",
    "answer": "1850",
    "explanation": "R(10) = 200(10) – 150 = 2000 – 150 = 1850."
  },
  {
    "id": 406,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A linear function f is defined by f(x) = mx + 120, and f(10) = 300. What is the value of m?",
    "answer": "18",
    "explanation": "f(10) = 10m + 120 = 300, so 10m = 180 and m = 18."
  },
  {
    "id": 407,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "If the function f(x) = 5x + 20 represents the cost (in dollars) of renting a bike for x hours, how much does it cost for 7 hours?",
    "answer": "55",
    "explanation": "f(7) = 5(7) + 20 = 35 + 20 = 55 dollars."
  },
  {
    "id": 408,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function T(x) = 50 – 0.75x gives the temperature (°F) after x minutes of cooling. What is the temperature after 40 minutes?",
    "answer": "20",
    "explanation": "T(40) = 50 – 0.75(40) = 50 – 30 = 20°F."
  },
  {
    "id": 409,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A rental car company charges a base fee plus a per-mile rate. If the cost function is C(m) = 0.45m + 30, what is the cost for driving 150 miles?",
    "answer": "97.5",
    "explanation": "C(150) = 0.45(150) + 30 = 67.5 + 30 = 97.5 dollars."
  },
  {
    "id": 410,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "If the function f(x) = 7x + 5, what is f(3)?",
    "answer": "26",
    "explanation": "f(3) = 7(3) + 5 = 21 + 5 = 26."
  },
  {
    "id": 411,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function s(t) = 60 – 2t gives the speed (in mph) of a car t seconds after braking. How long until the car stops?",
    "answer": "30",
    "explanation": "Solve 60 – 2t = 0, so 2t = 60 and t = 30 seconds."
  },
  {
    "id": 412,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A bookstore sells notebooks with cost modeled by C(n) = 2.5n + 10. If a customer spends $35, how many notebooks did they buy?",
    "answer": "10",
    "explanation": "Solve 2.5n + 10 = 35. Subtract 10: 2.5n = 25, so n = 25/2.5 = 10."
  },
  {
    "id": 413,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "If f(x) = 9x – 4 represents pages read in x hours, how many pages are read in 6 hours?",
    "answer": "50",
    "explanation": "f(6) = 9(6) – 4 = 54 – 4 = 50 pages."
  },
  {
    "id": 414,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "The function L(x) = 60 – 0.2x represents the liquid level (in gallons) in a tank after x minutes of draining. How many minutes until the tank is empty if it initially contains 60 gallons?",
    "answer": "300",
    "explanation": "Set 60 – 0.2x = 0, so 0.2x = 60 and x = 300."
  },
  {
    "id": 415,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear functions",
    "question": "A linear function f is defined by f(x) = mx + 40. If f(0) = 40 and f(10) = 100, what is f(5)?",
    "answer": "70",
    "explanation": "The slope m = (100 – 40)/10 = 6; then f(5) = 6(5) + 40 = 30 + 40 = 70."
  },
  {
    "id": 416,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "Given P(t) = 24.8(1.036)^t, the function P gives the predicted population, in millions, of a certain country for the period from 1984 to 2018, where t is the number of years after 1984. According to the model, what is the best interpretation of the statement \"P(8) is approximately equal to 32.91\"?",
    "answer": "8 years after 1984, the predicted population of this country was approximately 32.91 million.",
    "explanation": "The function P gives the predicted population, in millions, of a certain country for the period from 1984 to 2018, where t is the number of years after 1984. Since the value of P(8) is the value of P(t) when t = 8, it follows that \"P(8) is approximately equal to 32.91\" means that the value of P(t) is\napproximately equal to 32.91 when t = 8. Therefore, the best interpretation of the statement \"P(8) is approximately equal to 32.91\" is that 8 years after 1984, the predicted population of this country was approximately 32.91 million.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 417,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 4 + x^(1 / 2). What is the value of f(144)?",
    "answer": "16",
    "explanation": "The value of f(144) is the value of f(x) when x = 144. It's given that the function f is defined by f(x) = 4 + x^(1 / 2). Substituting 144 for x in\nthis equation yields f(144) = 4 + 144^(1 / 2). Since the positive square root of 144 is 12, it follows that this equation can be rewritten as f(144) = 4 + 12, or f(144) = 16. Therefore, the value of f(144) is 16."
  },
  {
    "id": 418,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 1 / 6x. What is the value of f(x) when x = 3?",
    "answer": "2025-01-18 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "It's given that f(x) = 1/6x. Substituting 3 for x in the function yields f(3) = 1/6(3), f(3) = 1/(6 * 3), or f(3) = 1/18. Therefore, when x = 3, the value of f(x) is 1/18."
  },
  {
    "id": 419,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "Given P(t) = 1800(1.02)^t, the fuction P gives the estimated number of marine mammals in a certain area, where t is the number of years since a study began. What is the best interpretation of P(0) = 1800 in this context?",
    "answer": "The estimated number of marine mammals in the area was 1800 when the study began.",
    "explanation": "The function P gives the estimated number of marine mammals in a certain area, where t is the number of years since a study began. Since the value of P(0) is the value of P(t) when t = 0, it follows that P(0) = 1800 means that the value of P(t) is 1800 when t = 0. Since t is the number of years since the study began, it follows that t = 0 is 0 years since the study began, or when the study began. Therefore, the best interpretation of P(0) = 1800 in this context is the estimated number of marine mammals in the area was 1800 when the study began.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 420,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function f is definced by f(x) = 10(x)^2 - 32x - 152. What is the value of f(0)?",
    "answer": "-152",
    "explanation": "The value of  f(0) is the value of f(x) when x = 0. The function f is defined by f(x) = 10(x)^2 - 32x - 152. Substituting 0 for x in this equation yields f(0) = 10(0)^2 - 32(0) - 152. This equation can be rewritten as f(0) = 10(0) - 0 - 152, or f(0) = -152. Therefore, the value of f(0) is -152."
  },
  {
    "id": 421,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "If f(x) = (x^2 - 6x + 3) / (x - 1), what is f(-1)?",
    "answer": "-5",
    "explanation": "Substituting –1 for x in the equation that defines f gives f(-1) = ((-1)^2 - 6(-1) + 3) / ((-1) - 1). Simplifying the expressions in the numerator and denominator yields (1 + 6 + 3) / (-2), which is equal to 10 / -2 or -5."
  },
  {
    "id": 422,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "f(x) = 2(3^x)\nFor the function f defined above, what is the value of f(2)?",
    "answer": "18",
    "explanation": "The value of f(2) is found by evaluating the expression 2(3^x) when x = 2. Substituting 2 for x in the given equation yields f(2) = 2(3^2). Simplifying 3^2 in the equation results in f(2) = 2(9). Evaluating the right-hand side of the equation yields f(2) = 18. Therefore, the value of f(2) is 18."
  },
  {
    "id": 423,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "A ball is dropped from an initial height of 22 feet and bounces off the ground repeatedly. The function h estimates that the maximum height reached after each time the ball hits the ground is 85% of the maximum height reached after the previous time the ball hit the ground. Which equation defines h, where h(n) is the estimated maximum height of the ball after it has hit the ground n times and n is a whole number greater than 1 and less than 10?",
    "answer": "h(n) = 22(0.85)^n",
    "explanation": "It's given that for the function h, h(n) is the estimated maximum height, in feet, of the ball after it has hit the ground n times. It's also given that the function h estimates that the maximum height reached after each time the ball hits the ground is 85% of the maximum height reached after the previous time the ball hit the ground. It follows that h is a decreasing exponential function that can be written in the form h(n) = a(p/100)^n , where a is the initial height, in feet, the ball was dropped from and the function estimates that the maximum height reached after each time the ball hits the ground is p% of the maximum height reached after the previous time the ball hit the ground. It's given that the ball is dropped from an initial height of 22 feet. Therefore, a = 22. Since the function h estimates that the maximum height reached after each time the ball hits the ground is 85% of the maximum height reached after the previous time the ball hit the ground, p = 85. Substituting 22 for a and 85 for p in the equation h(n) = a(p/100)^n yields h(n) = 22(85/100)^n, or h(n) = 22(0.85)^n."
  },
  {
    "id": 424,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = x^3 + 9. What is the value of f(2)?",
    "answer": "17",
    "explanation": "It's given that f(x) = x^3 + 9. Substituting 2 for x in this equation yields f(2) = (2)^3 + 9. This is equivalent to f(2) = 8 + 9, or f(2) = 17."
  },
  {
    "id": 425,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function h is defined by h(x) = 8 / (5x + 6). What is the value of h(2)?",
    "answer": "2025-01-02 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "The value of h(2) is the value of h(x) when x = 2. Substituting 2 for x in the given equation yields h(2) = 8 / (5(2) + 6), which is equivalent\nto h(2) = 8 / 16, or h(2) = 1/2. Therefore, the value of h(2) is 1/2. Note that 1/2 and 0.5 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 426,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function f(x) = 200000(1.21)^x gives a company’s predicted annual revenue, in dollars, x years after the company started selling light bulbs online, where 0 < x <= 10. What is the best interpretation of the statement “f(5) is approximately equal to 518748” in this context?",
    "answer": "5 years after the company started selling light bulbs online, its predicted annual revenue is approximately 518748 dollars.",
    "explanation": "It's given that the function f(x) = 200000(1.21)^x gives a company's predicted annual revenue, in dollars, x years after the company started selling light bulbs online. It follows that f(x) represents the company's predicted annual revenue, in dollars, x years after the company started selling light bulbs online. Since the value of f(5) is the value of f(x) when x = 5, it follows that \"f(5) is approximately equal to 518748\" means that f(x) is approximately equal\nto 518748 when x = 5. Therefore, the best interpretation of the statement \"f(5) is approximately equal to 518748\" in this context is 5 years after the company started selling light bulbs online, its predicted annual revenue is approximately 518748dollars."
  },
  {
    "id": 427,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 6 + (x)^(1/2). What is the value of f(36)?",
    "answer": "12",
    "explanation": "The value of f(36) is the value of f(x) when x  = 36. Substituting 36 for x in the given equation yields f(36) = 6 + (36)^(1/2), which is\nequivalent to f(36) = 6 + 6, or f(36) = 12. Thus, the value of f(36) is 12."
  },
  {
    "id": 428,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function g is defined by g(x) = x^2 + 9. For which value of x is g(x) = 25?",
    "answer": "4, -4",
    "explanation": "It's given that g(x) = x^2 + 9. Substituting 25 for g(x) in this equation yields 25 = x^2 + 9. Subtracting 9 from both sides of this equation\nyields 16 = x^2. Taking the square root of each side of this equation yields x = +-4. It follows that g(x) = 25 when the value of x is 4 or -4."
  },
  {
    "id": 429,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The y-intercept of the graph of y = x^2 + 31 in the xy-plane is (0, y). What is the value of y?",
    "answer": "31",
    "explanation": "It's given that the y-intercept of the graph of y = x^2 + 31 in the xy-plane is (0, y). Substituting 0 for x in the given equation yields y = (0)^2\n + 31, or y = 31. Thus, the value of y is 31."
  },
  {
    "id": 430,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function g is defined by g(x) = |x + 18|. What is the value of g(4)?",
    "answer": "22",
    "explanation": "The value of g(4) is the value of g(x) when x = 4. Substituting 4 for x in the given equation yields g(4) = |4 + 18|, which is equivalent to g(4) = |22|, or g(4) = 22. Therefore, the value of g(4) is 22."
  },
  {
    "id": 431,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The kinetic energy, in joules, of an object with mass 0 kilograms traveling at a speed of v meters per second is given by the function K, where K(v) = (9 / 2)(v)^2. What is the best interpretation of K(34) = 5202 in this context?",
    "answer": "The object traveling at 34 meters per second has a kinetic energy of 5202 joules.",
    "explanation": "It's given that the kinetic energy, in joules, of an object with a mass of 9 kilograms traveling at a speed of meters per second is given by the function K, where K(v) = (9/2)(v)^2. It follows that in the equation K(34) = 5202, 34 is the value of v, or the speed of the object, in meters per second, and 5202 is the kinetic energy, in joules, of the object at that speed. Therefore, the best interpretation of K(34) = 5202 in this context is the object traveling at 34 meters per second has a kinetic energy of 5202 joules."
  },
  {
    "id": 432,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 8(x)^(1/2). For what value of x does f(x) = 48?",
    "answer": "36",
    "explanation": "It's given that f(x) = 8(x)^(1/2). Substituting 48 for f(x) in this equation yields 48 = 8(x)^(1/2). Dividing both sides of this equation by 8 yields 6 = x^(1/2). Squaring both sides of this equation yields x = 36. Therefore, the value of x for which f(x) = 48 is 36."
  },
  {
    "id": 433,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = x^3 + 15. What is the value of f(2)?",
    "answer": "23",
    "explanation": "The value of f(2) is the value of f(x) when x = 2. Substituting 2 for x in the given function yields f(2) = (2)^2 + 15, or f(2) = 8 + 15, which is equivalent to f(2) = 23. Therefore, the value of f(2) is 23."
  },
  {
    "id": 434,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 5(x)^2. What is the value of f(8)?",
    "answer": "320",
    "explanation": "It's given that the function f is defined by f(x) = 5(x)^2. Substituting 8 for x in the given function yields f(8) = 5(8)^2, which is equivalent to f(8) = 5(64), or f(8) = 320. Therefore, the value of f(8) is 320."
  },
  {
    "id": 435,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 16 / x. What is the value of f(x) when x = 17?",
    "answer": "16 / 17",
    "explanation": "It's given that f(x) = 16 / x. Substituting 17 for x in this function yields f(17) = 16 / 17. Therefore, when x = 17, the value of f(x) is 16 / 17."
  },
  {
    "id": 436,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "f(x) = (x + 0.25x)(50 - x)\nThe function f is defined above. What is the value of f(20)?",
    "answer": "750",
    "explanation": "Adding the like terms x and 0.25 yields the equation f(x) = (1.25x)(50 - x). Substituting 20 for x yields f(20) = (1.25(20))(50 - 20). The product 1.25(20) is equal to 25, and the difference 50 - 20 is equal to 30. Substituting these values in the given equation gives f(20) = (25)(30), and multiplying 25 by 30 results in f(20) = 750."
  },
  {
    "id": 437,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A store sells two different-sized containers of a certain Greek yogurt. The store's sales of this Greek yogurt totaled 1277.94 dollars last month. The equation 5.48x + 7.30y = 1277.94 represents this situation, where x is the number of smaller containers sold and y is the number of larger containers sold. According to the equation, which of the following represents the price, in dollars, of each smaller container?",
    "answer": "5.48",
    "explanation": "It is given that the store's sales of a certain Greek yogurt totaled 1277.94 dollars last month. It is also given that the equation 5.48x + 7.30y = 1277.94 represents this situation, where x is the number of smaller containers sold and y is the number of larger containers sold. Since x represents the number of smaller containers of yogurt sold, the expression 5.48x represents the total sales, in dollars, from smaller containers of yogurt. This means that x smaller containers of yogurt were sold at a price of 5.48 dollars each. Therefore, according to the equation, 5.48 represents the price, in dollars, of each smaller container."
  },
  {
    "id": 438,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A gardener buys two kinds of fertilizer. Fertilizer A contains 60% filler materials by weight and Fertilizer B contains 40% filler materials by weight. Together, the fertilizers bought by the gardener contain a total of 240 pounds of filler materials. Which equation models this relationship, where x is the number of pounds of Fertilizer A and y is the number of pounds of Fertilizer B?",
    "answer": "0.6x + 0.4y = 240",
    "explanation": "Since Fertilizer A contains 60% filler materials by weight, it follows that x pounds of Fertilizer A consists of 0.6x pounds of filler materials. Similarly, y pounds of Fertilizer B consists of 0.4y pounds of filler materials. When x pounds of Fertilizer A and y pounds of Fertilizer B are combined, the result is 240 pounds of filler materials. Therefore, the total amount, in pounds, of filler materials in a mixture of x pounds of Fertilizer A and y pounds of Fertilizer B can be expressed as 0.6x + 0.4y = 240."
  },
  {
    "id": 439,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Line k is defined by y = (1/4)x + 1. Line j is parallel to line k in the xy-plane. What is the slope of j?",
    "answer": "0.25, 1/4",
    "explanation": "It is given that line k is defined by y = (1/4)x + 1. It is also given that line j is parallel to line k in the xy-plane. A line in the xy-plane represented by an equation in slope-intercept form y = mx + b has a slope of m and a y-intercept of (0, b). Therefore, the slope of line k is 1/4. Since parallel lines have equal slopes, the slope of line j is 1/4. Note that 1/4 and 0.25 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 440,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "The equation x + y = 1440 represents the number of minutes of daylight between sunrise and sunset, x, and the number of minutes of non-daylight, y, on a particular day in Oak Park, Illinois. If this day has 670 minutes of daylight, how many minutes of non-daylight does it have?",
    "answer": "770",
    "explanation": "It is given that the equation x + y = 1440 represents the number of minutes of daylight, x, and the number of minutes of non-daylight, y, on a particular day in Oak Park, Illinois. It is also given that this day has 670 minutes of daylight. Substituting 670 for x in the equation x + y = 1440 yields 670 + y = 1440. Subtracting 670 from both sides of this equation yields y = 770. Therefore, this day has 770 minutes of non-daylight."
  },
  {
    "id": 441,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "For a camping trip, a group bought x one-liter bottles of water and y three-liter bottles of water, for a total of 240 liters of water. Which equation represents this situation?",
    "answer": "x + 3y = 240",
    "explanation": "It is given that for a camping trip, a group bought x one-liter bottles of water and y three-liter bottles of water. Since the group bought x one-liter bottles of water, the total number of liters bought from x one-liter bottles of water is represented as 1x, or x. Since the group bought y three-liter bottles of water, the total number of liters bought from y three-liter bottles of water is represented as 3y. It is given that the group bought a total of 240 liters; thus, the equation x + 3y = 240 represents this situation."
  },
  {
    "id": 442,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A line in the xy-plane has a slope of -1/2 and passes through the point (0,3). Which equation represents this line?",
    "answer": "y = -1/2x + 3",
    "explanation": "A line in the xy-plane with a slope of m and a y-intercept of (0,b) can be represented by the equation y = mx + b. It's given that the line has a slope of -1/2. Therefore, m = -1/2. It's also given that the line passes through the point (0,3). Therefore, b = 3. Substituting -1/2 for m and 3 for b in the equation y = mx + b yields y = -1/2x + 3. Therefore, the equation y = -1/2x + 3 represents this line."
  },
  {
    "id": 443,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "F = 2.50x + 7.00y In the equation above, F represents the total amount of money, in dollars, a food truck charges for x drinks and y salads. The price, in dollars, of each drink is the same, and the price, in dollars, of each salad is the same. Which of the following is the best interpretation for the number 7.00 in this context?",
    "answer": "The price, in dollars, of one salad",
    "explanation": "It's given that 2.50x + 7.00y is equal to the total amount of money, in dollars, a food truck charges for x drinks and y salads. Since each salad has the same price, it follows that the total charge for y salads is 7.00y dollars. When y = 1, the value of the expression 7.00y is 7.00 × 1, or 7.00. Therefore, the price for one salad is 7.00 dollars."
  },
  {
    "id": 444,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "What is the y-intercept of the graph of y = 34x + 81 in the xy-plane?",
    "answer": "(0,81)",
    "explanation": "In the xy-plane, the graph of an equation in the form y = mx + b, where m and b are constants, has a slope of m and a y-intercept of (0,b). Therefore, the y-intercept of the graph of y = 34x + 81 is (0,81)."
  },
  {
    "id": 445,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A shipment consists of 5-pound boxes and 10-pound boxes with a total weight of 220 pounds. There are 13 10-pound boxes in the shipment. How many 5-pound boxes are in the shipment?",
    "answer": "18",
    "explanation": "It's given that the shipment consists of 5-pound boxes and 10-pound boxes with a total weight of 220 pounds. Let x represent the number of 5-pound boxes and y represent the number of 10-pound boxes in the shipment. Therefore, the equation 5x + 10y = 220 represents this situation. It's given that there are 13 10-pound boxes in the shipment. Substituting 13 for y in the equation 5x + 10y = 220 yields 5x + 10(13) = 220, or 5x + 130 = 220. Subtracting 130 from both sides of this equation yields 5x = 90. Dividing both sides of the equation by 5 yields 18. Thus, there are 18 5-pound boxes in the shipment."
  },
  {
    "id": 446,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A teacher is creating an assignment worth 70 points. The assignment will consist of questions worth 1 point and questions worth 3 points. Which equation represents this situation, where x represents the number of 1-point questions and y represents the number of 3-point questions?",
    "answer": "x + 3y = 70",
    "explanation": "Since x represents the number of 1-point questions and y represents the number of 3-point questions, the assignment is worth a total of 1 × x + 3 × y, or x + 3y, points. Since the assignment is worth 70 points, the equation x + 3y = 70 represents this situation."
  },
  {
    "id": 447,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "On a 210-mile trip, Cameron drove at an average speed of 60 miles per hour for the first x hours. He then completed the trip, driving at an average speed of 50 miles per hour for the remaining y hours. If x = 1, what is the value of y?",
    "answer": "3",
    "explanation": "It is given that Cameron drove 60 miles per hour for x hours. Therefore, the distance driven at this speed can be represented by 60x. He then drove 50 miles per hour for y hours. Therefore, the distance driven at this speed can be represented by 50y. Since Cameron drove 210 total miles, the equation 60x + 50y = 210 represents this situation. If x = 1, substitution yields 60(1) + 50y = 210, or 60 + 50y = 210. Subtracting 60 from both sides of this equation yields 50y = 150. Dividing both sides of this equation by 50 yields y = 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 448,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "In the xy-plane, line t passes through the points (0,9) and (1,17). Which equation defines line t?",
    "answer": "y = 8x + 9",
    "explanation": "An equation defining a line in the xy-plane can be written in the form y = mx + b, where m represents the slope and (0, b) represents the y-intercept of the line. It is given that line t passes through the point (0,9), therefore, b = 9. The slope m of a line can be found using any two points on the line (x1, y1) and (x2, y2), and the slope formula m = (y2 - y1) / (x2 - x1). Substituting (0,9) and (1,17) for (x1, y1) and (x2, y2), respectively, in the slope formula yields m = (17 - 9) / (1 - 0), or m = 8. Substituting 8 for m and 9 for b in the equation y = mx + b yields y = 8x + 9."
  },
  {
    "id": 449,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Line t in the xy-plane has a slope of -1/3 and passes through the point (9,10). Which equation defines line t?",
    "answer": "y = -x/3 + 13",
    "explanation": "The equation that defines line t in the xy-plane can be written in slope-intercept form y = mx + b, where m is the slope of line t and (0, b) is its y-intercept. It is given that line t has a slope of -1/3. Therefore, m = -1/3. Substituting -1/3 for m in the equation y = mx + b yields y = -1/3x + b, or y = -x/3 + b. It is also given that line t passes through the point (9,10). Substituting 9 for x and 10 for y in the equation y = -x/3 + b yields 10 = -9/3 + b, or 10 = -3 + b. Adding 3 to both sides of this equation yields 13 = b. Substituting 13 for b in the equation y = -x/3 + b yields y = -x/3 + 13."
  },
  {
    "id": 450,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Line k is defined by y = -17/3x + 5. Line j is perpendicular to line k in the xy-plane. What is the slope of line j?",
    "answer": "2025-03-17 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "It is given that line j is perpendicular to line k in the xy-plane. This means that the slope of line j is the negative reciprocal of the slope of line k. The equation of line k, y = -17/3x + 5, is written in slope-intercept form y = mx + b, where m is the slope of the line and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the line. It follows that the slope of line k is -17/3. The negative reciprocal of a number is -1 divided by the number. Therefore, the negative reciprocal of -17/3 is -1 / (-17/3), or 3/17. Thus, the slope of line j is 3/17. Note that 3/17, 0.1764, 0.1765, and 0.176 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 451,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Line p is defined by 2y + 18x = 9. Line r is perpendicular to line p in the xy-plane. What is the slope of line r?",
    "answer": "2025-01-09 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "It is given that line r is perpendicular to line p in the xy-plane. This means that the slope of line r is the negative reciprocal of the slope of line p. If the equation for line p is rewritten in slope-intercept form y = mx + b, where m and b are constants, then m is the slope of the line and (0, b) is its y-intercept. Subtracting 18x from both sides of the equation 2y + 18x = 9 yields 2y = -18x + 9. Dividing both sides of this equation by 2 yields y = -9x + 9/2. It follows that the slope of line p is -9. The negative reciprocal of -9 is -1 / (-9), or 1/9. Thus, the slope of line r is 1/9."
  },
  {
    "id": 452,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "What is the y-intercept of the graph of y = 4x + 7 in the xy-plane?",
    "answer": "(0,7)",
    "explanation": "In the xy-plane, the graph of an equation in the form y = mx + b, where m and b are constants, has a slope of m and a y-intercept of (0,b). Therefore, the y-intercept of the graph of y = 4x + 7 is (0,7)."
  },
  {
    "id": 453,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A bookstore sells used and new books. The store sold 15 used books and 10 new books for a total sales revenue of 280. Which of the following equations represents this situation, where x is the price of one used book in dollars and y is the price of one new book in dollars?",
    "answer": "15x + 10y = 280",
    "explanation": "The store sold 15 used books and 10 new books for a total of 280. Since x is the price of one used book, the total revenue from used books is represented as 15x. Similarly, since y is the price of one new book, the total revenue from new books is represented as 10y. Therefore, the total sales revenue is given by the equation 15x + 10y = 280."
  },
  {
    "id": 454,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A store sells two types of fruit baskets: small and large. The price in dollars of a small basket is s, and the price in dollars of a large basket is l. A customer buys 3 small baskets and 2 large baskets for a total of 44. Which equation represents this situation?",
    "answer": "3s + 2l = 44",
    "explanation": "The price in dollars of a small basket is s, and the price in dollars of a large basket is l. The total cost for 3 small baskets is 3s, and the total cost for 2 large baskets is 2l. Since the total cost is given as 44, the equation that represents this situation is 3s + 2l = 44."
  },
  {
    "id": 455,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Line m is defined by the equation y = 5x + 4. Line n is perpendicular to line m in the xy-plane. What is the slope of line n?",
    "answer": "2025-01-05 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "Line m is given by y = 5x + 4. This is in slope-intercept form y = mx + b, where m is the slope. Since the slope of line m is 5, the slope of a line perpendicular to it is the negative reciprocal of 5, which is -1/5. Therefore, the slope of line n is -1/5."
  },
  {
    "id": 456,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "2.5b + 5r = 80 The given equation describes the relationship between the number of birds, b, and the number of reptiles, r, that can be cared for at a pet care business on a given day. If the business cares for 16 reptiles on a given day, how many birds can it care for on this day?",
    "answer": "0",
    "explanation": "The number of birds can be found by calculating the value of b when r = 16 in the given equation. Substituting 16 for r in the given equation yields 2.5b + 5(16) = 80, or 2.5b + 80 = 80. Subtracting 80 from both sides of this equation yields 2.5b = 0. Dividing both sides of this equation by 2.5 yields b = 0. Therefore, if the business cares for 16 reptiles on a given day, it can care for 0 birds on this day. "
  },
  {
    "id": 457,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Figure A and figure B are both regular polygons. The sum of the perimeter of figure A and the perimeter of figure B is 63 inches. The equation 3x + 6y = 63 represents this situation, where x is the number of sides of figure A and y is the number of sides of figure B. Which statement is the best interpretation of 6 in this context?",
    "answer": "Each side of figure B has a length of 6 inches.",
    "explanation": "It's given that figure A and figure B (not shown) are both regular polygons and the sum of the perimeters of the two figures is 63 inches. It's also given that x is the number of sides of figure A and y is the number of sides of figure B, and that the equation 3x + 6y = 63 represents this situation. Thus, 3x and 6y represent the perimeters, in inches, of figure A and figure B, respectively. Since 6y represents the perimeter, in inches, of figure B and y is the number of sides of figure B, it follows that each side of figure B has a length of 6 inches."
  },
  {
    "id": 458,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "What is the slope of the graph of y = (5/13)x - 23 in the xy-plane?",
    "answer": ".3846, 5/13",
    "explanation": "The graph of a line in the xy-plane can be represented by the equation y = mx + b, where m is the slope of the line and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept. The given equation can be written as y = (5/13)x - 23. Therefore, the slope of the graph of this equation in the xy-plane is 5/13. Note that 5/13, .3846, 0.385, and 0.384 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 459,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "In the xy-plane, line k passes through the points (0, -5) and (1, -1). Which equation defines line k?",
    "answer": "y = 4x - 5",
    "explanation": "An equation defining a line in the xy-plane can be written in the form y = mx + b, where m represents the slope and (0, b) represents the y-intercept of the line. It’s given that line k passes through the point (0, -5); therefore, b = -5. The slope, m, of a line can be found using any two points on the line, (x1, y1) and (x2, y2), and the slope formula m = (y2 - y1) / (x2 - x1). Substituting the points (0, -5) and (1, -1) for (x1, y1) and (x2, y2), respectively, in the slope formula yields m = ( -1 - (-5) ) / (1 - 0), or m = 4. Substituting 4 for m and -5 for b in the equation y = mx + b yields y = 4x - 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 460,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "When line n is graphed in the xy-plane, it has an x-intercept of (-4, 0) and a y-intercept of (0, 86/3). What is the slope of line n?",
    "answer": "43/6",
    "explanation": "It's given that when line n is graphed in the xy-plane, it has an x-intercept of (-4, 0) and a y-intercept of (0, 86/3). The slope, m, of a line can be found using any two points on the line, (x1, y1) and (x2, y2), and the slope formula m = (y2 - y1) / (x2 - x1). Substituting the points (-4, 0) and (0, 86/3) for (x1, y1) and (x2, y2), respectively, in the slope formula yields m = (86/3 - 0) / (0 - (-4)), or m = 43/6. Therefore, the slope of line n is 43/6."
  },
  {
    "id": 461,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A store sells two different-sized containers of blueberries. The store's sales of these blueberries totaled 896.86 dollars last month. The equation 4.51x + 6.07y = 896.86 represents this situation, where x is the number of smaller containers sold and y is the number of larger containers sold. According to the equation, what is the price, in dollars, of each smaller container?",
    "answer": "4.51, 451/100",
    "explanation": "It's given that the equation 4.51x + 6.07y = 896.86 represents this situation, where x is the number of smaller containers sold, y is the number of larger containers sold, and 896.86 is the store's total sales, in dollars, of blueberries last month. Therefore, 4.51x represents the store's sales, in dollars, of smaller containers, and 6.07y represents the store's sales, in dollars, of larger containers. Since x is the number of smaller containers sold, the price, in dollars, of each smaller container is 4.51."
  },
  {
    "id": 462,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A line passes through the points (4, 6) and (15, 24) in the xy-plane. What is the slope of the line?",
    "answer": "1.636, 18/11",
    "explanation": "For a line that passes through the points (x1, y1) and (x2, y2) in the xy-plane, the slope of the line can be calculated using the slope formula, m = (y2 - y1) / (x2 - x1). It's given that a line passes through the points (4, 6) and (15, 24) in the xy-plane. Substituting (4, 6) for (x1, y1) and (15, 24) for (x2, y2) in the slope formula, m = (24 - 6) / (15 - 4), yields m = 18/11. Therefore, the slope of the line is 18/11. Note that 18/11 and 1.636 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 463,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "What is the slope of the graph of y = (1/4)(27x + 15) + 7x in the xy-plane?",
    "answer": "13.75, 55/4",
    "explanation": "In the xy-plane, the graph of an equation in the form y = mx + b, where m and b are constants, has a slope of m and a y-intercept of (0, b). Applying the distributive property to the right-hand side of the given equation yields y = (27/4)x + (15/4) + 7x. Combining like terms yields y = (55/4)x + (15/4). This equation is in the form y = mx + b, where m = 55/4 and b = 15/4. It follows that the slope of the graph of y = (1/4)(27x + 15) + 7x in the xy-plane is 55/4. Note that 55/4 and 13.75 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 464,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "2x + y = 37 In triangle QRS, sides QR and RS each have a length of x centimeters and side SQ has a length of y centimeters. The given equation represents this situation. Which of the following is the best interpretation of 37 in this context?",
    "answer": "The sum of the lengths, in centimeters, of the three sides of the triangle",
    "explanation": "It's given that in triangle QRS, sides QR and RS each have a length of x centimeters. Therefore, the expression 2x represents the sum of the lengths, in centimeters, of sides QR and RS. It's also given that side SQ has a length of y centimeters. Therefore, the expression 2x + y represents the sum of the lengths, in centimeters, of sides QR, RS, and SQ. Since 2x + y is the sum of the lengths, in centimeters, of the three sides of the triangle and 2x + y = 37, it follows that 37 is the sum of the lengths, in centimeters, of the three sides of the triangle."
  },
  {
    "id": 465,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "The graph of 7x + 2y = -31 in the xy-plane has an x-intercept at (a, 0) and a y-intercept at (0, b), where a and b are constants. What is the value of b/a?",
    "answer": "2025-07-02 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "The x-coordinate a of the x-intercept (a, 0) can be found by substituting 0 for y in the given equation, which gives 7x + 2(0) = -31, or 7x = -31. Dividing both sides of this equation by 7 yields x = -31/7. Therefore, the value of a is -31/7. The y-coordinate b of the y-intercept (0, b) can be found by substituting 0 for x in the given equation, which gives 7(0) + 2y = -31, or 2y = -31. Dividing both sides of this equation by 2 yields y = -31/2. Therefore, the value of b is -31/2. It follows that the value of b/a is (-31/2) / (-31/7), which is equivalent to (31/2) * (7/31), or 7/2."
  },
  {
    "id": 466,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Keenan made 32 cups of vegetable broth. Keenan then filled x small jars and y large jars with all the vegetable broth he made. The equation 3x + 5y = 32 represents this situation. Which is the best interpretation of 5y in this context?",
    "answer": "The total number of cups of vegetable broth in the small jars",
    "explanation": " It's given that the equation 3x + 5y = 32 represents the situation where Keenan filled x small jars and y large jars with all the vegetable broth he made, which was 32 cups. Therefore, 3x represents the total number of cups of vegetable broth in the small jars and 5y represents the total number of cups of vegetable broth in the large jars."
  },
  {
    "id": 467,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "In the xy-plane, line ℓ passes through the point (0, 0) and is parallel to the line represented by the equation y = 8x + 2. If line ℓ also passes through the point (3, d), what is the value of d?",
    "answer": "24",
    "explanation": "A line in the xy-plane can be defined by the equation y = mx + b, where m is the slope of the line and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the line. It's given that line ℓ passes through the point (0, 0). Therefore, the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of line ℓ is 0. It's given that line ℓ is parallel to the line represented by the equation y = 8x + 2. Since parallel lines have the same slope, it follows that the slope of line ℓ is 8. Therefore, line ℓ can be defined by an equation in the form y = mx + b, where m = 8 and b = 0. Substituting 8 for m and 0 for b in y = mx + b yields the equation y = 8x + 0, or y = 8x. If line ℓ passes through the point (3, d), then when x = 3, y = d for the equation y = 8x. Substituting 3 for x and d for y in the equation y = 8x yields d = 8(3), or d = 24."
  },
  {
    "id": 468,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "In the xy-plane, line p has a slope of -5/3 and an x-intercept of (-6, 0). What is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of line p?",
    "answer": "-10",
    "explanation": "A line in the xy-plane can be represented by the equation y = mx + b, where m is the slope of the line and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept. It's given that line p has a slope of -5/3. Therefore, m = -5/3. It's also given that line p has an x-intercept of (-6, 0). Therefore, when x = -6, y = 0. Substituting -5/3 for m, -6 for x, and 0 for y in the equation y = mx + b yields 0 = (-5/3)(-6) + b, which is equivalent to 0 = 10 + b. Subtracting 10 from both sides of this equation yields -10 = b. Therefore, the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of line p is -10."
  },
  {
    "id": 469,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "In the xy-plane, line k intersects the y-axis at the point (0, -6) and passes through the point (2, 2). If the point (20, w) lies on line k, what is the value of w?",
    "answer": "74",
    "explanation": "The y-intercept of a line in the xy-plane is the ordered pair (x, y) of the point of intersection of the line with the y-axis. Since line k intersects the y-axis at the point (0, -6), it follows that (0, -6) is the y-intercept of this line. An equation of any line in the xy-plane can be written in the form y = mx + b, where m is the slope of the line and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept. Therefore, the equation of line k can be written as y = mx + (-6), or y = mx - 6. The value of m can be found by substituting the x- and y-coordinates from a point on the line, such as (2,2), for x and y, respectively. This results in 2 = 2m - 6. Solving this equation for m gives m = 4. Therefore, an equation of line k is y = 4x - 6. The value of w can be found by substituting the x-coordinate, 20, for x in the equation of line k and solving this equation for y. This gives y = 4(20) - 6, or y = 74. Since w is the y-coordinate of this point, w = 74."
  },
  {
    "id": 470,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Line p is defined by 4y + 8x = 6. Line r is perpendicular to line p in the xy-plane. What is the slope of line r?",
    "answer": ".5, 1/2",
    "explanation": "For an equation in slope-intercept form y = mx + b, m represents the slope of the line in the xy-plane defined by this equation. It's given that line p is defined by 4y + 8x = 6. Subtracting 8x from both sides of this equation yields 4y = -8x + 6. Dividing both sides of this equation by 4 yields y = -8/4 x + 6/4, or y = -2x + 3/2. Thus, the slope of line p is -2. If line r is perpendicular to line p, then the slope of line r is the negative reciprocal of the slope of line p. The negative reciprocal of -2 is -1/(-2) = 1/2. Note that 1/2 and .5 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 471,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A certain apprentice has enrolled in 85 hours of training courses. The equation 10x + 15y = 85 represents this situation, where x is the number of on-site training courses and y is the number of online training courses this apprentice has enrolled in. How many more hours does each online training course take than each on-site training course?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "It's given that the equation 10x + 15y = 85 represents the situation, where x is the number of on-site training courses, y is the number of online training courses, and 85 is the total number of hours of training courses the apprentice has enrolled in. Therefore, 10x represents the number of hours the apprentice has enrolled in on-site training courses, and 15y represents the number of hours the apprentice has enrolled in online training courses. Subtracting these numbers gives 15 - 10, or 5 more hours each online training course takes than each on-site training course. ​"
  },
  {
    "id": 472,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "In the xy-plane, line k is defined by x + y = 0. Line j is perpendicular to line k, and the y-intercept of line j is (0,3). Which of the following is an equation of line j?",
    "answer": "x - y = -3",
    "explanation": "It's given that line j is perpendicular to line k and that line k is defined by the equation x + y = 0. This equation can be rewritten in slope-intercept form, y = -x, where m represents the slope of the line. Thus, the slope of line k is -1. Since line j and line k are perpendicular, their slopes are opposite reciprocals of each other. Thus, the slope of line j is 1. It's given that the y-intercept of line j is (0,3). Therefore, the equation for line j in slope-intercept form is y = x + 3, which can be rewritten as x - y = -3."
  },
  {
    "id": 473,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "The line with the equation (4/5)x + (1/3)y = 1 is graphed in the xy-plane. What is the x-coordinate of the x-intercept of the line?",
    "answer": "1.25, 5/4",
    "explanation": "The y-coordinate of the x-intercept is 0, so 0 can be substituted for y, giving (4/5)x + (1/3)(0) = 1. This simplifies to (4/5)x = 1. Multiplying both sides by 5 gives 4x = 5. Dividing both sides of 4x = 5 by 4 gives x = 5/4, which is equivalent to 1.25. Note that 1.25 and 5/4 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 474,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "5G + 45R = 380 At a school fair, students can win colored tokens that are worth a different number of points depending on the color. One student won G green tokens and R red tokens worth a total of 380 points. The given equation represents this situation. How many more points is a red token worth than a green token?",
    "answer": "40",
    "explanation": "It's given that 5G + 45R = 380, where G is the number of green tokens and R is the number of red tokens won by one student and these tokens are worth a total of 380 points. Since the equation represents the situation where the student won points with green tokens and red tokens for a total of 380 points, each term on the left-hand side of the equation represents the number of points won for one of the colors. Since the coefficient of G in the given equation is 5, a green token must be worth 5 points. Similarly, since the coefficient of R in the given equation is 45, a red token must be worth 45 points. Therefore, a red token is worth 45 - 5 points, or 40 points, more than a green token."
  },
  {
    "id": 475,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "5x + 7y = 1, ax + by = 1 In the given pair of equations, a and b are constants. The graph of this pair of equations in the xy-plane is a pair of perpendicular lines. Which of the following pairs of equations also represents a pair of perpendicular lines?",
    "answer": "10x + 7y = 1, ax + 2by = 1",
    "explanation": "Two lines are perpendicular if their slopes are negative reciprocals, meaning that the slope of the first line is equal to -1 divided by the slope of the second line. Each equation in the given pair of equations can be written in slope-intercept form, y = mx + b, where m is the slope of the graph of the equation in the xy-plane. For the first equation, 5x + 7y = 1, subtracting 5x from both sides gives 7y = -5x + 1, and dividing both sides of this equation by 7 gives y = (-5/7)x + (1/7). Therefore, the slope of the graph of this equation is -5/7. For the second equation, ax + by = 1, subtracting ax from both sides gives by = -ax + 1, and dividing both sides of this equation by b gives y = (-a/b)x + (1/b). Therefore, the slope of the graph of this equation is -a/b. Since the slopes of perpendicular lines must be negative reciprocals, the correct choice is B."
  },
  {
    "id": 476,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Line h is defined by (1/5)x + (1/7)y - 70 = 0. Line j is perpendicular to line h in the xy-plane. What is the slope of line j?",
    "answer": "2025-05-07 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "It's given that line h is defined by (1/5)x + (1/7)y - 70 = 0. This equation can be written in slope-intercept form y = mx + b, where m is the slope of line h. Adding 70 to both sides of (1/5)x + (1/7)y - 70 = 0 yields (1/5)x + (1/7)y = 70. Subtracting (1/5)x from both sides of this equation yields (1/7)y = (-1/5)x + 70. Multiplying both sides by 7 yields y = (-7/5)x + 490. Therefore, the slope of line h is -7/5. Since line j is perpendicular to line h, the slope of line j must be the negative reciprocal of -7/5, which is 5/7."
  },
  {
    "id": 477,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "The graph of 9x - 10y = 19 is translated down 4 units in the xy-plane. What is the x-coordinate of the x-intercept of the resulting graph?",
    "answer": "59/9, 6.555, 6.556",
    "explanation": "When the graph of an equation in the form Ax + By = C is translated down k units in the xy-plane, the resulting graph can be represented by the equation Ax + B(y + k) = C. It's given that the graph of 9x - 10y = 19 is translated down 4 units. Therefore, the resulting graph can be represented by the equation 9x - 10(y + 4) = 19, or 9x - 10y - 40 = 19. Adding 40 to both sides of this equation yields 9x - 10y = 59. The x-coordinate of the x-intercept is found by substituting y = 0, which results in 9x = 59. Dividing both sides by 9 gives x = 59/9. Note that 59/9, 6.555, and 6.556 are valid ways to enter the correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 478,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Line ℓ in the xy-plane is perpendicular to the line with equation x = 2. What is the slope of line ℓ?",
    "answer": "0",
    "explanation": "It is given that line ℓ is perpendicular to a line whose equation is x = 2. A line whose equation is x = 2 is vertical, so ℓ must be horizontal. Horizontal lines have a slope of 0, so ℓ has a slope of 0."
  },
  {
    "id": 479,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "How many liters of a 25% saline solution must be added to 3 liters of a 10% saline solution to obtain a 15% saline solution?",
    "answer": "1,5",
    "explanation": "The total amount, in liters, of a saline solution can be expressed as the liters of each type of saline solution multiplied by the percent concentration of the saline solution. This gives 3(0.10), x(0.25), and (x + 3)(0.15), where x is the amount, in liters, of 25% saline solution and 10%, 15%, and 25% are represented as 0.10, 0.15, and 0.25, respectively. Thus, the equation 3(0.10) + 0.25x = 0.15(x + 3) must be true. Multiplying 3 by 0.10 and distributing 0.15 to (x + 3) yields 0.30 + 0.25x = 0.15x + 0.45. Subtracting 0.15x and 0.30 from each side of the equation gives 0.10x = 0.15. Dividing each side of the equation by 0.10 yields x = 1.5. Note that 1.5 and 3/2 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 480,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "What is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the graph of (3/7)x = (-5/9)y + 21 in the xy-plane?",
    "answer": "189/5, 37.8",
    "explanation": "A y-intercept of a graph in the xy-plane is a point where the graph intersects the y-axis, which is a point with an x-coordinate of 0. Substituting 0 for x in the given equation yields (3(0)/7) = (-5/9)y + 21, or 0 = (-5/9)y + 21. Subtracting 21 from both sides of this equation yields -21 = (-5/9)y. Multiplying both sides of this equation by -9 yields 189 = 5y. Dividing both sides of this equation by 5 yields 189/5 = y. Therefore, the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the graph of the given equation in the xy-plane is 189/5. Note that 189/5 and 37.8 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 481,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "The graph of the equation ax + ky = 6 is a line in the xy-plane, where a and k are constants. If the line contains the points (-2, -6) and (0, -3), what is the value of k?",
    "answer": "-2",
    "explanation": "The value of k can be found using the slope-intercept form of a linear equation, y = mx + b, where m is the slope and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept. The equation ax + ky = 6 can be rewritten in the form y = (-ax/k) + (6/k). One of the given points, (0, -3), is the y-intercept. Thus, the y-coordinate of the y-intercept -3 must be equal to 6/k. Multiplying both sides by k gives -3k = 6. Dividing both sides by -3 gives k = -2."
  },
  {
    "id": 482,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "5x = 15 - 4x + y = -2 The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of x + y?",
    "answer": "13",
    "explanation": "Adding the second equation of the given system to the first equation yields  \n5x + (-4x + y) = 15 + (-2), which is equivalent to x + y = 13. So the value of x + y is 13."
  },
  {
    "id": 483,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "y = 12x - 20, y = 28 What is the solution (x, y) to the given system of equations?",
    "answer": "(4, 28)",
    "explanation": "The second equation in the given system is y = 28. Substituting 28 for y in the first equation in the given system yields 28 = 12x - 20. Adding 20 to both sides of this equation yields 48 = 12x. Dividing both sides of this equation by 12 yields 4 = x. Therefore, the solution (x, y) to the given system of equations is (4, 28)."
  },
  {
    "id": 484,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A petting zoo sells two types of tickets. The standard ticket, for admission only, costs $5. The premium ticket, which includes admission and food to give to the animals, costs $12. One Saturday, the petting zoo sold a total of 250 tickets and collected a total of $2,300 from ticket sales. Which of the following systems of equations can be used to find the number of standard tickets, s, and premium tickets, p, sold on that Saturday?",
    "answer": "s + p = 250 5s + 12p = 2,300",
    "explanation": "It's given that the petting zoo sells two types of tickets, standard and premium, and that s represents the number of standard tickets sold and p represents the number of premium tickets sold. It's also given that the petting zoo sold 250 tickets on one Saturday; thus, s + p = 250. It's also given that each standard ticket costs $5 and each premium ticket costs $12. Thus, the amount collected in ticket sales can be represented by 5s for standard tickets and 12p for premium tickets. On that Saturday the petting zoo collected a total of $2,300 from ticket sales; thus, 5s + 12p = 2,300. These two equations are correctly represented in choice A."
  },
  {
    "id": 485,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "y = 4x x = y + 6 The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of x?",
    "answer": "10",
    "explanation": "According to the first equation in the given system, y = 4. Substituting 4 for y in the second equation in the given system yields x = 4 + 6, or x = 10."
  },
  {
    "id": 486,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "x + y = 18 5y = x What is the solution (x, y) to the given system of equations?",
    "answer": "(15, 3)",
    "explanation": "The second equation in the given system defines the value of x as 5y. Substituting 5y for x into the first equation yields 5y + y = 18 or 6y = 18. Dividing each side of this equation by 6 yields y = 3. Substituting 3 for y in the second equation yields 5(3) = x or x = 15. Therefore, the solution (x, y) to the given system of equations is (15, 3)."
  },
  {
    "id": 487,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "x = 10 y = x + 21 The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of y?",
    "answer": "31",
    "explanation": "It's given by the first equation in the given system of equations that x = 10. Substituting 10 for x in the second equation in the given system yields y = 10 + 21, or y = 31. Therefore, the value of y is 31."
  },
  {
    "id": 488,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "y = 2x + 3 x = 1 What is the solution (x, y) to the given system of equations? ",
    "answer": "(1, 5)",
    "explanation": "Since it's given that x = 1, substituting 1 for x in the first equation yields y = 2(1) + 3. Simplifying the right-hand side of this equation yields y = 2 + 3, or y = 5. Therefore, the ordered pair (1, 5) is a solution to the given system of equations."
  },
  {
    "id": 489,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "A printer produces posters at a constant rate of 42\nposters per minute. At what rate, in posters per\nhour\n, does the printerproduce the posters?",
    "answer": "2520",
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 2520. There are 60 minutes in one hour. At a rate of 42\nposters per minute, the number of postersproduced in one hour can be determined by\n(42 posters / 1 minute) (60 minutes / 1 hour) which is 2,520 posters per hour."
  },
  {
    "id": 490,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "Each face of a fair 14-sided die is labeled with a number from 1 through 14, with a different number appearing on each face.If the die is rolled one time, what is the probability of rolling a 2",
    "answer": "2025-01-14 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "Choice A is correct. The total number of possible outcomes for rolling a fair 14-sided die is\n14. The number of possibleoutcomes for rolling a 2 is 1. The probability of rolling a 2\nis 1. The number of possible outcomes for rolling a 2 divided by thetotal number of possible outcomes, or 1/14.\n. "
  },
  {
    "id": 491,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Probability and conditional probability",
    "question": "There are 55 students in Spanish club. A sample of the Spanish club students was selected at random and asked whetherthey intend to enroll in a new study program. Of those surveyed, 20% responded that they intend to enroll in the studyprogram. Based on this survey, which of the following is the best estimate of the total number of Spanish club students whointend to enroll in the study program?",
    "answer": "11",
    "explanation": "It’s given that 20% of the students surveyed responded that they intend to enroll in the study program.Therefore, the proportion of students in Spanish club who intend to enroll in the study program, based on the survey, is\n.Since there are 55 total students in Spanish club, the best estimate for the total number of these students who intend toenroll in the study program is 55(0.20)\n, or 11."
  },
  {
    "id": 492,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "For a person m miles from a fl ash of lightning, the length of the time interval fromthe moment the person sees the lightning to the moment the person hears thethunder is\nk seconds. The ratio of m to k can be estimated to be 1 to 5. Accordingto this estimate, the person is how many miles from a fl ash of lightning if the timeinterval is 25 seconds?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the ratio of m to k is estimated to be 1 to 5. Therefore, when k = 20, the relationshipbetween these ratios can be expressed by the proportion m/25 = 1/5. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 25 yields m = 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 493,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "A customer spent $27 to purchase oranges at $3 per pound. How many pounds of oranges did the customer purchase?",
    "answer": "9",
    "explanation": "t’s given that the customer spent $27 to purchase oranges at $3 per pound. Therefore, the numberof pounds of oranges the customer purchased is\n$27(1 pound / $3), or 9 pounds."
  },
  {
    "id": 494,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "A mechanical device in a workshop produces items at a constant rate of 60 items per hour. At this rate, how many items willthe mechanical device produce in\nhours?",
    "answer": "180",
    "explanation": "It's given that a mechanical device produces items at a constant rate of 60 items per hour. At this rate,the mechanical device will produce ( 60 items / 1 hour)  ( 3 hour), or 180 items in 3 hours."
  },
  {
    "id": 495,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "A group of monarch butterfl ies migrated from Chicago, Illinois, to Michoacán,Mexico, fl ying a total of 2,100 miles. It took a single butterfl y in the group 120 daysto travel this route one way. On average, how many miles did the butterfl y travel perday?",
    "answer": "17.5",
    "explanation": "If the butterfly traveled 2,100 miles in 120 days, then it traveled, on average, (2100miles per day / 120 days) = 17.5 miles."
  },
  {
    "id": 496,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "In a box of pens, the ratio of black pens to red pens is 8to 1. There are 40 black pens in the box. How many red pens are inthe box?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the ratio of black pens to red pens is 8 to 1. Therefore, there are 1/8 as many red pens asblack pens in the box. It’s also given that there are 40 black pens in the box. Therefore, the number of red pens is 1/8 of the 40 black pens. Thus, the number of red pens is 40(1/8), or 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 497,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Inference from sample statistics and margin of error",
    "question": "A city has 50 city council members. A reporter polled a random sample of 20 citycouncil members and found that 6 of those polled supported a specifi c bill. Basedon the sample, which of the following is the best estimate of the number of citycouncil members in the city who support the bill?",
    "answer": "15",
    "explanation": "Because a random sample of the city council was polled, the proportion of the sample who supportedthe bill is expected to be approximately equal to the proportion of the total city council who supports the bill. Since 6 of the20 polled, or 30%, supported the bill, it can be estimated that\n, or 15, city council members support the bill."
  },
  {
    "id": 498,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "The population density of Worthington is 290 people per square mile. Worthington has a population of 92,800people. Whatis the area, in square miles, of Worthington?",
    "answer": "320",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the population density of Worthington is 290 people per square mile and Worthington hasa population of 92,800 people. Therefore, the area of Worthington is 92,800 people ( 1 square miles / 290 people), which is equivalent to ( 92,800 square miles / 290 ), or 320 square miles."
  },
  {
    "id": 499,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "A wind turbine completes 900 revolutions in 50 minutes. At this rate, how many revolutions per minute does this turbinecomplete?",
    "answer": "18",
    "explanation": "Dividing the number of revolutions by the number of minutes gives the number of revolutions the turbinecompletes per minute. It’s given that the wind turbine completes 900 revolutions in 50 minutes. Therefore, at this rate, thisturbine completes (900/50) , or 18, revolutions per minute."
  },
  {
    "id": 500,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "What percentage of 300 is 75 ?",
    "answer": "0.25",
    "explanation": "Let x represent the percentage of 300 that is 75 . This can be written as x /100(300) = 75, or 3x = 75. Dividing both sides of this equation by 3 yield x = 25. Therefore, 25% of 300 is 75."
  },
  {
    "id": 501,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "The cost of a certain shirt is $20 before a 5% sales tax is added. What is the totalcost, including sales tax, to purchase the shirt?",
    "answer": "21",
    "explanation": "Choice C is correct. The total cost to purchase the shirt is the $20 cost of the shirt plus the 5% sales tax. The value of the 5%sales tax on the $20 shirt is equivalent to (0.05)($20), or $1. Therefore, the total cost to purchase the shirt is $20 + $1, or $21."
  },
  {
    "id": 502,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "The ratio of the length of line segment XY to the length of line segment ZV is 6 to 1. If the length of line segment\nis 102 inches, what is the length, in inches, of line segment ZV?",
    "answer": "17",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the ratio of the length of line segment XY to the length of line segment ZV is 6 to 1,which means XY / ZV = 6 / 1. It’s given that the length of line segment XY is 102 inches. If the length, in inches, of line segment ZV is represented by L, the value of L can be calculated by solving the equation 102 / L = 6 /1 or 102 / L = 6. Multiplying eachside of this equation by L yields 102 = 6L. Dividing each side of this equation by 6 yields 17 = L. Therefore, the length ofline segment ZV is 17inches."
  },
  {
    "id": 503,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "The ratio of t to u is 1 to 2, and .What is the value of u ?",
    "answer": "20",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the ratio of t to u is 1 to 2. Since , it follows that the ratio of 10 to u is also 1 to 2. Therelationship between these ratios can be represented by the proportion 10 / u = 1 /2 . Multiplying both sides of this equation by2 and then by u yields 20 =u."
  },
  {
    "id": 504,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "Last year, 200 students enrolled in an interior design program. This year, the number of students enrolled is 147% of lastyear’s number. How many students are enrolled in the interior design program this year?",
    "answer": "294",
    "explanation": "It's given that the number of students enrolled in an interior design program this year is 147%of lastyear's number, which is 200.\n147% of 200 can be expressed as (147/100)(200) , or (1.47)(200) , which is equivalent to 294. Therefore, 294 students are enrolled in the interior design program this year."
  },
  {
    "id": 505,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "21 is 21% of what number?",
    "answer": "42",
    "explanation": "Let x represent the number that 21 is 21% of. It follows that 21 / x = 21 /100. Multiplying each side of thisequation by x yields 21 = 21x / 100 . Multiplying each side of this equation by 100 yields 2,100 = 21x. Dividing each side of this equation by 21 yields 100 = x. Therefore, 21is 21% of 100"
  },
  {
    "id": 506,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "A special camera is used for underwater ocean research. When the camera is at a depth of\n58 fathoms, what is the camera'sdepth in feet? ( 1 fathom = 6 feet)",
    "answer": "348",
    "explanation": "It's given that 1 fathom is equivalent to 6 feet. Therefore, 58 fathoms is equivalent to (58 fathoms) (6 feet / 1 fathom) , or 348 feet. Thus, when the camera is at a depth of fathoms, the camera's depth, in feet, is"
  },
  {
    "id": 507,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "One-variable data: Distributions and measures of center and spread",
    "question": "73, 74, 75, 77, 79, 82, 84, 85, 91 What is the median of the data shown?",
    "answer": "79",
    "explanation": "The median of a data set with an odd number of values is the middle value of the set when thevalues are ordered from least to greatest. Because the given data set consists of nine values that are ordered from least togreatest, the median is the fi fth value in the data set. Therefore, the median of the data shown is 79."
  },
  {
    "id": 508,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "How many yards are equivalent to 612inches? (1 yard = 36 inches)",
    "answer": "17",
    "explanation": "It’s given that 1 yard = 36 inches. Therefore, 612 inches is equivalent to 612 inches ( 1 yard / 36 inches),which can be rewritten as ( 612 yard / 36 ) , or 17yards."
  },
  {
    "id": 509,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Probability and conditional probability",
    "question": "Of the 8 planets in our solar system, 4 are considered rocky. If a student randomlyselects 1 of those 8 planets as a topic for a report, what is the probability that theselected planet will be rocky?",
    "answer": "2025-01-02 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "If one of these planets is selected at random, the probability that the selected planet will be rocky iscalculated by dividing the number of planets that are considered rocky by the total number of planets. It’s given that 4 of the8 total planets are considered rocky. Therefore, the probability that the selected planet will be rocky is 4/8, which isequivalent to 1/2."
  },
  {
    "id": 510,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "What is 23% of 100?",
    "answer": "23",
    "explanation": "23 of 100 can be calculated by multiplying (23/100) by 100, which yields (23/100) 100, or 23."
  },
  {
    "id": 511,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "Shaquan has 7 red cards and 28 blue cards. What is the ratio of redcards to blue cards that Shaquan has?",
    "answer": "1 to 4",
    "explanation": "Choice A is correct. It’s given that Shaquan has 7 red cards and 28 blue cards. Therefore, the ratio of red cards to blue cardsthat Shaquan has is 7 to 28. This ratio can be reduced by dividing both parts of the ratio by 7, which yields the ratio 1 to 4."
  },
  {
    "id": 512,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Inference from sample statistics and margin of error",
    "question": "A random sample of 50 people from a town with a population of 14,878 wereasked to name their favorite flavor of ice cream. If 7 people in the sample namedchocolate as their favorite ice‑cream flavor, about how many people in the townwould be expected to name chocolate?",
    "answer": "2100",
    "explanation": "Using cross multiplication, 7 * 14,878 = x * 50; solving for x yields 2,083. The choiceclosest to the value of 2,083 is 2,100"
  },
  {
    "id": 513,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "How many yards are equivalent to 77 rods? (5.5 yards = 1 rod)",
    "answer": "423.5",
    "explanation": "It's given that 5.5 yards = 1 rod . Therefore, 77 rods is equivalent to (77 rods) ( 5.5 yards / 1 rod) , or 423.5 yards."
  },
  {
    "id": 514,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "One-variable data: Distributions and measures of center and spread",
    "question": "4, 10 , 18, 4, 4, 5, 6, 5 What is the median of the data set shown?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "If a data set contains an even number of data values, when the data values are listed in ascending ordescending order, the median is between the two middle values. The given data set contains 8 values. When listed inascending order, the data set is 4, 4, 4, 5, 5, 6, 10, 18 and the two middle values are 5 and 5. Since the two middle values arethe same, the median must be 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 515,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "The International Space Station orbits Earth at an average speed of 4.76 miles persecond. What is the space station’s average speed in miles per hour?",
    "answer": "17136",
    "explanation": "Since 1 minute = 60 seconds and 1 hour = 60 minutes, it follows that 1 hour = (60)(60), or 3,600seconds. Using this conversion factor, the space station’s average speed of ((4.76 miles / second) * (3,600 seconds / hour)) = 17,136 miles / hour second, or 17,136 miles per hour."
  },
  {
    "id": 516,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "The population density of Iceland, in people per square kilometer of land area,increased from 2.5 in 1990 to 3.3 in 2014. During this time period, the land area ofIceland was 100,250 square kilometers. By how many people did Iceland’spopulation increase from 1990 to 2014?",
    "answer": "80200",
    "explanation": "The increase in Iceland’s population can be found by multiplying the increase in population density, inpeople per square kilometer, by the area, in square kilometers. It’s given that the population density of Iceland was 2.5 peopleper square kilometer in 1990 and 3.3 people per square kilometer in 2014. The increase in population density can be foundby subtracting 2.5 from 3.3, which yields 0.8. It’s given that the land area of Iceland was 100,250 square kilometers. Thus, theincrease in population is 0.8(100,250), or 80,200."
  },
  {
    "id": 517,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "The ratio 140 to m is equivalent to the ratio 4 to 28. What is the value of m?",
    "answer": "980",
    "explanation": "It's given that the ratio 140 to m is equivalent to the ratio 4 to 28. Therefore, the value of m  canbe found by solving the equation (140 / m) = (4 / 28). Multiplying each side of this equation by m yields 140 = (4m / 28). Multiplying eachside of this equation by 28 yields 3,920 = 4m. Dividing each side of this equation by 4 yields 980 = m. Therefore, thevalue of is 980."
  },
  {
    "id": 518,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Evaluating statistical claims: Observational studies and experiments",
    "question": "Residents of a town were surveyed to determine whether they are satisfi ed with theconcession stand at the local park. A random sample of 200 residents wasselected. All 200 responded, and 87% said they are satisfi ed. Based on thisinformation, which of the following statements must be true? I. Of all the town residents, 87% would say they are satisfi ed with the concession stand at the local park. II. If another random sample of 200 residents were surveyed, 87% would say they are satisfied.",
    "answer": "Neither",
    "explanation": "The purpose of surveying a random sample of residents is to approximate the percent of the townresidents that are satisfi ed with the concession stand. The sample doesn’t necessarily get the same result as surveyingevery resident of the town, nor would another sample necessarily have identical results. Therefore, although it’s possible thateither statement I or statement II could prove true by surveying every resident of the town, these statements cannot beproven true solely based on the results of the sample."
  },
  {
    "id": 519,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "How many fluid ounces are equivalent to 76 quarts? 8 fluids ounces = 1 cup and 4 cups = 1 quart",
    "answer": "2432",
    "explanation": "It's given that 4 cups = 1 quart. It follows that 76 quarts is equivalent to (76 quarts) (4 cups / 1 quarts), or 304 cups. It's also given that 8 fluid ounces = 1 cup. It follows that 304 cups is equivalent to (304 cups) ( 8 fluid ounces / 1 cup) , or 2,432 fluid ounces."
  },
  {
    "id": 520,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "If x / y = 4 and 24x / ny = 4, what is the value of n?",
    "answer": "24",
    "explanation": "The equation 24x / ny = 4 can be rewritten as (24 / n) ( x / y) = 4. It's given that x / y = 4. Substituting 4 for x /4 in the equation (24 / n) (x / y) = 4 yields (24 / n) (4) = 4. Multiplying both sides of this equation by n yields (24) (4) = 4n. Dividing both sides of this equation by 4 yields 24 = n. Therefore, the value of n is 24."
  },
  {
    "id": 521,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "Pure beeswax has a density of 0.555 ounce per cubic inch. An online companysells pure beeswax at a price of $8.00 per ounce. What is the selling price, indollars per cubic inch, for pure beeswax purchased from this company?",
    "answer": "4.44",
    "explanation": "The selling price, in dollars per cubic inch, is found by multiplying the density, in ounces per cubicinch, by the unit price, in dollars per ounce: (0.555 ounce / 1 cubic inch) ( $8 / 1 ounce) yields $4.44 / 1 cubic inch."
  },
  {
    "id": 522,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Inference from sample statistics and margin of error",
    "question": "A study was done on the weights of different types of fi sh in a pond. A randomsample of fi sh were caught and marked in order to ensure that none were weighedmore than once. The sample contained 150 largemouth bass, of which 30%weighed more than 2 pounds. Which of the following conclusions is bestsupported by the sample data?",
    "answer": "Approximately 30% of all largemouth bass in the pond weigh more than 2 pounds.",
    "explanation": "The sample of 150 largemouth bass was selected at random from all the largemouth bass in the pond,and since 30% of the fi sh in the sample weighed more than 2 pounds, it can be concluded that approximately 30% of alllargemouth bass in the pond weigh more than 2 pounds."
  },
  {
    "id": 523,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Probability and conditional probability",
    "question": "In a bag, there are 7 red, 4 white, 33 blue, and 33 yellow cubes. If one of these cubes is selected at random, what is theprobability of selecting a cube that is neither blue nor yellow?",
    "answer": "2025-01-07 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "If the cube is neither blue nor yellow, then it must be either red or white.Therefore, the probability of selecting a cube that is neither blue nor yellow is equivalent to the probability of selecting a cubethat is either red or white. If one of these cubes is selected at random, the probability of selecting a cube that is either red orwhite is equal to the sum of the number of red cubes and white cubes divided by the total number of cubes in the bag. There are 7\nred cubes, 4 white cubes, and 77 total cubes in the bag. Therefore, the probability of selecting a red or white cube is (7 + 4) / 77, which is equivalent to 11 / 77, or 1 / 7. Thus, if one cube is selected at random, the probability of selecting a cube that isneither blue nor yellow is 1 / 7."
  },
  {
    "id": 524,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "One-variable data: Distributions and measures of center and spread",
    "question": "15, 14, 18, 17, x\nThe mean and the median of the fi ve numbers above are equal. Which of thefollowing is NOT a possible value of x?",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "If x is 6, then the fi ve numbers in the given list are 15, 14, 18, 17, 6. The mean of these fi ve numbers is thesum of all the values divided by the number of values, or (70 / 5) = 14. The median of these fi venumbers can be found by ordering the numbers from least to greatest and determining the middle value. When ordered fromleast to greatest, the numbers in the given list are 6, 14, 15, 17, 18, and the middle value is 15. Since the mean is 14 and themedian is 15, the mean and median aren’t equal when x is 6."
  },
  {
    "id": 525,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Inference from sample statistics and margin of error",
    "question": "A park ranger asked a random sample of visitors how far they hiked during theirvisit. Based on the responses, the estimated mean was found to be 4.5 miles, withan associated margin of error of 0.5 miles. Which of the following is the bestconclusion from these data?",
    "answer": "It is plausible that the mean distance hiked for all visitors is between 4 and 5 miles.",
    "explanation": "The given estimated mean has an associated margin of error because from sample data, the populationmean can’t be determined precisely. Rather, from the sample mean, an interval can be determined within which it’s plausiblethat the population’s mean is likely to lie. Since the estimated mean is 4.5 miles with an associated margin of error of 0.5miles, it follows that between 4.5 - 0.5 miles and 4.5 + 0.5 miles, or between 4 and 5 miles, is plausibly the mean distancehiked for all visitors."
  },
  {
    "id": 526,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "For the fi nale of a TV show, viewers could use either social media or a textmessage to vote for their favorite of two contestants. The contestant receivingmore than 50% of the vote won. An estimated 10% of the viewers voted, and 30%of the votes were cast on social media. Contestant 2 earned 70% of the votes castusing social media and 40% of the votes cast using a text message. Based on thisinformation, which of the following is an accurate conclusion?",
    "answer": "Viewers voting by social media were more likely to prefer Contestant 2 than were viewers voting by text message.",
    "explanation": "It is given that Contestant 2 earned 70% of the votes cast using social media and 40% of the votes castusing a text message. Based on this information, viewers voting by social media were more likely to prefer Contestant 2 thanwere viewers voting by text message."
  },
  {
    "id": 527,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "During the fi rst month of sales, a company sold 1,300,000 units of a certain type ofsmartphone. During the same month, 15% of the units sold were returned. If salesand the return rate remain the same for each of the next 5 months, about howmany units of this smartphone will be returned to the company during this 6-monthperiod?",
    "answer": "1170000",
    "explanation": "Of the 1,300,000 units sold during the fi rst month, 15% were returned, so (1,300,000)(0.15) = 195,000\nunits were returned during the fi rst month. If the units were sold and returned at the same rate for the next 5 months, then a total of (195,000)(6) = 1,170,000 smartphone units were returned during the 6-month period."
  },
  {
    "id": 528,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "At a particular track meet, the ratio of coaches to athletes is 1\nto 26\n. If there are x\ncoaches at the track meet, which of thefollowing expressions represents the number of athletes at the track meet?",
    "answer": "26x",
    "explanation": "It’s given that at a particular track meet, the ratio of coaches to athletes is 1 to 26. If one number in aratio is multiplied by a value, the other number must be multiplied by the same value in order to maintain the same ratio. If there are x coaches at the track meet, multiplying both numbers in the ratio by x yields 1(x) to 25(x), or x to 26x.Therefore, the expression 26x represents the number of athletes at the track meet."
  },
  {
    "id": 529,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "On April 18, 1775, Paul Revere set off on his midnight ride from Charlestown toLexington. If he had ridden straight to Lexington without stopping, he would havetraveled 11 miles in 26 minutes. In such a ride, what would the average speed ofhis horse have been, to the nearest tenth of a mile per hour?",
    "answer": "127/5",
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 25.4. The average speed is the total distance divided by the total time. The total distance is 11 milesand the total time is 26 minutes. Thus, the average speed is 11/26\nmiles per minute. The question asks for the average speedin miles per hour, and there are 60 minutes in an hour; converting miles per minute to miles per hour gives the following: (11 miles / 26 miles)(60 minutes / 1 hour) = 660 /  26 miles per hour  = 127/5"
  },
  {
    "id": 530,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "Last year, Cedric had\nplants in his garden. This year, the number of plants in Cedric’s garden is\ngreater than thenumber of plants in his garden last year. How many plants does Cedric have in his garden this year?",
    "answer": "56",
    "explanation": "It’s given that Cedric had 35 plants in his garden last year and that the number of plants in Cedric'sgarden this year is 60% greater than the number of plants in his garden last year. It follows that the number of plants inCedric’s garden this year is 35 plus 60% of 35, which is equal to 35 + 35( 60 / 100), or 35 + 35(0.6). This expression is equivalent to 35 + 21, or 56. Therefore, Cedric has 56 plants in his garden this year."
  },
  {
    "id": 531,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Two-variable data: Models and scatter plots",
    "question": "An inspector begins a day of work with a large sample of shirts that need to bechecked for defects. The inspector works at a constant rate throughout themorning. What type of model is best to model the number of shirts remaining to bechecked for defects at any given time throughout the morning?",
    "answer": "A linear model with a negative slope",
    "explanation": "Since the work is done at a constant rate, a linear model best models the situation. The number of shirtsremaining is dependent on the length of time the inspector has worked; therefore, if the relationship were graphed, timewould be the variable of the horizontal axis and the number of remaining shirts would be the variable of the\nvertical axis.Since the number of shirts decreases as the time worked increases, it follows that the slope of this graph is negative."
  },
  {
    "id": 532,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Probability and conditional probability",
    "question": "At a movie theater, there are a total of 350\ncustomers. Each customer is located in either theater A, theater B, or theater C. Ifone of these customers is selected at random, the probability of selecting a customer who is located in theater A is\n0.48,and the probability of selecting a customer who is located in theater B is 0.24\n. How many customers are located in theater C?",
    "answer": "98",
    "explanation": "If the probability of selecting a customer in theater A is 0.48, then (0.48)(350), or 168, customers are located in theater A. If the probability of selecting a customer in theater B is 0.24, then (0.24)(350), or 84, customers are located in theater B. It follows that there are 168 + 84, or 252, customers in theater A and theater B.Therefore, there are 350 - 252, or 98, customers in theater C."
  },
  {
    "id": 533,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "An object has a mass of 168\ngrams and a volume of 24\ncubic centimeters. What is the density, in grams per cubiccentimeter, of the object?",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "Dividing themass, in grams, of the object by the volume, in cubic centimeters, of the object gives the density, in grams per cubiccentimeter, of the object. It follows that the density of the object is 168 grams / 24 cubic centimeters, which is equivalent to 168 / 24 grams percubic centimeter, or 7 grams per cubic centimeter."
  },
  {
    "id": 534,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Probability and conditional probability",
    "question": "Each vertex of a 14 -sided polygon is labeled with one of the 14 letters A through N, with a different letter at each vertex. Ifone vertex is selected at random, what is the probability that the letter D will be at the selected vertex? (Express your answeras a decimal or fraction, not as a percent.)",
    "answer": "2025-01-14 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "If one vertex of the polygon is selected at random, the probability that the letter D will be at theselected vertex is equal to the number of vertices labeled with the letter D divided by the total number of vertices. It's giventhat each vertex is labeled with one of the 14 letters A  through N, with a different letter at each vertex. It follows that there is 1 vertex labeled with the letter D. It's also given that the polygon is 14-sided. It follows that there are a total of 14 vertices.Thus, the probability that the letter D will be at the selected vertex is 1/ 14."
  },
  {
    "id": 535,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "Which expression represents the result of increasing a positive quantity w by 43 %?",
    "answer": "1.43w",
    "explanation": "The result of increasing a positive quantity w by x% can be represented by the expression ( 1 + x/100)w. Therefore, the result of increasing a positive quantity w by 43% can be found by substituting 43 for x in the expression ( 1 + x / 100)w,, which gives ( 1 + 43 / 100)w,, or 1.43w. Thus, the expression 1.43w represents the result of increasing a positive quantity w by 43%."
  },
  {
    "id": 536,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "Tanya earns $13.50 per hour at her part-time job. When she works z\nhours, she earns 13.50z dollars. Which of the following expressions gives the amount, indollars, Tanya will earn if she works\n3z hours?",
    "answer": "3(13.50z)",
    "explanation": "Since her hourly rate is constant, ifshe works 3 times as many hours, or 3z\nhours, she will earn 3 times as many dollars, or 3(13.50z)."
  },
  {
    "id": 537,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "The population of City A increased by 7% from 2015 to 2016. If the 2016 population is k times the 2015 population, what isthe value of k?",
    "answer": "1.07",
    "explanation": "It's given that the population of City A increased by 7% from 2015 to 2016. Therefore, the population of City A in 2016 includes 100% of the population of City A in 2015 plus an additional 7% of the population of City A in 2015.This means that the population of City A in 2016 is 107% of the population in 2015. Thus, the population of City A in 2016 is 107/100, or 1.07, times the 2015 population. Therefore, the value of k is 1.07."
  },
  {
    "id": 538,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "One-variable data: Distributions and measures of center and spread",
    "question": "The list gives the mass, in grams, of\nalpine marmots. 4,010; 4,010; 3,030; 4,050; 3,050 What is the mean mass, in grams, of these 5 alpine marmots?",
    "answer": "3630",
    "explanation": "The sum of the masses, in grams, of these alpine marmots is 4,010; 4,010; 3,030; 4,050; 3,050, or 18,150\ngrams. The number of alpine marmots in the data set is 5. Therefore, the mean mass, in grams, of these 5 alpinemarmots is 18,150 / 5, or 3,630."
  },
  {
    "id": 539,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "Which of the following represents the result of increasing the quantity x\nby 9%, where x > 0?",
    "answer": "1.09x",
    "explanation": "Increasing the positive quantity x by 9% is the result of adding 9% of x to x. 9% of x can be representedalgebraically as 9/100x, or 0.09x. Adding this expression to x yields x + 0.09x, or 1.09x."
  },
  {
    "id": 540,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "The number k is 36% greater than 50. If k is the product of50 and r, what is the value of r?",
    "answer": "1.36r",
    "explanation": "Multiplying the terms (36 / 100) (50) yields 18, so k = 50, or k = 68. It’s also given that k is the product of 50 and r, which can be rewritten as k = 50r. Substituting 68 for k yields 68 = 50r. Dividing both sides of this equation by 50 yields r =1.36."
  },
  {
    "id": 541,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "Jennifer bought a box of Crunchy Grain cereal. The nutrition facts on the box statethat a serving size of the cereal is 3/4 cup and provides 210 calories, 50 of whichare calories from fat. In addition, each serving of the cereal provides 180 milligrams of potassium, which is 5% of the daily allowance for adults. If p percent of an adult’s daily allowance of potassium is provided by x servings of CrunchyGrain cereal per day, which of the following expresses p in terms of x?",
    "answer": "p =5x",
    "explanation": "It’s given that each serving of Crunchy Grain cereal provides 5% of an adult’s daily allowance ofpotassium, so x servings would provide x times 5%. The percentage of an adult’s daily allowance of potassium, p, is 5 timesthe number of servings, x. Therefore, the percentage of an adult’s daily allowance of potassium can be expressed as p =5x."
  },
  {
    "id": 542,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "The expression 0.35x represents the result of decreasing a positive quantity x by what percent?",
    "answer": "0.65",
    "explanation": "Let n% represent the percent by which the positive quantity x is decreased to result in 0.35x. The value of n can be found by solving the equation x - (n/100)x = 0.35x. Since x is a common factor of each of the terms on theleft-hand side of this equation, the equation can be rewritten as x( 1 - n/100) = 0.35x. Dividing each side of this equation by x yields 1 - (n/100) = 0.35. Multiplying each side of this equation by 100 yields 100 - n = 35. Subtracting 100 fromeach side of this equation yields -n = -65. Dividing each side of this equation by -1yields n = 65. Therefore, the expression represents the result of decreasing the positive quantity x by 65%."
  },
  {
    "id": 543,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "A school district is forming a committee to discuss plans for the construction of anew high school. Of those invited to join the committee, 15% are parents ofstudents, 45% are teachers from the current high school, 25% are school anddistrict administrators, and the remaining 6 individuals are students. How manymore teachers were invited to join the committee than school and districtadministrators?",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "The 6 students represent (100 - 15 - 45 - 25) % = 15% of those invited to join the committee. If x\npeople were invited to join the committee, then 0.15x = 6\n. Thus, there were ( 6 /0.15) = 40\npeople invited to join thecommittee. It follows that there were 0.45(40) = 18\nteachers and 0.25(40) = 10\nschool and district administrators invitedto join the committee. Therefore, there were 8 more teachers than school and district administrators invited to join thecommittee."
  },
  {
    "id": 544,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Evaluating statistical claims: Observational studies and experiments",
    "question": "A sample of 40 fourth-grade students was selected at random from a certainschool. The 40 students completed a survey about the morning announcements,and 32 thought the announcements were helpful. Which of the following is thelargest population to which the results of the survey can be applied?",
    "answer": "All fourth-grade students at the school",
    "explanation": "Selecting a sample of a reasonable size at random to use for a survey allows the results from that surveyto be applied to the population from which the sample was selected, but not beyond this population. In this case, thepopulation from which the sample was selected is all fourth-grade students at a certain school. Therefore, the results of thesurvey can be applied to all fourth-grade students at the school."
  },
  {
    "id": 545,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "The positive number a is 2,241% of the sum of the positive numbers b and c, and b is 83% of c. What percent of b is a?",
    "answer": "49.41",
    "explanation": "It’s given that a is 2,241% of the sum of b and c. This can be represented by the equation a = (2,241/100) (b + c), or a = 22.41( b + c). It’s also given that that b is 83% of c. This can be represented by the equation b = (83 / 100)c, or b = 0.83c. Dividing both sides of this equation by 0.83yields (b / 0.83) = c. Substituting (b / 0.83) for c in the equation a = 22.41 ( b + c) yields a = 22.41 ( b + (b / 0.83)), or a = 22.41 (1.83b / 0.83), which is equivalent to a = 41.0103b / 0.83, or a = 49.41b. This equation is equivalent to a = (4,941 / 100); therefore, a is 4,941% of b."
  },
  {
    "id": 546,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "One-variable data: Distributions and measures of center and spread",
    "question": "Data set A consists of positive integers less than. The list shown gives of the integers from data set A. 43, 45, 44, 43, 38, 39, 40, 46, 40 The mean of these 9 integers is 42. If the mean of data set A is an integer that is greater than 42, what is the value of thelargest integer from data set A?",
    "answer": "52",
    "explanation": "The mean of a data set is calculated by dividing the sum of the data values by the number ofvalues. It’s given that data set A consists of 10 values, 9 of which are shown. Let x represent the 10th data value in data setA, which isn’t shown. The mean of data set A can be found using the expression (43 + 45 + 44 + 43 + 38 + 39 + 40 + 46 +40 + x) / 2 , or (378 + x) / 10.It’s given that the mean of the 9 values shown is 42 and that the mean of all 10 numbers is greater than 42. Consequently,the 10th data value,x, is larger than 42. It’s also given that the data values in data set A are positive integers less than 60.Thus, 42 < x < 60. Finally, it’s given that the mean of data set A is an integer. This means that the sum of the 10 data values, 378 + x, is divisible by 10. Thus,378 + x must have a ones digit of 0. It follows that x must have a ones digit of 2.Since 42 < x <60 and x has a ones digit of 2, the only possible value of x is 52. Since 52 is larger than any of the integersshown, the largest integer from data set A is 52.."
  },
  {
    "id": 547,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "One-variable data: Distributions and measures of center and spread",
    "question": "A data set of 27 different numbers has a mean of 33 and a median of 33. A newdata set is created by adding 7 to each number in the original data set that isgreater than the median and subtracting 7 from each number in the original dataset that is less than the median. Which of the following measures does NOT havethe same value in both the original and new data sets?",
    "answer": "Standard deviation",
    "explanation": "When a data set has an odd number of elements, the median can be found by ordering the values fromleast to greatest and determining the middle value. Out of the 27 different numbers in this data set, 13 numbers are belowthe median, one number is exactly 33, and 13 numbers are above the median. When 7 is subtracted from each number belowthe median and added to each number above the median, the data spread out from the median. Since the median of thisdata set, 33, is equivalent to the mean of the data set, the data also spread out from the mean. Since standard deviation is ameasure of how spread out the data are from the mean, a greater spread from the mean indicates an increased standarddeviation."
  },
  {
    "id": 548,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Probability and conditional probability",
    "question": "A grove has 6 rows of birch trees and 5 rows of maple trees. Each row of birch trees has 8 trees 20 feet or taller and 6 treesshorter than 20 feet. Each row of maple trees has 9 trees 20 feet or taller and 7 trees shorter than 20 feet. A tree from oneof these rows will be selected at random. What is the probability of selecting a maple tree, given that the tree is 20 feet ortaller?",
    "answer": "15/31",
    "explanation": "If a tree from one of these rows is selected at random, the probability of selecting a maple tree, giventhat the tree is 20\nfeet or taller, is equal to the number of maple trees that are 20 feet or taller divided by the total number oftrees that are 20 feet or taller. It's given that there are 6 rows of birch trees, and each row of birch trees has 8 trees that are 20 feet or taller. This means that there are a total of 6(8), or 48, birch trees that are 20 feet or taller. It's given that there are 5 rows of maple trees, and each row of maple trees has 9 trees that are 20 feet or taller. This means that there are a total of 5(9), or 45, maple trees that are 290 feet or taller. It follows that there are a total of 48 + 45, or 93, trees that are 20 feet ortaller. Therefore, the probability of selecting a maple tree, given that the tree is 20 feet or taller, is 45/93, or 15/31."
  },
  {
    "id": 549,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "A sample of oak has a density of 807 kilograms per cubic meter. The sample is in the shape of a cube, where each edge hasa length of 0.90 meters. To the nearest whole number, what is the mass, in kilograms, of this sample?",
    "answer": "588",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the sample is in the shape of a cube with edge lengths of 0.9 meters. Therefore, thevolume of the sample is 0.9 ^3, or 0.729, cubic meters. It’s also given that the sample has a density of 807 kilograms per 1 cubic meter. Therefore, the mass of this sample is 0.729 cubic meters ( 807 killograms / 1 cubic meter), or 588.303."
  },
  {
    "id": 550,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "The number a is 190% greater than the number b. The number b is 80% less than 24. What is the value of a?",
    "answer": "9.12",
    "explanation": "It's given that the number b is 80% less than 24. It follows that b is equal to 24 minus 80% of 24, which can be written as b = 24 - (80/100)24. This is equivalent to b = 24 - 0.8*(24), or b = 4.8. It's also given that the number a is 190% greater than the number b. It follows that a is equal to b plus 190% of b. Since b = 4.8, this can be written as a = 4.8 + (190/100)4.8. This is equivalent to a = 4.8 + 1.9(4.8), or a = 13.92."
  },
  {
    "id": 551,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "Jeremy deposited x dollars in his investment account on January 1, 2001. Theamount of money in the account doubled each year until Jeremy had 480 dollars inhis investment account on January 1, 2005. What is the value of x?",
    "answer": "30",
    "explanation": "The situation can be represented by the equation x(2^4) = 480, where the 2 represents the factthat the amount of money in the account doubled each year and the 4 represents the fact that there are 4 years betweenJanuary 1, 2001, and January 1, 2005. Simplifying x(2^4) = 480 gives 16x = 480. Therefore, x =30."
  },
  {
    "id": 552,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "One-variable data: Distributions and measures of center and spread",
    "question": "The mean score of 8 players in a basketball game was 14.5 points. If the highestindividual score is removed, the mean score of the remaining 7 players becomes12 points. What was the highest score?",
    "answer": "32",
    "explanation": "If the mean score of 8 players is 14.5, then the total of all 8 scores is 14.5 * 8 = 116. If the mean of 7scores is 12, then the total of all 7 scores is 12 * 7 = 84. Since the set of 7 scores was made by removing the highest scoreof the set of 8 scores, then the difference between the total of all 8 scores and the total of all 7 scores is equal to theremoved score: 116 - 84 = 32."
  },
  {
    "id": 553,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "If 4a/b = 6.7 and a / bn = 26.8, what is the value of n?",
    "answer": "2025-01-16 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "Dividing both sides of this equation by 4 yields (a /b ) = 1.675. The equation a / bn = 26.8 can be rewritten as ( a / b ) (1 / n). Substituting 1.675 for a/b in this equation yields (1.675)(1/n) = 26.8, or 1.675 / n = 26.8. Multiplying bothsides of this equation by n yields 1.675 = 26.8n. Dividing both sides of this equation by 26.8 yields n = 1/16."
  },
  {
    "id": 554,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "In 2008, Zinah earned 14% more than in 2007,  and in 2009 Zinah earned 4% more than in 2008. If Zinah earned y times asmuch in 2009 as in 2007, what is the value of y?",
    "answer": "1.1856",
    "explanation": "This situation can be represented by the equation j = (1 + (14/100))h, or j = 1.14h. It’s also given that in 2009 Zinah earned 4% more than in 2008. Let k represent theamount Zinah earned in 2009. This situation can be represented by the equation k = ( 1 + (4/100))j , or k = 1.04j.Substituting 1.14h for j in the equation k = 1.04j yields k = (1.04)(1.14h), or k = ( 1 + (4/100))j. If Zinah earned y times as much in 2009 as in 2007, then the value of y is 1.1856."
  },
  {
    "id": 555,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "The density of a certain type of wood is 353 kilograms per cubic meter. A sample of this type of wood is in the shape of acube and has a mass of 345 kilograms. To the nearest hundredth of a meter, what is the length of one edge of this sample?",
    "answer": "0.99",
    "explanation": "In this formula yields  (345 / 353) = s^3. Taking the cube root of both sides of this equation yields 3 square root 345 / 353 = s, or s = .99."
  },
  {
    "id": 556,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "210 is p% greater than 30. What is the value of p?",
    "answer": "600",
    "explanation": "Dividing bothsides of this equation by 30 yields 7 = 1 + (p/100). Subtracting 1 from both sides of this equation yields 6 = ( p / 100). Multiplyingboth sides of this equation by 100 yields p = 600. Therefore, the value of p is 600."
  },
  {
    "id": 557,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Probability and conditional probability",
    "question": "On May 10, 2015, there were 83 million Internet subscribers in Nigeria. The majorInternet providers were MTN, Globacom, Airtel, Etisalat, and Visafone. BySeptember 30, 2015, the number of Internet subscribers in Nigeria had increasedto 97 million. If an Internet subscriber in Nigeria on September 30, 2015, is selectedat random, the probability that the person selected was an MTN subscriber is 0.43.There were\np\nmillion MTN subscribers in Nigeria on September 30, 2015. To thenearest integer, what is the value of\np\n?",
    "answer": "42",
    "explanation": "It’s given that in Nigeria on September 30, 2015, the probability of selecting an MTN subscriberfrom all Internet subscribers is 0.43, that there were p million, or p(1,000,000), MTN subscribers, and that there were 97million, or 97,000,000, Internet subscribers. The probability of selecting an MTN subscriber from all Internet subscribers canbe found by dividing the number of MTN subscribers by the total number of Internet subscribers. Therefore, the equation  ( p(1,000,000) / 97,000,000)) = 0.43 can be used to solve for p. Dividing 1,000,000 from the numerator and denominator of theexpression on the left-hand side yields p/97 = .43. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 97 yields p = (0.43)(97) = 41.71, which, to the nearest integer, is 42."
  },
  {
    "id": 558,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "One-variable data: Distributions and measures of center and spread",
    "question": "The mean amount of time that the 20 employees of a construction company haveworked for the company is 6.7 years. After one of the employees leaves thecompany, the mean amount of time that the remaining employees have worked forthe company is reduced to 6.25 years. How many years did the employee who leftthe company work for the company?",
    "answer": "15.25",
    "explanation": "Choice D is correct. The mean amount of time that the 20 employees worked for the company is 6.7 years. This means thatthe total number of years all 20 employees worked for the company is (6.7)(20) = 134 years. After the employee left, themean amount of time that the remaining 19 employees worked for the company is 6.25 years. Therefore, the total number ofyears all 19 employees worked for the company is (6.25)(19) = 118.75 years. It follows that the number of years that theemployee who left had worked for the company is 134 – 118.75 = 15.25 years."
  },
  {
    "id": 559,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "A certain town has an area of 4.36 square miles. What is the area, in square yards, of this town? (1 mile = 1,760 yards)",
    "answer": "13505536",
    "explanation": "Since the number of yards in 1 mile is 1,760, the number of square yards in 1 square mile is (1,760)(1,760) = 3,087,600. Therefore, if the area of the town is 4,36 square miles, it is 4.36(3,097,600) = 13,505,536, in square yards."
  },
  {
    "id": 560,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "The result of increasing the quantity x by 400% is 60. What is the value of x?",
    "answer": "12",
    "explanation": "It's given that the result of increasing the quantity x by 400% is  60. This can be written as x + (400/100)x = 60, which is equivalent to x + 4x = 60, or 5x = 60. Dividing each side of this equation by 5 yields x = 12. Therefore, the value of x is 12."
  },
  {
    "id": 561,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "The population of Greenville increased by 7% from 2015 to 2016. If the 2016 population is k times the 2015 population,what is the value of k?",
    "answer": "1.07",
    "explanation": "Let x be the 2015 population of Greenville. It's given that the population increased by 7% from 2015 to2016. The increase in population can be written as (0.07)x. The 2016 population of Greenville is given as the sum of the2015 population of Greenville and the increase in population from 2015 to 2016. This can be rewritten as x + (0.07)x, or 1.07x. Therefore, the value of k is 1.07."
  },
  {
    "id": 562,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "The population density of Cedar County is 230 people per square mile. The county has a population of 85,100 people. Whatis the area, in square miles, of Cedar County?",
    "answer": "370",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the population density of Cedar County is 230 people per square mile and thecounty has a population of 85,100 people. Based on the population density, it follows that the area of Cedar County is (85,100 people)(1 square mile / 230 people), or 370 square miles."
  },
  {
    "id": 563,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "In a group, 40% of the items are red. Of all the red items in the group, 30% also have stripes. What percentage of the items inthe group are red with stripes?",
    "answer": "0.12",
    "explanation": "It follows that the number of red items in the groupcan be represented by 0.4x, where x represents the total number of items in the group. It’s also given that of all the reditems in the group, 30% also have stripes. It follows that the number of items in the group that are red and have stripes canbe represented by 0.3(0.4x), or 0.12x. The expression0.12x represents 12% of x. Since x represents the total numberof items in the group, it follows that 12% of the items in the group are red and have stripes."
  },
  {
    "id": 564,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "A distance of 112 furlongs is equivalent to how many feet? (1 furlong = 220 yard and 1 yard = 3 feet)",
    "answer": "73920",
    "explanation": "It follows that a distance of 112 furlongs is equivalent to (112 furlongs) (220 yard/ 1 furlong) ( 3 feet / 1 yard), or 73920 feet."
  },
  {
    "id": 565,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "A number n is increased 6%. If the result is 318, what is the value of n?",
    "answer": "300",
    "explanation": "The decimal equivalent of 6% is 0.06. Since increasing the number n by 6% yields the number 318, thissituation can be represented by the equation n( 1 + 0.06) = 318, or n(1,06) = 318. Dividing both sides of this equation by1.06 yields n = 300."
  },
  {
    "id": 566,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "One-variable data: Distributions and measures of center and spread",
    "question": "The weights, in pounds, for 15 horses in a stable were reported, and the mean,median, range, and standard deviation for the data were found. The horse with thelowest reported weight was found to actually weigh 10 pounds less than itsreported weight. What value remains unchanged if the four values are reportedusing the corrected weight?",
    "answer": "Median",
    "explanation": "The median weight is found by ordering the horses’ weights from least to greatest and then determiningthe middle value from this list of weights. Decreasing the value for the horse with the lowest weight doesn’t affect themedian since it’s still the lowest value."
  },
  {
    "id": 567,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "For the values j and k, the ratio of j to k is 11 to 12. If j is multiplied by 17, what is k multiplied by in order to maintain thesame ratio?",
    "answer": "17",
    "explanation": "If one value is multiplied by a number, then the other value must be multiplied by the same numberin order to maintain the same ratio. It’s given that j is multiplied by 17. Therefore, in order to maintain the same ratio, k must also be multiplied by 17."
  },
  {
    "id": 568,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Probability and conditional probability",
    "question": "At a conference, there are a total of 275\nattendees. Each attendee is assigned to either group A, group B, or group C. If oneof these attendees is selected at random, the probability of selecting an attendee who is assigned to group A is 0.44 and theprobability of selecting an attendee who is assigned to group B is 0.24. How many attendees are assigned to group C?",
    "answer": "88",
    "explanation": "It follows that there are 0.44(275), or 121, attendees who are assigned to group A and 0.24(275, or 66, attendees who areassigned to group B. The number of attendees who are assigned to group C is the number of attendees who are notassigned to group A or group B. In other words, the number of attendees who are assigned to group C is the total number ofattendees minus the number of attendees who are assigned to group A and group B. Therefore, the number of attendeeswho are assigned to group C is 275 - 121 - 66, or 88."
  },
  {
    "id": 569,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "A customer’s monthly water bill was $75.74. Due to a rate increase, her monthly billis now $79.86. To the nearest tenth of a percent, by what percent did the amount ofthe customer’s water bill increase?",
    "answer": "0.054",
    "explanation": "To fi nd the percent increase of the customer’s water bill, the absolute increase of the bill, in dollars, isdivided by the original amount of the bill, and the result is multiplied by 100%, as follows: (79.86 - 75.74) / 75.74 = 0.54;0.054 * 100% = 5.4."
  },
  {
    "id": 570,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Probability and conditional probability",
    "question": "If 1,200 customers register for new accounts at a social media website every day,what fraction of the fi rst 60,000 new accounts are registered in the fi rst 5 days?",
    "answer": "2025-01-10 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "If 1,200 customers register for new accounts every day, then (1,200)(5) = 6,000 customers registered fornew accounts in the first 5 days. Therefore, of the first 60,000 new accounts that were registered, 6,000 / 60,000, or 1/10, were registered in the firrst 5 days."
  },
  {
    "id": 571,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "How many tablespoons are equivalent to 14 teaspoons? ( 3 teaspoons = 1 tablespoon)",
    "answer": "14/3",
    "explanation": "teaspoons is equivalent to (14 teaspoons) ( 1 tablespoons / 3 teaspoons), or 14/ 3 tablespoons. Note that 14/3, 4.666, and 4.667 are examples of ways to enter acorrect answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 572,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "The amount of Hanna's bill for a food order was $50. Hanna gave a tip of 20% of the amount of the bill. What is the amount,in dollars, of the tip Hanna gave?",
    "answer": "10",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the amount of Hanna's food order was $50 and that Hanna gave a tip of 20% of theamount of the bill. 20% of 50 can be calculated as (20/100)(50), which yields 1000/10, or 10. Therefore, the amount, in dollars, ofthe tip Hanna gave is 10"
  },
  {
    "id": 573,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "A triathlon is a multisport race consisting of three different legs. A triathlon participant completed the cycling leg with anaverage speed of 19.700 miles per hour. What was the average speed, in  yards per hour, of the participant during the cyclingleg?",
    "answer": "34672",
    "explanation": "It follows that an average speed of 19.700 miles perhour is equivalent to (19.700 miles / 1 hour)(1,760 yard / 1 miles), or 34,672 yards per hour."
  },
  {
    "id": 574,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "The total area of a coastal city is 92.1 square miles, of which 11.3 square miles iswater. If the city had a population of 621,000 people in the year 2010, which of thefollowing is closest to the population density, in people per square mile of landarea, of the city at that time?",
    "answer": "7690",
    "explanation": "The land area of the coastal city can be found by subtracting the area of the water from the total area ofthe coastal city; that is, 92.1 - 11.3 = 80.8 square miles. The population density is the population divided by the land area,or 621,000 / 80.8 = 7,686, which is closest to 7,690 people per square mile."
  },
  {
    "id": 575,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "d = 55t\nThe equation above can be used to calculate the distance d, in miles, traveled by acar moving at a speed of 55 miles per hour over a period of t hours. For anypositive constant k, the distance the car would have traveled after 9k hours is howmany times the distance the car would have traveled after 3k hours?",
    "answer": "3",
    "explanation": "Since the distance is equal to the amount of time multiplied by a constant, the given equation d = 55t represents a proportional relationship between distance and time in this situation. Since 9l = 3 * 3k, the time when t = 9l hours is 3 times the time when t = 3k hours. Therefore, the distance traveled after 9k hours is 3 times the distance after 3k hours."
  },
  {
    "id": 576,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "One side of a fl at board has an area of 874 square inches. If a pressure of 19 pounds per square inch of area is exerted onthis side of the board, what is the total force, in pounds, exerted on this side of the board?",
    "answer": "16606",
    "explanation": "It's given that one side of a fl at board has an area of 874 square inches. If a pressure of 19 pounds per square inch of area is exerted on this side of the board, the total force exerted on this side of the board is (874 square inches) ( 19 pounds / 1 square inch), or 16,606 pounds."
  },
  {
    "id": 577,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "432 is 96% of what number?",
    "answer": "450",
    "explanation": "Let x represent the number that 432 is 96% of. This can be written as (96 / 100)x, or 0.96x = 432. Dividing both sides of this equation by 0.96 yields x = 450. Therefore, 432 is 96% of 450."
  },
  {
    "id": 578,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "One-variable data: Distributions and measures of center and spread",
    "question": "A fi sh hatchery has three tanks for holding fi sh before they are introduced into thewild. Ten fi sh weighing less than 5 ounces are placed in tank A. Eleven fi shweighing at least 5 ounces but no more than 13 ounces are placed in tank B.Twelve fi sh weighing more than 13 ounces are placed in tank C. Which of thefollowing could be the median of the weights, in ounces, of these 33 fi sh?",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "The median of a set of numbers is the middle number when the values in the set are ordered from leastto greatest. There are 33 fi sh, so in an ordered list of the weights, the 17th value would be the median weight. The 10 fi sh intank A weigh the least, and these 10 weights would be the fi rst 10 values on the ordered list. The 11 fi sh in tank B have thenext set of higher weights, and so would be the 11th through 21st weights in the ordered list, which includes the medianweight as the 17th value. The fi sh in tank B weigh at least 5 ounces but no more than 13 ounces; of the given choices, only 8ounces falls within this range of values."
  },
  {
    "id": 579,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "What number is 40% greater than 115?",
    "answer": "161",
    "explanation": "For a number to be 40% greater than 115, it follows that the number is ( 100 % of 115) + (40 % of 115), which can be written as 100/100(115) + 40/100 (115). This expression is equivalent to 1(115) + 0.4(115), or 1.4(115), which is equal to 161. Therefore, 161 is 40% greater than 115. "
  },
  {
    "id": 580,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "13 is p% of 25. What is the value of p?",
    "answer": "25",
    "explanation": "It's given that 13 is p% of 25. It follows that 18/25 = p/100. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 100 gives 52 = p. Therefore, the value of pis 52."
  },
  {
    "id": 581,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "One-variable data: Distributions and measures of center and spread",
    "question": "2, 10, 3, 7, 6\nThe mean of the list of numbers above is what fraction ofthe sum of the five numbers?",
    "answer": "2025-01-05 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "The mean of the list of numbers is found by dividing the sum of the numbers by the number ofvalues in the list. Since there are 5 numbers in the list, the mean is 1/5 of the sum of the numbers. Note that 1/5 and .2 areexamples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 582,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "An insect moves at a speed of 3/20 feet per second. What is this speed, in yards per second? (3 feet = 1 yard)",
    "answer": "2025-01-20 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "It follows that a speed of 3/20 feet per second is equivalent to (3/20) (1/3) or 1/20 yards per second."
  },
  {
    "id": 583,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Inference from sample statistics and margin of error",
    "question": "To estimate the proportion of a population that has a certain characteristic, a random sample was selected from thepopulation. Based on the sample, it is estimated that the proportion of the population that has the characteristic is 0.49, withan associated margin of error of 0.04. Based on this estimate and margin of error, which of the following is the mostappropriate conclusion about the proportion of the population that has the characteristic?",
    "answer": "It is plausible that the proportion is between 0.45 and 0.53",
    "explanation": "Subtracting the margin of error from the estimate and adding the margin of error to theestimate gives an interval of plausible values for the true proportion of the population that has the characteristic. Therefore,it’s plausible that the proportion of the population that has this characteristic is between 0.45b and 0.53."
  },
  {
    "id": 584,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "Thomas installed a new stove in his restaurant. At the time of installation, the stovehad a value of $800. Thomas estimates that each year the value of the stove willdepreciate by 20% of the previous year’s estimated value. What is the estimatedvalue of the stove exactly 2 years after Thomas installed it?",
    "answer": "512",
    "explanation": "Choice B is correct. If the stove’s value depreciates by 20% of the previous year’s estimated value, then each year it retains100% – 20% = 80%, or 0.80, of the previous year’s estimated value. Since the stove’s value was $800 when Thomas installedit, the estimated value after two years would be (0.80)(0.80)($800) = $512."
  },
  {
    "id": 585,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "The number of coins in a collection increased from 9 to 90. What was the percent increase in the number of coins in this collection?",
    "answer": "9",
    "explanation": "It follows that the number ofcoins in the collection increased by 90 - 9, or 81. Let x% represent the percentage that 81 is of 9. The value of x can befound using the proportion 81 / 9 = x / 100, or 9 = x/100. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 100 yields 900 = x. Thus,when the number of coins in the collection increased from 9 to 90, the percent increase was 900%."
  },
  {
    "id": 586,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "To study fluctuations in composition, samples of pumice were taken from 29\nlocations and cut in the shape of a cube. Thelength of the edge of one of these cubes is 3.000\ncentimeters. This cube has a density of 0.230\ngrams per cubic centimeter.What is the mass of this cube, in grams?",
    "answer": "6.21",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the samples of pumice were cut in the shape of a cube. It's also given that thelength of the edge of one of these cubes is 3.000 centimeters. Therefore, the volume of this cube is (3.000 cm)^3,or 27 cubic centimeters. Since the density of this cube is 0.230 grams per cubic centimeter, it follows that the mass of thiscube is 6.21 grams."
  },
  {
    "id": 587,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "The number a is 70% less than the positive number b. The number c is 60% greater than a. The number c is how many times b?",
    "answer": "0.48",
    "explanation": "It's given that the number a is 70% less than the positive number b. Therefore, a = ( 1 - 70/100)b,which is equivalent to a = (1 - 0.70)b, or a = 0.30b. It's also given that the number c is 60% greater than a. Therefore, c = (1 + 60/100)a,, which is equivalent to c = 1(1 + 0.60)a, or c = 1.60a. Since a = 3.60b, substituting 0.30b for a in theequation c = 1.60a yields c = 1.60(0.30b), or c = 0.48b. Thus, c is 0.48times b."
  },
  {
    "id": 588,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Evaluating statistical claims: Observational studies and experiments",
    "question": "Near the end of a US cable news show, the host invited viewers to respond to a pollon the show’s website that asked, “Do you support the new federal policydiscussed during the show?” At the end of the show, the host reported that 28%responded “Yes,” and 70% responded “No.” Which of the following best explainswhy the results are unlikely to represent the sentiments of the population of theUnited States?",
    "answer": "Those who responded to the poll were not a random sample of the population of the United States.",
    "explanation": "In order for the poll results from a sample of a population to represent the entire population, the samplemust be representative of the population. A sample that is randomly selected from a population is more likely than a sampleof the type described to represent the population. In this case, the people who responded were people with access to cabletelevision and websites, which aren’t accessible to the entire population. Moreover, the people who responded also chose towatch the show and respond to the poll. The people who made these choices aren’t representative of the entire population ofthe United States because they were not a random sample of the population of the United States."
  },
  {
    "id": 589,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "Objects R and S each travel at a constant speed. The speed of object R is half the speed of object S. Object R travels a distance of 4x inches in y seconds. Which expression represents the time, in seconds, it takes object S to travel a distance of 24x inches?",
    "answer": "3y",
    "explanation": "Let n represent the time, in seconds, it takes object S to travel a distance of 24x inches. The value of n can be found by solving the equation 8x inches / y second = 24x inches / n seconds, which can be written as 8x / y = 24x / n. Multiplying each side of this equation by ny yields 8xn = 24xy. Dividing each side of this equation by 8xyields n = 3y"
  },
  {
    "id": 590,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "One-variable data: Distributions and measures of center and spread",
    "question": "Data set A consists of the heights of 75 objects and has a mean of 25 meters. Data set B consists of the heights of 50 objects and has a mean of 65 meters. Data set C consists of the heights of the 125 objects from data sets A and B. What is the mean, in meters, of data set C?",
    "answer": "41",
    "explanation": "The mean of a data set is computed by dividing the sum of the values in the data set by thenumber of values in the data set. It’s given that data set A consists of the heights of 75 objects and has a mean of 25 meters. This can be represented by the equation x/75 =25, where x represents the sum of the heights of the objects, inmeters, in data set A. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 75 yields x = 75(25), or x = 1,875 meters. Therefore, thesum of the heights of the objects in data set A is 1,875 meters. It’s also given that data set B consists of the heights of 50 objects and has a mean of 65 meters. This can be represented by the equation y / 50 = 65, where y represents the sum of theheights of the objects, in meters, in data set B. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 50 yields y = 50(65), or y = 3,250 meters. Therefore, the sum of the heights of the objects in data set B is 3,250 meters. Since it’s given that dataset C consists of the heights of the 125 objects from data sets A and B, it follows that the mean of data set C is the sum ofthe heights of the objects, in meters, in data sets A and B divided by the number of objects represented in data sets A and B,or (1,875 + 3,250) / 125, which is equivalent to 41 meters"
  },
  {
    "id": 591,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "One-variable data: Distributions and measures of center and spread",
    "question": "Data set F consists of 55 integers between 170 and 290. Data set G consists of all the integers in data set F as well as the integer 10. Which of the following must be less for data set F than for data set G?\nThe mean\nThe median",
    "answer": "Neither I nor II",
    "explanation": "It's given that data set F consists of 55 integers between 170 and 290 and data set G consists of all theintegers in data set F as well as the integer 10. Since the integer 10 is less than all the integers in data set F, the mean ofdata set G must be less than the mean of data set F. Thus, the mean of data set F isn't less than the mean of data set G.When a data set is in ascending order, the median is between the two middle values when there is an even number of valuesand the median is the middle value when there is an odd number of values. It follows that the median of data set F is eithergreater than or equal to the median of data set G. Therefore, the median of data set F isn't less than the median of data setG. Thus, neither the mean nor the median must be less for data set F than for data set G."
  },
  {
    "id": 592,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "One-variable data: Distributions and measures of center and spread",
    "question": "Data set A consists of the heights of 75 buildings and has a mean of 32 meters. Data set B consists of the heights of 50 buildings and has a mean of 62 meters. Data set C consists of the heights of the 125 buildings from data sets A and B. Whatis the mean, in meters, of data set C?",
    "answer": "44",
    "explanation": "The mean of a data set is computed by dividing the sum of the values in the data set by thenumber of values in the data set. It's given that data set A consists of the heights of 75 buildings and has a mean of 32 meters. This can be represented by the equation x / 75 = 32, where x represents the sum of the heights of the buildings, inmeters, in data set A. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 75 yields x = 75(32), or x = 2,400 meters. Therefore, thesum of the heights of the buildings in data set A is 2,400 meters. It's also given that data set B consists of the heights of 50 buildings and has a mean of 62 meters. This can be represented by the equation y / 50 = 62, where y represents the sum ofthe heights of the buildings, in meters, in data set B. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 50 yields y = 50(62), or y = 3,100 meters. Therefore, the sum of the heights of the buildings in data set B is 3,100 meters. Since it's given that dataset C consists of the heights of the 125 buildings from data sets A and B, it follows that the mean of data set C is the sum ofthe heights of the buildings, in meters, in data sets A and B divided by the number of buildings represented in data sets A and B, or (2,400 + 3100) / 125, which is equivalent to 44 meters."
  },
  {
    "id": 593,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "After 20% of the original number of marbles in a group were removed from the group, 360 marbles remained in the group.How many marbles were removed from the group?",
    "answer": "90",
    "explanation": "Let x represent theoriginal number of marbles in the group. It follows that 20x / 100, or 0.20x, marbles were removed from the group. Therefore, x - 0.20x marbles remained in the group. It's also given that 360 marbles remained in the group. Thus, x - 0.20x = 360,or 0.80x = 360. Dividing both sides of this equation by 0.80 yields 450. Substituting 450 for x in the expression 0.20x yields 0.20(450), or 90"
  },
  {
    "id": 594,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "The number a is 110% greater than the number b. The number b is 90% less than 47. What is the value of a?",
    "answer": "9.87",
    "explanation": "Substituting 4.7 for b in the equation a = 2.1b yields a = 2.1(4.7), which is equivalent to a =9.87\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 595,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "140 is p% greater than 10. What is the value of p?",
    "answer": "1300",
    "explanation": "It's given that 140 is p% greater than 10. It follows that 140 = 10 + (p / 100) 10, which is equivalent to 140 = 10 + (10p / 100), or 140 = 10 + 0.1p. Subtracting 10 from each side of this equation yields 130 = 0.1p. Dividing eachside of this equation by 0.1 yields 1,300 = p, or p = 1,300."
  },
  {
    "id": 596,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "For an electric field passing through a flat surface perpendicular to it, the electric flux of the electric field through the surfaceis the product of the electric fi eld’s strength and the area of the surface. A certain flat surface consists of two adjacentsquares, where the side length, in meters, of the larger square is 3 times the side length, in meters, of the smaller square. Anelectric fi eld with strength 29.00 volts per meter passes uniformly through this surface, which is perpendicular to the electricfield. If the total electric flux of the electric field through this surface is 4,600 volts * meters, what is the electric flux, in volts * meters, of the electric field through the larger square?",
    "answer": "4176",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the side length of the larger square is 3 times the side length of the smallersquare. This means that the area of the larger square is 3^2, or 9, times the area of the smaller square. If the area of thesmaller square is represented by x, then the area of the larger square can be represented by 9x. Therefore, the fl at surfaceof the two adjacent squares has a total area of x + 9x, or 10x. It’s given that an electric fi eld with strength 29.00 volts permeter passes uniformly through this surface and the total electric fl ux of the electric fi eld through this surface is 4,600 volts * meters. Since it's given that the electric fl ux is the product of the electric fi eld’s strength and the area of thesurface, the equation 29(10x)  = 4,640, or 290x = 4,640, can be used to represent this situation. Dividing each side ofthis equation by 280 yields x =16. Substituting 16 for x in the expression for the area of the larger square, 9x, yields 9(16), or 144, square meters. Since the area of the larger square is 144\nsquare meters, the electric flux, in 4,600 volts * meters, of theelectric fi eld through the larger square can be determined by multiplying the area of the larger square by the strength of theelectric fi eld. Thus, the electric flux is (144)(29) = 4,176 4,600 volts * meters\n\n."
  },
  {
    "id": 597,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "The number w is 110% greater than the number z. The number z is 55% less than 50. What is the value of w?",
    "answer": "47.25",
    "explanation": "It follows that w = ( 1 + 110/100)z, or w 2.1z. It’s also given that the number z is 55% less than 50. It follows that z = ( 1 - 55/100)(50),or z = 0.46(50), which yields z = 22.5. Substituting 22.5 for z in the equation w = 2.1z yields w = 2.1(22.5), which is equivalent to w = 47.25\n\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 598,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Inference from sample statistics and margin of error",
    "question": "In State X, Mr. Camp’s eighth-grade class consisting of 26 students was surveyedand 34.6 percent of the students reported that they had at least two siblings. Theaverage eighth‑grade class size in the state is 26. If the students in Mr. Camp’sclass are representative of students in the state’s eighth-grade classes and thereare 1,800 eighth-grade classes in the state, which of the following best estimatesthe number of eighth‑grade students in the state who have fewer than twosiblings?",
    "answer": "30600",
    "explanation": "It is given that 34.6% of 26 students in Mr. Camp’s class reported that they had at least two siblings.Since 34.6% of 26 is 8.996, there must have been 9 students in the class who reported having at least two siblings and 17students who reported that they had fewer than two siblings. It is also given that the average eighth-grade class size in thestate is 26 and that Mr. Camp’s class is representative of all eighth-grade classes in the state. This means that in eacheighth-grade class in the state there are about 17 students who have fewer than two siblings. Therefore, the best estimate ofthe number of eighth-grade students in the state who have fewer than two siblings is 17 × (number of eighth-grade classes inthe state), or 17 * 1,800 = 30,600 \n."
  },
  {
    "id": 599,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "The number of zebras in a population in 2018 was 1.27 times the number of zebras in this population in 2014. If the numberof zebras in this population in 2014 is p% of the number of zebras in this population in 2018, what is the value of p, to thenearest whole number?",
    "answer": "79",
    "explanation": "Let x represent the number of zebras in the population in 2014 and let y represent the number ofzebras in the population in 2018. It’s given that the number of zebras in this population in 2018 was 1.27 times the numberof zebras in this population in 2014. It follows that the equation y = 1.27x represents this situation. Dividing both sides ofthis equation by 1.27 yields (1y/1.27) = x. Therefore, the number of zebras in this population in2014 is 1 / 1.27 times the number of zebras in this population in 2018. If the number of zebras in this population in x = p / 100 y is 1/1.27 = p/100 of thenumber of zebras in this population in 2018, then x = py / 100. It follows that 100/1.27 = p, which means p  is approximately equal to 78.74. Therefore, the value of p, to the nearest whole number, is 79."
  },
  {
    "id": 600,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "A gift shop buys souvenirs at a wholesale price of 7.00 dollars each and resells them each at a retail price that is 290% of the wholesale price. At the end of the season, any remaining souvenirs are marked at a discounted price that is 80% off the retail price. What is the discounted price of each remaining souvenir, in dollars?",
    "answer": "203/50",
    "explanation": "It's given that the retail price is 290% of the wholesale price of $7.00. Thus, the retail price is %7.00(290/100), or $20.30. It's also given that the discounted price is 80% off the retail price. Thus, the discounted price is  $20.30(0.20), or 203/50."
  },
  {
    "id": 601,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "According to a set of standards, a certain type of substance can contain a maximum of 0.001% phosphorus by mass. If asample of this substance has a mass of 140 grams, what is the maximum mass, in grams, of phosphorus the sample cancontain to meet these standards?",
    "answer": "0.0014",
    "explanation": "It's given that a certain type of substance can contain a maximum of 0.001% phosphorus bymass to meet a set of standards. If a sample of the substance has a mass of 140 grams, it follows that the maximum mass,in grams, of phosphorus the sample can contain to meet the standards is 0.001/100(140), or 0.0014"
  },
  {
    "id": 602,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "37% of the items in a box are green. Of those,37% are also rectangular. Of the green rectangular items, 42% are alsometal. Which of the following is closest to the percentage of the items in the box that are not rectangular green metal items?",
    "answer": "0.9425",
    "explanation": "Let x represent the total number of items in the box.It follows that 0.37x, items in the box are green. It's also given that of those, 37% are also rectangular. Therefore, 37/100(0.37x), or 0.1369x, items in the box are green rectangular items. It's also given that of the green rectangular items, 42% are also metal. Therefore, 42/100(0.1369x), or 0.057498x, items in the box are rectangular green metal items. Thenumber of the items in the box that are not rectangular green metal items is the total number of items in the box minus thenumber of rectangular green metal items in the box. Therefore, the number of items in the box that are not rectangular greenmetal items is x -0.057498x, or 0.942502x. The percentage of items in the box that are not rectangular green metalitems is the percentage that 0.942502x is of x. If p% represents this percentage, the value of 94.25%"
  },
  {
    "id": 603,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "Anita created a batch of green paint by mixing 2 ounces of blue paint with 3ounces of yellow paint. She must mix a second batch using the same ratio of blueand yellow paint as the fi rst batch. If she uses 5 ounces of blue paint for thesecond batch, how much yellow paint should Anita use?",
    "answer": "1.5 times the amount of blue paint used in the second batch",
    "explanation": "It’s given that Anita used a ratio of 2 ounces of blue paint to 3 ounces of yellow paint for the fi rst batch.For any batch of paint that uses the same ratio, the amount of yellow paint used will be 3/2, or 1.5, times the amount of bluepaint used in the batch. Therefore, the amount of yellow paint Anita will use in the second batch will be 1.5 times the amountof blue paint used in the second batch."
  },
  {
    "id": 604,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "A certain park has an area of 11,863,808 square yards. What is the area, in square miles, of this park? (1 miles = 1,760 yards)",
    "answer": "3.83",
    "explanation": "Since 1 mile is 1,760 yards, 1,760^2 = 3,097,600 square yards. 11,863,808 square yards  / 3,097,600 square yards = 3.83 "
  },
  {
    "id": 605,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "The value of a collectible comic book increased by 167% from the end of 2011 to the end of 2012 and then decreased by 16% from the end of 2012 to the end of 2013. What was the net percentage increase in the value of the collectible comicbook from the end of 2011 to the end of 2013?",
    "answer": "1.2428",
    "explanation": "If the value of the comic book at the end of 2011 was x dollars, then the value, in dollars, of the comic book at the end of 2012 was x + (167/100)x, which can be rewritten as 1x = 1.67x, or 2.67x . It’s also given that the value of the comicbook decreased by 16%from the end of 2012 to the end of 2013. Therefore, the value, in dollars, of the comic book at the end of 2013 was 2.67x - (2.67x)(0.16), or 2.2428x. Thus, if the valueof the comic book at the end of 2011 was x dollars, and the value of the comic book at the end of 2013 was 2.2428x dollars, then from the end of 2011 to the end of 2013, the value of the comic book increased by 2.2428x - 1x, or 1.2428x,dollars. Therefore, the increase in the value of the comic book from the end of 2011 to the end of 2013 is equal to 1.2428 times the value of the comic book at the end of 2011. It follows that from the end of 2011 to the end of 2013, the netpercentage increase in the value of the comic book was 124.28."
  },
  {
    "id": 606,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "During a sale, the original prices of all the items in a clothing store have beenreduced by 20%. What is the sale price of a jacket with an original price of $50 ?",
    "answer": "40",
    "explanation": "Multiplying the original price, $50,by 20% gives the amount, in dollars, that the price of the jacket is reduced by: 50 * 0.20 = 10. Subtracting this value from theoriginal price results in the sale price of the jacket: $50 - $10, or $40."
  },
  {
    "id": 607,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Inference from sample statistics and margin of error",
    "question": "Scott selected 20 employees at random from all 400 employees at a company. He found that 16 of the employees in thissample are enrolled in exactly three professional development courses this year. Based on Scott’s fi ndings, which of thefollowing is the best estimate of the number of employees at the company who are enrolled in exactly three professionaldevelopment courses this year?",
    "answer": "320",
    "explanation": "Since (16/20) is equal to 0.80, or 80%, it follows that 80% of theemployees in the sample are enrolled in exactly three professional development courses this year. Therefore, the bestestimate for the percentage of employees at the company who are enrolled in exactly three professional developmentcourses this year is 80%. It’s given that there are a total of 400 employees at the company. Therefore, the best estimate ofthe number of employees at the company who are enrolled in exactly three professional development courses this year is 320."
  },
  {
    "id": 608,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Probability and conditional probability",
    "question": "For a particular machine that produces beads, 29 out of every 100 beads it produces have a defect. A bead produced by themachine will be selected at random. What is the probability of selecting a bead that has a defect?",
    "answer": "29/100",
    "explanation": "It’s given that 29 out of every 100 beads that the machine produces have a defect. It follows that if themachine produces k beads, then the number of beads that have a defect is 29k/100, for some constant k. If a bead producedby the machine will be selected at random, the probability of selecting a bead that has a defect is given by the number ofbeads with a defect,, divided by the number of beads produced by the machine, k. Therefore, the probability ofselecting a bead that has a defect is 29/100"
  },
  {
    "id": 609,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Probability and conditional probability",
    "question": "A bag contains a total of 60 marbles. A marble is to be chosen at random from thebag. If the probability that a blue marble will be chosen is 0.35, how many marblesin the bag are blue?",
    "answer": "21",
    "explanation": "Multiplying the number of marbles in the bag by the probability of selecting a blue marble gives thenumber of blue marbles in the bag. Since the bag contains a total of 60 marbles and the probability that a blue marble will beselected from the bag is 0.35, there are a total of (0.35)(60) = 21 blue marbles in the bag."
  },
  {
    "id": 610,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Probability and conditional probability",
    "question": "On a street with 7 houses, 2 houses are blue. If a house from this street is selected at random, what is the probability ofselecting a house that is blue?",
    "answer": "2025-02-07 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "If a house from the street is selected at random, the probability of selecting a house that is blue is equalto the number of houses on the street that are blue divided by the total number of houses on the street. Since there are 2  blue houses on a street with 7 total houses, the probability of selecting a house that is blue from this street is 2/7."
  },
  {
    "id": 611,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Inference from sample statistics and margin of error",
    "question": "In a study, the data from a random sample of a population had a mean of 37, withan associated margin of error of 3. Which of the following is the most appropriate conclusion that can be made about the population mean?",
    "answer": "It is between 34 and 40.",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the mean of the data from a random sample of a population is 37, with an associatedmargin of error of 3. The most appropriate conclusion that can be made is that the mean of the entire population will fallbetween 37, plus or minus 3. Therefore, the population mean is between 37 - 3 = 34 and 37 + 3 = 40."
  },
  {
    "id": 612,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "What is 10% of 370?",
    "answer": "37",
    "explanation": "10% of 370 can be represented as 10 * 370 / 100, which is equivalent to 0.10(370), or 37"
  },
  {
    "id": 613,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Probability and conditional probability",
    "question": "-13,4,23\nA data set of three numbers is shown. If a number from this data set is selected at random, what is the probability ofselecting a negative number?",
    "answer": "2025-01-03 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "If a number from the data set is selected at random, the probability of selecting a negative number is thecount of negative numbers in the data set divided by the total count of numbers in the data set. It's given that a data set ofthree numbers is shown. It follows that the total count of numbers in the data set is 3. In the data set shown, -13 is the onlynegative number. It follows that the count of negative numbers in the data set is 1. Therefore, if a number from the data setis selected at random, the probability of selecting a negative number is 1/3."
  },
  {
    "id": 614,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Probability and conditional probability",
    "question": "There are 20 buttons in a bag: 8 white buttons, 2 orange buttons, and 10 brown buttons. If one of these buttons is selectedat random, what is the probability of selecting a white button?",
    "answer": "2025-08-20 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "It’s given that there are 20 buttons in a bag and 8 of the buttons are white. If one button from the bag isselected at random, the probability of selecting a white button is the number of white buttons in the bag divided by the totalnumber of buttons in the bag. Therefore, if one button from the bag is selected at random, the probability of selecting a whitebutton is 8/20."
  },
  {
    "id": 615,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "Rita’s total bill at a restaurant was $25.00, including tax. If she left a tip of 20% ofthe total bill, what was the amount of the tip?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "The total bill was $25.00. The percentage 20% is equivalent to the decimal 0.2. The tip is the product ofthe percentage and the total bill; therefore, 0.2 * 25 = 5\n, so the tip was $5.00."
  },
  {
    "id": 616,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "If t = 4u, which of the following is equivalent 2t?",
    "answer": "8u",
    "explanation": "It’s given that t = 4u. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 2 yields 2t = 2(4u), or 2t = 8u."
  },
  {
    "id": 617,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "What number is 20%greater than 60 ?",
    "answer": "72",
    "explanation": "The number that is 20% greater than 60 is also 120% of 60. Thedecimal equivalent of 120% is 1.2, and 1.2(60) = 72\n."
  },
  {
    "id": 618,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "Out of 300 seeds that were planted, 80% sprouted. How many of these seeds sprouted?",
    "answer": "240",
    "explanation": "It’s given that 80% of the 300 seeds sprouted. Therefore, the number of seeds that sprouted canbe calculated by multiplying the number of seeds that were planted by 80/100, which gives 300 * 80 / 100, or 240."
  },
  {
    "id": 619,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "How many yards are equivalent to 1,116 inches? ( 1 yard = 36 inches)",
    "answer": "31",
    "explanation": "It's given that 1 yard is equal to 36 inches. Therefore, 1,116 inches is equivalent to (1,116 inches) (1 yard / 36 inches), or 31 yards."
  },
  {
    "id": 620,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "How many teaspoons are equivalent to 44 tablespoons? ( 3 teaspoons = 1 tablespoon)",
    "answer": "132",
    "explanation": "It's given that 3 teaspoons is equivalent to 1 tablespoon. Therefore, 44 tablespoons is equivalent to (44tablespoons)(3 teaspoons / 1 tablespoon), or 132 teaspoons."
  },
  {
    "id": 621,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "The ratio x to y is equivalent to the ratio 12 to t. When x = 156, what is the value of y in terms of t?",
    "answer": "13t",
    "explanation": "It's given that the ratio x to y is equivalent to the ratio 12 to t. This can be represented by  x / y = 12 / t.Substituting 156 for x in this equation yields 156 / y = 12 / t. This can be rewritten as 12y = 156t. Dividing both sides of this equation by 12 yields y = 13t"
  },
  {
    "id": 622,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Ratios, rates, proportional relationships, and units",
    "question": "How many meters are equivalent to 2,300 centimeters? ( 100 centimeters = 1 meter)",
    "answer": "23",
    "explanation": "It's given that 100 centimeters is equal to 1 meter. Therefore, 2,300 centimeters is equivalent to (2,300 centimeters) ( 1 meters / 100 centimeters), or 23 meters."
  },
  {
    "id": 623,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "There are 320 marbles in a container. Of these marbles, 10% are red. How many marbles in the container are red?",
    "answer": "32",
    "explanation": "It's given that 10% of the 320 marbles in a container are red. Therefore, the number of red marbles canbe calculated by multiplying the number of marbles in the container by 10/100, which gives 320 (10 / 100), or 32."
  },
  {
    "id": 624,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Probability and conditional probability",
    "question": "If 1,200 customers register for new accounts at a social media website every day,what fraction of the first 60,000 new accounts are registered in the fi rst 5 days?",
    "answer": "2025-01-10 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "If 1,200 customers register for new accounts every day, then (1,200)(5) = 6,000 customers registered for new accounts in the first 5 days. Therefore, of the first 60,000 new accounts that were registered, 6,000 / 60,000, or 1 /10, werer egistered in the first 5 days."
  },
  {
    "id": 625,
    "domain": "Problem Solving and Data Analysis",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Percentages",
    "question": "The amount of Hanna's bill for a food order was $50. Hanna gave a tip of 20% of the amount of the bill. What is the amount,in dollars, of the tip Hanna gave?",
    "answer": "10",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the amount of Hanna's food order was $50 and that Hanna gave a tip of 20% of the amount of the bill. 20% of 50 can be calculated as ( 20 / 100) (50), which yields 1000 / 100, or 10."
  },
  {
    "id": 626,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "A rectangle has a length that is 15 times its width. The function y = (15w)(w) represents this situation, where y is the area, in square feet, of the rectangle and y > 0. Which of the following is the best interpretation of 15w in this context?\n",
    "answer": "The length of the rectangle, in feet",
    "explanation": "It's given that a rectangle has a length that is 15 times its width. It's also given that the function y = (15w)(w) represents this situation, where y is the area, in square feet, of the rectangle and y > 0. The area of a rectangle can be calculated by multiplying the rectangle's length by its width. Since the rectangle has a length that is 15 times its width, it follows that w represents the width of the rectangle, in feet, and 15w represents the length of the rectangle, in feet. Therefore, the best interpretation of 15w in this context is that it's the length of the rectangle, in feet."
  },
  {
    "id": 627,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "p(x) + 57 = x^2\nThe given equation relates the value of x and its corresponding value of p(x) for the function p. What is the minimum value of the function p?",
    "answer": "-57",
    "explanation": "For a quadratic function defined by an equation of the form p(x) = a(x - h)^2 + k, where a, h, and k are constants and a > 0, the minimum value of the function is k. Subtracting 57 from both sides of the given equation yields p(x) = x^2 - 57. This function is in the form p(x) = a(x - h)^2 + k, wherea = 1, h = 0, and k = -57. Therefore, the minimum value of the function p is -57."
  },
  {
    "id": 628,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "A company has a newsletter. In January 2018, there were 1300 customers subscribed to the newsletter. For the next 24 months after January 2018, the total number of customers subscribed to the newsletter each month was 7% greater than the total number subscribed the previous month. Which equation gives the total number of customers, c, subscribed to the company's newsletter m months after January 2018, where m <= 24?",
    "answer": "c = 1300(1 + 7 / 100)^m, or c = 1300(1.07)^m",
    "explanation": "It's given that in January 2018, there were 1300 customers subscribed to a company's newsletter and for the next 24 months after January 2018, the total number of customers subscribed to the newsletter each month was 7% greater than the total number subscribed the previous month. It follows that this situation can be represented by the equation c = a(1 + r / 100)^m, where c is the total number of customers subscribed to the company's newsletter m months after January 2018, a is the number of customers subscribed to the newsletter in January 2018, and the total number of customers subscribed to the newsletter each month was r%  greater than the total number subscribed the previous month. Substituting 1300 for a and 7 for r in this equation yields c = 1300(1 + 7 / 100)^m, or c = 1300(1.07)^m."
  },
  {
    "id": 629,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "A rectangular volleyball court has an area of 162 square meters. If the length of the court is twice the width, what is the width of the court, in meters?",
    "answer": "9",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the volleyball court is rectangular and has an area of 162 square meters. The formula for the area of a rectangle is A = l * w, where A is the area, l is the length, and w is the width of the rectangle. It’s also given that the length of the volleyball court is twice the width, thus l = 2w. Substituting the given value into the formula for the area of a rectangle and using the relationship between length and width for this rectangle yields 162 = (2w)(w). This equation can be rewritten as 162 = 2w^2. Dividing both sides of this equation by 2 yields 81 = w^2. Taking the square root of both sides of this equation yields +-9 = w. Since the width of a rectangle is a positive number, the width of the volleyball court is 9 meters."
  },
  {
    "id": 630,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "S(n) = 38000a^n\nThe function S above models the annual salary, in dollars, of an employee n years after starting a job, where a is a constant. If the employee’s salary increases by 4% each year, what is the value of a?",
    "answer": "1.04",
    "explanation": "A model for a quantity S that increases by a certain percentage per time period n is an exponential function in the form S(n) = I(1 + r / 100)^n, where I is the initial value at time n = 0 for r% annual increase. It’s given that the annual increase in an employee’s salary is 4%, so r = 4. The initial value can be found by substituting 0 for n in the given function, which yields s(0) = 38000. Therefore, I = 38000. Substituting these values for r and I into the form of the exponential function S(n) = I(1 + r / 100)^n yields S(n) = 38000(1 + 4 / 100)^n, or S(n) = 38000(1.04)^n. Therefore, the value of a in the given function is 1.04."
  },
  {
    "id": 631,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "D = 5640(1.9)^t\nThe equation above estimates the global data traffic D, in terabytes, for the year that is t years after 2010.What is the best interpretation of the number 5,640 in this context?",
    "answer": "The estimated data traffic, in terabytes, in 2010",
    "explanation": "Since t represents the number of years after 2010, the estimated data traffic, in terabytes, in 2010 can be calculated using the given equation whent = 0 . Substituting 0 for t in the given equation yields D = 5640(1.9)^0, or D = 5640. Thus, 5,640 represents the estimated data traffic, in terabytes, in 2010."
  },
  {
    "id": 632,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "A rectangle has a length of x units and a width of (x - 15) units. If the rectangle has an area of 76 square units, what is the value of x?",
    "answer": "19",
    "explanation": "The area of a rectangle is equal to its length multiplied by its width. Multiplying the given length, x units, by the given width, (x - 15) units, yields x(x - 15) square units. If the rectangle has an area of 76 square units, it follows that x(x - 15) = 76, or x^2 - 15x= 76. Subtracting 76 from both sides of this equation yields x^2 - 15x - 76. Factoring the left-hand side of this equation yields (x - 19)(x + 4). Applying the zero product property to this equation yields two solutions: x = 19 and x = -4. Since x is the rectangle’s length, in units, which must be positive, the value of x is 19."
  },
  {
    "id": 633,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "A scientist initially measures 12000 bacteria in a growth medium. 4 hours later, the scientist measures 24000 bacteria. Assuming exponential growth, the formula P = C(2)^(rt) gives the number of bacteria in the growth medium, where r and C are constants and P is the number of bacteria t hours after the initial measurement. What is the value of r?",
    "answer": "2025-01-04 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the formula P = C(2)^(rt) gives the number of bacteria in a growth medium, where r and C are constants and P is the number of bacteria t hours after the initial measurement. It’s also given that a scientist initially measures 12000 bacteria in the growth medium. Since the initial measurement is 0 hours after the initial measurement, it follows that when t = 0, P = 12000. Substituting 0 for t and 12000 for P in the given equation yields 12000 = C(2)^(r * 0), or 12000 = C(2)^(0), which is equivalent to 12000 = C. It’s given that 4 hours later, the scientist measures 24000 bacteria, or when t = 4, P = 24000. Substituting 4 for t, 24000 for P, and 12000 for C in the given equation yields 24000 = 12000(2)^(4 * r). Dividing each side of this equation by 12000 yields 2 = 2^(4r), or 2^1 = 2^4r, which is equivalent to 1 = 4r. Dividing both sides of this equation by 4 yields 1/4 = r. Therefore, the value of r is 1/4."
  },
  {
    "id": 634,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "g(x) = x^2 + 55\nWhat is the minimum value of the given function?",
    "answer": "55",
    "explanation": "For a quadratic function defined by an equation of the form g(x) = a(x - h)^2 + k, where a, h, and k are constants and a > 0, the minimum value of the function is k. In the given function, a = 1, h = 0, and k = 55. Therefore, the minimum value of the given function is 55."
  },
  {
    "id": 635,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "A sample of a certain isotope takes 29 years to decay to half its original mass. The function s(t) = 184(0.5)^(t/29) gives the approximate mass of this isotope, in grams, that remains t years after a 184-gram sample starts to decay. Which statement is the best interpretation of s(87) = 23 in this context?",
    "answer": "Approximately 23 grams of the sample remains 87 years after the sample starts to decay.",
    "explanation": "In the given function, s(t) represents the approximate mass, in grams, of the sample that remains t years after the sample starts to decay. It follows that the best interpretation of s(87) = 23 is that approximately 23 grams of the sample remains 87 years after the sample starts to decay.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 636,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "f(x) = (x + 6)(x - 4)\nIf the given function f is graphed in the xy-plane, where y = f(x), what is the x-coordinate of an x-intercept of the graph?",
    "answer": "-6, 4",
    "explanation": "The x-intercepts of a graph in the xy-plane are the points where y = 0. Thus, for an x-intercept of the graph of y = f(x), 0 = f(x). Substituting 0 for f(x) in the equation f(x) = (x + 6)(x - 4) yields 0 = (x + 6)(x - 4). By the zero product property, x + 6 = 0 and x - 4 = 0. Subtracting 6 from x + 6 = 0 yields x = -6. Adding 4 from x - 4 = 0 yields x = 4. Therefore, the x-coordinates of the x-intercepts of the graph of y = f(x) are -6 and 4.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 637,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 4x^(-1). What is the value of f(21)?",
    "answer": "2025-04-21 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "It’s given that function f is defined by the equation f(x) = 4x^(-1). The value of f(21) is the value of f(x) when x = 21. Substituting 21 for x in the given equation yields f(21) = 4(21)^(-1), which is equivalent to f(21) = 4(1/21), or f(21) = 4/21."
  },
  {
    "id": 638,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "Immanuel purchased a certain rare coin on January 1. The function f(x) = 65(1.03)^x, where 0 <= x <= 10, gives the predicted value, in dollars, of the rare coin x years after Immanuel purchased it. What is the best interpretation of the statement “f(8) is approximately equal to 82” in this context?\n",
    "answer": "8 years after Immanuel purchased the rare coin, its predicted value is approximately 82 dollars.",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the function f(x) = 65(1.03)^x gives the predicted value, in dollars, of a certain rare coin x years after Immanuel purchased it. It follows that f(x) represents the predicted value, in dollars, of the coin x years after Immanuel purchased it. Since the value of f(8) is the value of f(x) when x = 8, it follows that “f(8) is approximately equal to 82” means that f(x) is approximately equal to 82 when x = 8. Therefore, the best interpretation of the statement “f(8) is approximately equal to 82” in this context is 8 years after Immanuel purchased the rare coin, its predicted value is approximately 82 dollars.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 639,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "From 2005 through 2014, the number of music CDs sold in the United States declined each year by approximately 15% of the number sold the preceding year. In 2005, approximately 600 million CDs were sold in the United States. Of the following, which best models C, the number of millions of CDs sold in the United States, t years after 2005?\n",
    "answer": "C = 600(0.85)^t",
    "explanation": "A model for a quantity C that decreases by a certain percentage per time period t is an exponential equation in the form C = I(1 - r/100)^t, where I is the initial value at time t = 0 for r% annual decline. It’s given that C is the number of millions of CDs sold in the United States and that t is the number of years after 2005. It’s also given that 600 million CDs were sold at time t = 0. Substituting 0 for t and 600 for C from the equation C = I(- t/100)^t yields 600 = I(1 - r/100)^0, or 600 = I. This number declines by 15% per year, so r = 15. Substituting 600 for I and 15 for r from the equation produces C = 600(1 - 15/100)^t, or C = 600(0.85)^t."
  },
  {
    "id": 640,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The product of two positive integers is 546. If the first integer is 11 greater than twice the second integer, what is the smaller of the two integers?",
    "answer": "14",
    "explanation": "Let x be the first integer and let y be the second integer. If the first integer is 11 greater than twice the second integer, then x = 2y + 11. If the product of the two integers is 546, then xy = 546. Substituting 2y + 11 for x in this equation results in (2y + 11)y = 546. Distributing y the to both terms in the parentheses results in 2y^2 + 11y = 546. Subtracting 546 from both sides of this equation results in 2y^2 + 11y - 546 = 0. The left-hand side of this equation can be factored by finding two values whose product is 2(-546), or -1092, and whose sum is 11. The two values whose product is -1092 and whose sum is 11 are 39 and -28. Thus, the equation 2y^2 + 11y - 546 = 0 can be rewritten as 2y^2 + 28y - 39y - 546, which is equivalent to 2y(y - 14) + 39(y - 14), or (2y + 39)(y - 14). By the zero product property, it follows that 2y + 39 = 0 and y - 14 = 0. Subtracting 39 from 2y + 39 = 0 yields 2y = -39. Dividing both sides of this equation by 2 yields y =-39/2. Since y is a positive integer, the value of y is not -39/2. Adding 14 to y - 14 = 0 yields y = 14. Substituting 14 for y in the equation xy = 546 yields x(14) = 546. Dividing both sides of this equation by 14 results in x = 39. Therefore, the two integers are 14 and 39, so the smaller of the two integers is 14."
  },
  {
    "id": 641,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "In the xy-plane, the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the graph of the function f is c. Which function value must be equal to c ?",
    "answer": "f(0)",
    "explanation": "A y-intercept is the point in the xy-plane where the graph of the function crosses the y-axis, which is where x = 0. It’s given that the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the graph of function f is c. It follows that the coordinate pair representing the y-intercept must be (0, c). Therefore, c must equal f(0)."
  },
  {
    "id": 642,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "f(t) = 500(0.5)^(t/12)\nThe function f models the intensity of an X-ray beam, in number of particles in the X-ray beam, t millimeters below the surface of a sample of iron. According to the model, what is the estimated number of particles in the X-ray beam when it is at the surface of the sample of iron?\n",
    "answer": "500",
    "explanation": "It's given that the function f models the intensity of an X-ray beam, in number of particles in the X-ray beam, t millimeters below the surface of a sample of iron. When the X-ray beam is at the surface of the sample of iron, it is 0 millimeters below the surface, so the value of t is 0. Substituting 0 for t in the function f(t) = 500(0.5)^(t/12) yields f(0) = 500(0.5)^(t/12). Since any positive number raised to the power of 0 is equal to 1, it follows that f(0) = 500(1), or f(0) = 500. Therefore, the estimated number of particles in the X-ray beam at the surface of the sample of iron is 500."
  },
  {
    "id": 643,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "y = 0.25x^2 - 7.5x + 90.25\nThe equation gives the estimated stock price y, in dollars, for a certain company x days after a new product launched, where 0 <= x <= 20. Which statement is the best interpretation of (x, y) = (1, 83) in this context?",
    "answer": "1 day after the new product launched, the company's estimated stock price is $83.",
    "explanation": "In the given equation, x represents the number of days after a new product launched, where 0 <= x <= 20, and y represents the estimated stock price, in dollars, for a certain company. Therefore, the best interpretation of (x, y) = (1, 83) in this context is that 1 day after the new product launched, the company's estimated stock price is $83.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 644,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "f(x) = x^3 + 3x^2 - 6x - 1\nFor the function f defined above, what is the value of f(-1)?\n",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "Substituting -1 for x in the given function f gives f(-1) = (-1)^3 + 3(-1)^2 - 6(-1) - 1, which simplifies to f(-1) = -1 + 3(1) - 6(-1) -1. This further simplifies to f(-1) = -1 + 3 + 6 - 1, or f(-1) = 7."
  },
  {
    "id": 645,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function f(w) = 6w^2 gives the area of a rectangle, in square feet(ft^2), if its width is w ft and its length is 6 times its width. Which of the following is the best interpretation of f(14) = 1176?",
    "answer": "If the width of the rectangle is 14 ft , then the area of the rectangle is 1176 ft^2.",
    "explanation": "The function f gives the area of the rectangle, in ft^2, if its width is w ft. Since the value of f(14) is the value of f(w) if w = 14, it follows that f(14) = 1176 means that f(w) is 1176 if w = 14. In the given context, this means that if the width of the rectangle is 14 ft, then the area of the rectangle is 1176 ft^2.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 646,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "An object’s kinetic energy, in joules, is equal to the product of one-half the object’s mass, in kilograms, and the square of the object’s speed, in meters per second. What is the speed, in meters per second, of an object with a mass of 4 kilograms and kinetic energy of 18 joules?",
    "answer": "3",
    "explanation": "It’s given that an object’s kinetic energy, in joules, is equal to the product of one-half the object’s mass, in kilograms, and the square of the object’s speed, in meters per second. This relationship can be represented by the equation K = (1/2)(m)(v)^2, where K is the kinetic energy, m is the mass, and v is the speed. Substituting a mass of 4 kilograms for m and a kinetic energy of 18 joules for K results in the equation 18 = (1/2)(4)(v)^2, or 18 = 2v^2. Dividing both sides of this equation by 2 yields 9 = v^2. Taking the square root of both sides yields v = -3 and v = 3. Since speed can’t be expressed as a negative number, the speed of the object is 3 meters per second.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 647,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The height, in feet, of an object x seconds after it is thrown straight up in the air can be modeled by the function h(x) = -16x^2 + 20x + 5. Based on the model, which of the following statements best interprets the equation h(1.4) = 1.64?",
    "answer": "The height of the object 1.4 seconds after being thrown straight up in the air is 1.64 feet.",
    "explanation": "The value 1.4 is the value of x, which represents the number of seconds after the object was thrown straight up in the air. When the function h is\nevaluated for x = 1.4, the function has a value of 1.64, which is the height, in feet, of the object.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 648,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "f(x) = -0.28(x - 27)^2 + 880\nAn engineer wanted to identify the best angle for a cooling fan in an engine in order to get the greatest airflow. The engineer discovered that the function above models the airflow f(x), in cubic feet per minute, as a function of the angle of the fan x, in degrees. According to the model, what angle, in degrees, gives the greatest airflow?",
    "answer": "27",
    "explanation": "The function f is quadratic, so it will have either a maximum or a minimum at the vertex of the graph. Since the coefficient of the quadratic term (–0.28) is negative, the vertex will be at a maximum. The equation f(x) = -0.28(x - 27) + 880 is given in vertex form, so the vertex is at  x = 27. Therefore, an angle of 27 degrees gives the greatest airflow.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 649,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function f(t) = 60000(2)^(t/410) gives the number of bacteria in a population t minutes after an initial observation. How much time, in minutes, does it take for the number of bacteria in the population to double?",
    "answer": "410",
    "explanation": "It's given that t minutes after an initial observation, the number of bacteria in a population is 60000(2)^(t/410). This expression consists of the initial number of bacteria, 60000, multiplied by the expression 2^(t/410). The time it takes for the number of bacteria to double is the increase in the value of t that causes the expression 2^(t/410) to double. Since the base of the expression 2^(t/410) is 2, the expression will double when the exponent increases by 1. Since the exponent of the expression 2^(t/410) is t/410, the exponent will increase by 1 when t increases by 410. Therefore the time, in minutes, it takes for the number of bacteria in the population to double is 410.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 650,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "A certain college had 3,000 students enrolled in 2015. The college predicts that after 2015, the number of students enrolled each year will be 2% less than the number of students enrolled the year before. What is the function that models the relationship between the number of students enrolled, f(x), and the number of years after 2015, x ?",
    "answer": "f(x) = 3000(0.98)^x",
    "explanation": "Because the change in the number of students decreases by the same percentage each year, the relationship between the number of students and the number of years can be modeled with a decreasing exponential function in the form f(x) = a(1 - r)^x, where f(x) is the number of students, a is the number of students in 2015, r is the rate of decrease each year, and x is the number of years since 2015. It’s given that 3,000 students were enrolled in 2015 and that the rate of decrease is predicted to be 2%, or 0.02. Substituting these values into the decreasing exponential function yields f(x) = 3000(1 - 0.02)^x, which is equivalent to f(x) = 3000(0.98)^x.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 651,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The number of bacteria in a liquid medium doubles every day. There are 44000 bacteria in the liquid medium at the start of an observation. Which represents the number of bacteria, y, in the liquid medium t days after the start of the observation? ",
    "answer": "y = 44000(2)^t",
    "explanation": "Since the number of bacteria doubles every day, the relationship between t and y can be represented by an exponential equation of the form y = a(b)^t, where a is the number of bacteria at the start of the observation and the number of bacteria increases by a factor of b every day. It’s given that there are  44000 bacteria at the start of the observation. Therefore, a = 44000. It’s also given that the number of bacteria doubles, or increases by a factor of 2, every day. Therefore, b = 2. Substituting 44000 for a and 2 for b in the equation y = a(b)^t yields y = 44000(2)^t."
  },
  {
    "id": 652,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "A rubber ball bounces upward one-half the height that it falls each time it hits the ground. If the ball was originally dropped from a distance of 20.0 feet above the ground, what was its maximum height above the ground, in feet, between the third and fourth time it hit the ground?",
    "answer": "2.5",
    "explanation": "After hitting the ground once, the ball bounces to 20 / 2 = 10 feet. After hitting the ground a second time, the ball bounces to 10 / 2 = 5 feet. After hitting the ground for the third time, the ball bounces to 5 / 2 = 2.5 feet."
  },
  {
    "id": 653,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "f(x) = x^2 - 18x - 360\nIf the given function f is graphed in the xy-plane, where y = f(x), what is an x-intercept of the graph?",
    "answer": "(-12, 0), (30, 0)",
    "explanation": "The x-intercepts of a graph in the xy-plane are the points where y = 0. Thus, for an x-intercept of the graph of function f, 0 = f(x). Substituting 0 for f(x) in the equation f(x) = x^2 - 18x - 360 yields 0 = x^2 - 18x - 360. Factoring the right-hand side of this equation yields 0 = (x + 12)(x - 30). By the zero product property, x + 12 = 0 and x - 30 = 0. Subtracting 12 from x + 12 = 0 yields x = -12. Adding 30 to x - 30 = 0 yields x = 30. Therefore, the x-intercepts of the graph of  y = f(x) are (-12, 0) and (30, 0)."
  },
  {
    "id": 654,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 7x^3. In the xy-plane, the graph of y = g(x) is the result of shifting the graph of y = f(x) down 2 units. Which equation defines function g?",
    "answer": "g(x) = 7x^3 - 2",
    "explanation": "If the graph of y = g(x) is the result of shifting the graph of y = f(x) down k units in the xy-plane, the function g can be defined by an equation of the form g(x) = f(x) - k. It’s given that f(x) = 7x^3 and the graph of y = g(x) is the result of shifting the graph of y = f(x) down 2 units. Substituting 7x^3 for f(x) and 2 for k in the equation g(x) = f(x) - k yields g(x) = 7x^3 - 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 655,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "According to Moore’s law, the number of transistors included on microprocessors doubles every 2 years. In 1985, a microprocessor was introduced that had 275,000 transistors. Based on this information, in which of the following years does Moore’s law estimate the number of transistors to reach 1.1 million?\n",
    "answer": "1989",
    "explanation": "Let x be the number of years after 1985. It follows that x/2 represents the number of 2-year periods that will occur within an x-year period. According to Moore’s law, every 2 years, the number of transistors included on microprocessors is estimated to double. Therefore, x years after 1985, the number of transistors will double x/2 times. Since the number of transistors included on a microprocessor was 275,000, or .275 million, in 1985, the estimated number of transistors, in millions, included x years after 1985 can be modeled as 0.275(2)^(x/2). The year in which the number of transistors is estimated to be 1.1 million is represented by the value of x when 1.1 = 0.275(2)^(x/2). Dividing both sides of this equation by .275 yields 4 = 2^(x/2), which can be rewritten as 2^2 = 2^(x/2). Since the exponential equation has equal bases on each side, it follows that the exponents must also be equal: 2 = x/2. Multiplying both sides of the equation 2 = x/2 by 2 yields x = 4. Therefore, according to Moore’s law, 4 years after 1985, or in 1989, the number of transistors included on microprocessors is estimated to reach 1.1 million.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 656,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function f is defined by f(x) = 270(0.1)^x. What is the value of f(0)?",
    "answer": "270",
    "explanation": "The value of f(0) is the value of f(x) when x = 0. Substituting 0 for x in the given function yields f(0) = 270(0.1)^0, or f(0) = 270(1), which is equivalent to f(0) = 270. Therefore, the value of f(0) is 270.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 657,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function f(x) = 206(1.034)^x models the value, in dollars, of a certain bank account by the end of each year from 1957 through 1972, where x is the number of years after 1957. Which is the best interpretation of “f(5) is approximately equal to 243” in this context?",
    "answer": "The value of the bank account is estimated to be approximately 243 dollars in 1962.",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the function f(x) = 206(1.034)^x models the value, in dollars, of a certain bank account by the end of each year from 1957 through 1972, where x is the number of years after 1957. It follows that f(x) represents the estimated value, in dollars, of the bank account x years after 1957. Since the value of f(5) is the value of f(x) when x = 5, it follows that “f(5) is approximately equal to 243” means that f(x) is approximately equal to 243 when x = 5. In the given context, this means that the value of the bank account is estimated to be approximately 243 dollars 5 years after 1957. Therefore, the best interpretation of the statement “f(5) is approximately equal to 243” in this context is the value of the bank account is estimated to be approximately 243 dollars in 1962."
  },
  {
    "id": 658,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "h(t) = -16t^2 + 110t + 72\nThe function above models the height h, in feet, of an object above ground t seconds after being launched straight up in the air. What does the number 72 represent in the function?",
    "answer": "The initial height, in feet, of the object",
    "explanation": "The variable t represents the seconds after the object is launched. Since h(0) = 72, this means that the height, in feet, at 0 seconds, or the initial height, is 72 feet."
  },
  {
    "id": 659,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "A model predicts that the population of Springfield was 15000 in 2005. The model also predicts that each year for the next 5 years, the population p increased by 4% of the previous year's population. Which equation best represents this model, where x is the number of years after 2005, for x <= 5?",
    "answer": "p = 15000(1.04)^x",
    "explanation": "It's given that a model predicts the population of Springfield in 2005 was 15000. The model also predicts that each year for the next 5 years, the population increased by 4% of the previous year's population. The predicted population in one of these years can be found by multiplying the predicted population from the previous year by 1.04. Since the predicted population in 2005 was 15000, the predicted population 1 year later is 15000(1.04). The predicted population 2 years later is this value times 1.04, which is 15000(1.04)(1.04), or 15000(1.04)^2. The predicted population 3 years later is this value times (1.04), or 15000(1.04)^3. More generally, the predicted population, p, x years after is represented by the equation p = 15000(1.04)^x. \n"
  },
  {
    "id": 660,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "N(d) = 115(0.90)^d\nThe function N defined above can be used to model the number of species of brachiopods at various ocean depths d, where d is in hundreds of meters. What does the model predict?\n",
    "answer": "For every increase in depth by 100 meters, the number of brachiopod species decreases by 10%.",
    "explanation": "The function N is exponential, so it follows that N(d) changes by a fixed percentage for each increase in d by 1. Since d is measured in hundreds of meters, it also follows that the number of brachiopod species changes by a fixed percentage for each increase in ocean depth by 100 meters. Since the base of the exponent in the model is 0.90, which is less than 1, the number of brachiopod species decreases as the ocean depth increases. Specifically, the number of brachiopod species at a depth of d + 100 meters is 90% of the number of brachiopod species at a depth of d meters. This means that for each increase in ocean depth by 100 meters, the number of brachiopod species decreases by 10%.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 661,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "g(x) = 11(1/12)^x\nIf the given function g is graphed in the xy-plane, where y = g(x), what is the y-intercept of the graph?",
    "answer": "(0, 11)",
    "explanation": "The x-coordinate of any y-intercept of a graph is 0. Substituting 0 for x in the given equation yields g(0) = 11(1/12)^0. Since any nonzero number raised to the power of 0 is 1, this gives g(0) = 11(1), or g(0) = 11. The y-intercept of the graph is, therefore, the point (0, 11)."
  },
  {
    "id": 662,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The area A, in square centimeters, of a rectangular painting can be represented by the expression w(w + 29), where w is the width, in centimeters, of the painting. Which expression represents the length, in centimeters, of the painting?\n",
    "answer": "w + 29",
    "explanation": "It's given that the expression w(w + 29) represents the area, in square centimeters, of a rectangular painting, where w is the width, in centimeters, of the painting. The area of a rectangle can be calculated by multiplying its length by its width. It follows that the length, in centimeters, of the painting is represented by the expression w + 29.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 663,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "A company opens an account with an initial balance of $36100.00. The account earns interest, and no additional deposits or withdrawals are made. The account balance is given by an exponential function A, where A(t) is the account balance, in dollars, t years after the account is opened. The account balance after 13 years is 68071.93. Which equation could define A?",
    "answer": "A(t) = 36100.00(1.05)^t",
    "explanation": "Since it's given that the account balance, A(t), in dollars, after t years can be modeled by an exponential function, it follows that function A can be written in the form A(t) = Nr^t, where N is the initial value of the function and r is a constant related to the growth of the function. It's given that the initial balance of the account is $36100.00, so it follows that the initial value of the function, or N, must be 36100.00. Substituting 36100.00 for N in the equation A(t) = Nr^t yields A(t) = 36100.00r^t. It's given that the account balance after 13 years, or when t = 13, is $68071.93. It follows that A(13) = 68071.93, or 36100.00r^13 = 68071.93. Dividing each side of the equation 36100.00r^13 = 68071.93 by 36100.00 yields r^13 = 68071.93/36100.00. Taking the 13th root of both sides of this equation is approximately equal to 1.05. Substituting 1.05 for r in the equation A(t) = 36100.00r^t yields A(t) =36100.00(1.05)^t, so the equation could define A."
  },
  {
    "id": 664,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The exponential function g is defined by g(x) = 19* a^x, where a is a positive constant. If g(3) = 2375, what is the value of g(4)?",
    "answer": "11875",
    "explanation": "It's given that the exponential function g is defined by g(x) = 19 * a^x, where a is a positive constant, and g(3) = 2375. It follows that when x = 3, g(x) = 2375. Substituting 3 for x and 2375 for g(x) in the given equation yields 2375 = 19 * a^3. Dividing each side of this equation by 19 yields 125 = a^3. Taking the cube root of both sides of this equation gives a = 5. Substituting 4 for x and 5 for a in the equation g(x) = 19 * a^x  yields g(4) = 19*5^4, or g(4) = 11875. Therefore, the value of g(4) is 11875."
  },
  {
    "id": 665,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "An egg is thrown from a rooftop. The equation h = -4.9t^2 + 9t + 18 represents this situation, where h is the height of the egg above the ground, in meters, t seconds after it is thrown. According to the equation, what is the height, in meters, from which the egg was thrown?\n",
    "answer": "18",
    "explanation": "It's given that an egg is thrown from a rooftop and that the equation h = -4.9t^2 + 9t + 18 represents this situation, where h is the height of the egg above the ground, in meters, t seconds after it is thrown. If follows that the height, in meters, from which the egg was thrown is the value of h when t = 0. Substituting 0 for t in the equation h(t) = -4.9t^2 + 9t + 18 yields h = -4.9(0)^2 + 9(0) + 18, or h = 18. Therefore, according to the equation, the height, in meters, from which the egg was thrown is 18."
  },
  {
    "id": 666,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The function p is defined by p(n) = 7n^3. What is the value of n when p(n) is equal to 56?",
    "answer": "2",
    "explanation": "It's given that p(n) = 7n^3. Substituting 56 for p(n) in this equation yields 56 = 7n^3. Dividing each side of this equation by 7 yields 8 = n^3. Taking the cube root of each side of this equation yields 2 = n. Therefore, when p(n) is equal to 56, the value of n is 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 667,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The equation E(t) = 5(1.8)^t gives the estimated number of employees at a restaurant, where t is the number of years since the restaurant opened. Which What is the best interpretation of the number 5 in this context?",
    "answer": "The estimated number of employees when the restaurant opened",
    "explanation": "For an exponential function of the form E(t) = a(b)^t, where a and b are constants, the initial value of the function, which is the value of the function when t = 0, is and the value of the function increases by a factor of b each time t increases by 1. Since the function E(t) = 5(1.08)^t gives the estimated number of employees at a restaurant and t is the number of years since the restaurant opened, the best interpretation of the number 5 in this context is\nthe estimated number of employees when t = 0, or when the restaurant opened."
  },
  {
    "id": 668,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "f(x) = (x + 4)(x - 1)(2x - 3)\nThe function f is defined above. What are x-intercepts of the graph of the function in the xy-plane?\n",
    "answer": "(-4, 0), (1, 0), (3/2, 0)",
    "explanation": "The graph of the function f in the xy-plane has x-intercepts at the points (x, y), where y = f(x) = 0. Substituting 0 for f(x) in the given equation\nyields 0 = (x + 4)(x - 1)(2x - 3). By the zero product property, x + 4 = 0, x - 1 = 0, or 2x - 3 = 0. Solving each of these linear equations for x, it follows that x = -4, x = 1, and x = 3/2, respectively. This means that the graph of the function f in the xy-plane has three x-intercepts: (-4, 0), (1, 0), and (3/2, -0)."
  },
  {
    "id": 669,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "An object is kicked from a platform. The equation h = -4.9t^2 + 7t + 9 represents this situation, where h is the height of the object above the ground, in meters, t seconds after it is kicked. Which number represents the height, in meters, from which the object was kicked?",
    "answer": "9",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the equation h = -4.9t^2 + 7t + 9 represents this situation, where h is the height, in meters, of the object t seconds after it is kicked. It follows that the height, in meters, from which the object was kicked is the value of h when t = 0. Substituting 0 for t in the equation h = -4.9t^2 + 7t + 9 yields h = -4.9(0)^2 + 7(0) + 9, or h = 9. Therefore, the object was kicked from a height of 9 meters."
  },
  {
    "id": 670,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "Bacteria are growing in a liquid growth medium. There were 300000 cells per milliliter during an initial observation. The number of cells per milliliter doubles every 3 hours. How many cells per milliliter will there be 15 hours after the initial observation?",
    "answer": "9600000",
    "explanation": "Let y represent the number of cells per milliliter x hours after the initial observation. Since the number of cells per milliliter doubles every 3 hours, the relationship between x and y can be represented by an exponential equation of the form y = a(b)^(x / k), where a is the number of cells per milliliter during the initial observation and the number of cells per milliliter increases by a factor of b every k hours. It’s given that there were 300000 cells per milliliter during the initial observation. Therefore, a = 300000. It’s also given that the number of cells per milliliter doubles, or increases by a factor of 2, every 3 hours. Therefore, b = 2 and k = 3. Substituting 300000 for a, 2 for b, and 3 for k in the equation y = a(b)^(x / k) yields y = 300000(2)^(x / 3). The number of cells per milliliter there will be 15 hours after the initial observation is the value of y in this equation when x = 15. Substituting 15 for x in the equation  yields y = 300000(2)^(15 / 3), or y = 300000(2)^5. This is equivalent to y = 300000(32), or y = 9600000. Therefore, 15 hours after the initial observation, there will be 9600000 cells per milliliter.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 671,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "The area A, in square centimeters, of a rectangular cutting board can be represented by the expression w(w + 9), where w is the width, in centimeters, of the cutting board. Which expression represents the length, in centimeters, of the cutting board?",
    "answer": "w + 9",
    "explanation": "It's given that the expression w(w + 9) represents the area, in square centimeters, of a rectangular cutting board, where w is the width, in centimeters, of the cutting board. The area of a rectangle can be calculated by multiplying its length by its width. It follows that the length, in centimeters, of the cutting board is represented by the expression w + 9. "
  },
  {
    "id": 672,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "f(x) = ((a - 19) / x) + 5\nIn the given function f, a is a constant. The graph of function f in the xy-plane, where y = f(x), is translated 3 units down and 4 units to the right to produce the graph of y = g(x). Which equation defines function g?",
    "answer": "g(x) = ((a - 19) / (x - 4)) + 2",
    "explanation": "It's given that the graph of y = g(x) is produced by translating the graph of y = f(x) 3 units down and 4 units to the right in the xy-plane. Therefore, function g can be defined by an equation in the form g(x) = f(x - 4) - 3. Function f is defined by the equation ((a - 19) / x) + 5, where a is a constant. Substituting x - 4 for x in the equation f(x) = ((a - 19) / x) + 5 yields f(x - 4) = ((a - 19) / (x - 4)) + 5. Substituting ((a - 19) / (x - 4)) + 5 for x in the equation g(x) = f(x - 4) - 3 yields g(x) = ((a - 19) / (x - 4)) + 5 - 3 , or g(x) = ((a - 19) / (x - 4)) + 2. Therefore, the equation that defines function g is g(x) = ((a - 19) / (x - 4)) + 2.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 673,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "A function p estimates that there 2000 were animals in a population in 1998. Each year 1998 from to 2010, the function estimates that the number of animals in this population increased by 3% of the number of animals in the population the previous year. Which equation defines this function, where p(x) is the estimated number of animals in the population x years after 1998?",
    "answer": "p(x) = 2000(1.03)^x",
    "explanation": "It's given that a function p estimates that there were 2000 animals in a population in 1998 and that each year from 1998 to 2010, the number of animals in this population increased by 3% of the number of animals in the population the previous year. It follows that this situation can be represented by the function p(x) = a(1 + (r / 100))^x, where p(x) is the estimated number of animals in the population x years after 1998, a is the estimated number of animals in the population in 1998, and each year the estimated number of animals increased by r%. Substituting 2000 for a and 3 for r in this function yields p(x) = 2000(1 + (3 / 100))^x, or p(x) = 2000(1.03)^x."
  },
  {
    "id": 674,
    "domain": "Advanced Math",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "NonLinear functions",
    "question": "There were no jackrabbits in Australia before 1788 when 24 jackrabbits were introduced. By 1920 the population of jackrabbits had reached 10 billion. If the population had grown exponentially, this would correspond to a 16.2% increase, on average, in the population each year. Which of the following functions best models the population p(t) of jackrabbits t years after 1788?",
    "answer": "p(t) = 24(1.162)^t",
    "explanation": "This exponential growth model can be written in the form p(t) = A(1 + r)^t, where p(t) is the population t years after 1788, A is the initial population, and r is the yearly growth rate, expressed as a decimal. Since there were 24 jackrabbits in Australia in 1788, A = 24. Since the number of jackrabbits increased by an average of 16.2% each year, r = 0.162. Therefore, the equation that best models this situation is p(t) = 24(1 + 0.162)^t, or p(t) = 24(1.162)^t."
  },
  {
    "id": 675,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "x = 4, y = 5 - x The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of y?",
    "answer": "1",
    "explanation": "The first equation in the given system of equations is x = 4. Substituting 4 for x in the second equation in the given system of equations yields y = 5 - 4, or y = 1."
  },
  {
    "id": 676,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "s + 7r = 27, r = 3. What is the solution (r, s) to the given system of equations?",
    "answer": "(3, 6)",
    "explanation": "The second equation in the given system is r = 3. Substituting 3 for r in the first equation in the given system yields s + 7(3) = 27, or s + 21 = 27. Subtracting 21 from both sides of this equation yields s = 6. Therefore, the solution (r, s) to the given system of equations is (3, 6)."
  },
  {
    "id": 677,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "4x = 20, -3x + y = -7. The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of x + y?",
    "answer": "13",
    "explanation": "It's given that 4x = 20 and -3x + y = -7 is a system of equations with a solution (x, y). Adding the second equation in the given system to the first equation yields 4x + (-3x + y) = 20 + (-7), which is equivalent to x + y = 13. Thus, the value of x + y is 13."
  },
  {
    "id": 678,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Hiro and Sofia purchased shirts and pants from a store. The price of each shirt purchased was the same and the price of each pair of pants purchased was the same. Hiro purchased 4 shirts and 2 pairs of pants for $86, and Sofia purchased 3 shirts and 5 pairs of pants for $166. Which of the following systems of linear equations represents the situation, if x represents the price, in dollars, of each shirt and y represents the price, in dollars, of each pair of pants?",
    "answer": "4x + 2y = 86, 3x + 5y = 166",
    "explanation": "Hiro purchased 4 shirts and each shirt cost x dollars, so he spent a total of 4x dollars on shirts. Likewise, Hiro purchased 2 pairs of pants, and each pair of pants cost y dollars, so he spent a total of 2y dollars on pants. Therefore, the total amount that Hiro spent was 4x + 2y. Since Hiro spent $86 in total, this can be modeled by the equation 4x + 2y = 86. Using the same reasoning, Sofia bought 3 shirts at x dollars each and 5 pairs of pants at y dollars each, so she spent a total of 3x + 5y dollars on shirts and pants. Since Sofia spent $166 in total, this can be modeled by the equation 3x + 5y = 166."
  },
  {
    "id": 679,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A dance teacher ordered outfits for students for a dance recital. Outfits for boys cost $26, and outfits for girls cost $35. The dance teacher ordered a total of 28 outfits and spent $881. If b represents the number of outfits the dance teacher ordered for boys and g represents the number of outfits the dance teacher ordered for girls, which of the following systems of equations can be solved to find b and g?",
    "answer": "26b + 35g = 881, b + g = 28",
    "explanation": "Outfits for boys cost $26 each and the teacher ordered b outfits for boys, so the teacher spent 26b dollars on outfits for boys. Similarly, outfits for girls cost $35 each and the teacher ordered g outfits for girls, so the teacher spent 35g dollars on outfits for girls. Since the teacher spent a total of $881 on outfits for boys and girls, the equation 26b + 35g = 881 must be true. And since the teacher ordered a total of 28 outfits, the equation b + g = 28 must also be true."
  },
  {
    "id": 680,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "y = 4x - 9, y = 19 What is the solution (x, y) to the given system of equations?",
    "answer": "(7, 19)",
    "explanation": "It's given by the second equation in the system that y = 19. Substituting 19 for y in the first equation yields 19 = 4x - 9. Adding 9 to both sides of this equation yields 28 = 4x. Dividing both sides of this equation by 4 yields 7 = x. Therefore, since x = 7 and y = 19, the solution (x, y) to the given system of equations is (7, 19)."
  },
  {
    "id": 681,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "An online bookstore sells novels and magazines. Each novel sells for $4, and each magazine sells for $1. If Sadie purchased a total of 11 novels and magazines that have a combined selling price of $20, how many novels did she purchase?",
    "answer": "3",
    "explanation": "Let n be the number of novels and m be the number of magazines that Sadie purchased. If Sadie purchased a total of 11 novels and magazines, then n + m = 11. It is given that the combined price of 11 novels and magazines is $20. Since each novel sells for $4 and each magazine sells for $1, it follows that 4n + m = 20. So the system of equations below must hold. 4n + m = 20, n + m = 11 Subtracting corresponding sides of the second equation from the first equation yields 3n = 9, so n = 3. Therefore, Sadie purchased 3 novels."
  },
  {
    "id": 682,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A discount airline sells a certain number of tickets, x, for a flight for $90 each. It sells the number of remaining tickets, y, for $250 each. For a particular flight, the airline sold 120 tickets and collected a total of $27,600 from the sale of those tickets. Which system of equations represents this relationship between x and y?",
    "answer": "x + y = 120, 90x + 250y = 27,600",
    "explanation": "The airline sold two types of tickets for this flight: x tickets at $90 each and the remaining y tickets at $250 each. Because the airline sold a total of 120 tickets for this flight, it must be true that x + y = 120. The amount, in dollars, collected from the sale of x tickets at $90 each is represented by 90x. The amount, in dollars, collected from the sale of the remaining y tickets at $250 each is represented by 250y. It is given that a total of $27,600 was collected from the sale of all tickets. Therefore, it must also be true that 90x + 250y = 27,600."
  },
  {
    "id": 683,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A movie theater charges $11 for each full-price ticket and $8.25 for each reduced-price ticket. For one movie showing, the theater sold a total of 214 full-price and reduced-price tickets for $2,145. Which of the following systems of equations could be used to determine the number of full-price tickets, f, and the number of reduced-price tickets, r, sold?",
    "answer": "f + r = 214, 11f + 8.25r = 2,145",
    "explanation": "The movie theater sells f full-price tickets and r reduced-price tickets, so the total number of tickets sold is f + r. Since the movie theater sold a total of 214 full-price and reduced-price tickets for one movie showing, it follows that f + r = 214. The movie theater charges $11 for each full-price ticket; thus, the sales for full-price tickets, in dollars, is given by 11f. The movie theater charges $8.25 for each reduced-price ticket; thus, the sales for reduced-price tickets, in dollars, is given by 8.25r. Therefore, the total sales, in dollars, for the movie showing is given by 11f + 8.25r. Since the total sales for all full-price and reduced-price tickets is $2,145, it follows that 11f + 8.25r = 2,145."
  },
  {
    "id": 684,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "x = 5, y = x - 8. Which of the following points (x, y) is the solution to the given system of equations in the xy-plane?",
    "answer": "(5, -3)",
    "explanation": "A solution to a system of equations in the xy-plane is a point (x, y) that lies on the graph of each equation in the system. The first equation given is x = 5. Substituting 5 for x in the second given equation yields y = 5 - 8, or y = -3. It follows that in the xy-plane, the point (5, -3) lies on the graph of each equation in the system. Therefore, the solution to the given system of equations in the xy-plane is (5, -3)."
  },
  {
    "id": 685,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "3x = 12, -3x + y = -6. The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of y?",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Adding the second equation in the given system to the first equation in the given system yields 3x + (-3x + y) = 12 + (-6), which is equivalent to y = 6."
  },
  {
    "id": 686,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A farmer sells apples and oranges at a market. The cost of an apple is $2, and the cost of an orange is $3. One day, the farmer sold a total of 50 apples and oranges and earned $120. Let a represent the number of apples sold and o represent the number of oranges sold. Which system of equations can be used to determine the values of a and o?",
    "answer": "a + o = 50, 2a + 3o = 120",
    "explanation": "The farmer sold a total of 50 apples and oranges, so the equation a + o = 50 represents this condition. The total earnings from apples and oranges is given by 2a + 3o = 120. Therefore, the correct system of equations is a + o = 50 and 2a + 3o = 120."
  },
  {
    "id": 687,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A train travels at a constant speed of 60 miles per hour. A car travels at a speed of 75 miles per hour. If both vehicles start at the same location and travel in the same direction, how long will it take for the car to be 30 miles ahead of the train?",
    "answer": "2 hours",
    "explanation": "The relative speed of the car compared to the train is 75 - 60 = 15 miles per hour. To be 30 miles ahead, the car must travel for 30 ÷ 15 = 2 hours.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 688,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A company is producing two types of items: Type A and Type B. The company makes a profit of $5 for each Type A item and $8 for each Type B item. If the company sells 100 items in total and makes a total profit of $700, how many Type B items were sold?",
    "answer": "40",
    "explanation": "Let x represent the number of Type A items sold and y represent the number of Type B items sold. The total number of items sold is given by x + y = 100. The total profit equation is given by 5x + 8y = 700. Solving for y, we get 8y = 700 - 5(100 - y), which simplifies to 8y = 700 - 500 + 5y, or 3y = 200. Therefore, y = 40."
  },
  {
    "id": 689,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A person is saving money in two different bank accounts. One account earns an interest rate of 2% per year, and the other earns an interest rate of 3% per year. If the total savings amount is $5000 and the total interest earned in a year is $120, how much money is in the account with the 3% interest rate?",
    "answer": "3000",
    "explanation": "Let x represent the amount in the 2% interest account and y represent the amount in the 3% interest account. The total amount equation is x + y = 5000, and the total interest equation is 0.02x + 0.03y = 120. Solving for y, we get y = 3000."
  },
  {
    "id": 690,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A store sells two types of notebooks: standard and premium. A standard notebook costs $4, and a premium notebook costs $7. If a customer buys 12 notebooks and spends a total of $60, how many premium notebooks did they buy?",
    "answer": "3",
    "explanation": "Let s represent the number of standard notebooks and p represent the number of premium notebooks. The total number of notebooks is given by s + p = 12. The total cost equation is given by 4s + 7p = 60. Solving for p, we get p = 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 691,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A car rental company offers two types of rental packages: economy and luxury. The economy package costs $30 per day, and the luxury package costs $50 per day. If a customer rents a total of 7 days and spends $280, how many days did they rent the luxury package?",
    "answer": "2",
    "explanation": "Let e represent the number of economy rental days and l represent the number of luxury rental days. The total days equation is given by e + l = 7. The total cost equation is given by 30e + 50l = 280. Solving for l, we get l = 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 692,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "y = -3x 4x + y = 15 The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of x?",
    "answer": "15",
    "explanation": "The given system of linear equations can be solved by the substitution method. Substituting -3x for y from the first equation in the given system into the second equation yields 4x + (-3x) = 15, or x = 15."
  },
  {
    "id": 693,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "x + y = 20 2(x + y) + 3y = 85 If (x, y) is the solution to the given system of equations, what is the value of y?",
    "answer": "15",
    "explanation": "Substituting 20 for x + y in the second equation in the system yields 2(20) + 3y = 85, or 40 + 3y = 85. Subtracting 40 from both sides of this equation yields 3y = 45. Dividing both sides of this equation by 3 yields y = 15."
  },
  {
    "id": 694,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "x = 8 x + 3y = 26 The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of y?",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "The first equation in the given system is x = 8. Substituting 8 for x in the second equation in the given system yields 8 + 3y = 26. Subtracting 8 from both sides of this equation yields 3y = 18. Dividing both sides of this equation by 3 yields y = 6. Therefore, the value of y is 6."
  },
  {
    "id": 695,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Connor has c dollars and Maria has m dollars. Connor has 4 times as many dollars as Maria, and together they have a total of $25.00. Which system of equations represents this situation?",
    "answer": "c = 4m c + m = 25",
    "explanation": "It’s given that Connor has c dollars, Maria has m dollars, and Connor has 4 times as many dollars as Maria. This can be represented by the equation c = 4m. It’s also given that together, Connor and Maria have a total of $25.00, which can be represented by the equation c + m = 25. Therefore, the system consisting of the equations c = 4m and c + m = 25 represents this situation."
  },
  {
    "id": 696,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A group of 202 people went on an overnight camping trip, taking 60 tents with them. Some of the tents held 2 people each, and the rest held 4 people each. Assuming all the tents were filled to capacity and every person got to sleep in a tent, exactly how many of the tents were 2-person tents?",
    "answer": "19",
    "explanation": "Let x represent the number of 2-person tents and let y represent the number of 4-person tents. It is given that the total number of tents was 60 and the total number of people in the group was 202. This situation can be expressed as a system of two equations, x + y = 60 and 2x + 4y = 202. The first equation can be rewritten as y = –x + 60. Substituting –x + 60 for y in the equation 2x + 4y = 202 yields 2x + 4(–x + 60) = 202. Distributing and combining like terms gives –2x + 240 = 202. Subtracting 240 from both sides of –2x + 240 = 202 and then dividing both sides by –2 gives x = 19. Therefore, the number of 2-person tents is 19."
  },
  {
    "id": 697,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "y = 3x, 2x + y = 12 The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of 5x?",
    "answer": "12",
    "explanation": "It's given by the first equation in the system that y = 3x. Substituting 3x for y in the equation 2x + y = 12 yields 2x + 3x = 12, or 5x = 12."
  },
  {
    "id": 698,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "At how many points do the graphs of the equations y = x + 20 and y = 8x intersect in the xy-plane?",
    "answer": "1",
    "explanation": "Each given equation is written in slope-intercept form, y = mx + b, where m is the slope and (0, b) is the y-intercept of the graph of the equation in the xy-plane. The graphs of two lines that have different slopes will intersect at exactly one point. The graph of the first equation is a line with slope 1. The graph of the second equation is a line with slope 8. Since the graphs are lines with different slopes, they will intersect at exactly one point."
  },
  {
    "id": 699,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A company that provides whale-watching tours takes groups of 21 people at a time. The company's revenue is 80 dollars per adult and 60 dollars per child. If the company's revenue for one group consisting of adults and children was 1,440 dollars, how many people in the group were children?",
    "answer": "12",
    "explanation": "Let x represent the number of children in a whale-watching tour group. Let y represent the number of adults in this group. Because it's given that 21 people are in a group and the group consists of adults and children, it must be true that x + y = 21. Since the company's revenue is 60 dollars per child, the total revenue from x children in this group was 60x dollars. Since the company's revenue is 80 dollars per adult, the total revenue from y adults in this group was 80y dollars. Because it's given that the total revenue for this group was 1,440 dollars, it must be true that 60x + 80y = 1,440. The equations x + y = 21 and 60x + 80y = 1,440 form a linear system of equations that can be solved to find the value of x, which represents the number of children in the group, using the elimination method. Multiplying both sides of the equation x + y = 21 by 80 yields 80x + 80y = 1,680. Subtracting 60x + 80y = 1,440 from 80x + 80y = 1,680 yields (80x + 80y) – (60x + 80y) = 1,680 – 1,440, which is equivalent to 80x – 60x + 80y – 80y = 240, or 20x = 240. Dividing both sides of this equation by 20 yields x = 12. Therefore, 12 people in the group were children."
  },
  {
    "id": 700,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "The system of equations above has solution (x, y). What is the value of x? (1/2)y = 4, x – (1/2)y = 2",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Adding the corresponding sides of the two equations eliminates y and yields x = 6, as shown. 1/2 y = 4 x – 1/2 y = 2 x + 0 = 6 If (x, y) is a solution to the system, then (x, y) satisfies both equations in the system and any equation derived from them. Therefore, x = 6."
  },
  {
    "id": 701,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A store sells two types of pens: standard pens cost $1.50 each, and premium pens cost $2.50 each. A customer bought a total of 20 pens and spent $35. How many standard pens did they buy?",
    "answer": "10",
    "explanation": "Let x represent the number of standard pens and y represent the number of premium pens. We have the system of equations: x + y = 20, 1.5x + 2.5y = 35. Solving for y in the first equation, y = 20 - x. Substituting into the second equation: 1.5x + 2.5(20 - x) = 35. Expanding: 1.5x + 50 - 2.5x = 35. Combining like terms: -x + 50 = 35. Subtracting 50 from both sides: -x = -15. Dividing by -1: x = 15. Therefore, the number of standard pens is 15."
  },
  {
    "id": 702,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A bakery sells two sizes of cakes: small cakes cost $8 each, and large cakes cost $15 each. A customer bought a total of 10 cakes and spent $104. How many small cakes did they buy?",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "Let x represent the number of small cakes and y represent the number of large cakes. We set up the system: x + y = 10, 8x + 15y = 104. Solving for y in the first equation, y = 10 - x. Substituting into the second equation: 8x + 15(10 - x) = 104. Expanding: 8x + 150 - 15x = 104. Combining like terms: -7x + 150 = 104. Subtracting 150 from both sides: -7x = -46. Dividing by -7: x = 6. Therefore, the number of small cakes is 6."
  },
  {
    "id": 703,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Two customers purchased the same kind of bread and eggs at a store. The first customer paid 12.45 dollars for 1 loaf of bread and 2 dozen eggs. The second customer paid 19.42 dollars for 4 loaves of bread and 1 dozen eggs. What is the cost, in dollars, of 1 dozen eggs?",
    "answer": "4.34",
    "explanation": "Let ℓ represent the cost, in dollars, of 1 loaf of bread, and let d represent the cost, in dollars, of 1 dozen eggs. The first customer's purchase is represented by the equation ℓ + 2d = 12.45. The second customer's purchase is represented by 4ℓ + d = 19.42. This system of equations is solved using elimination: multiplying the first equation by -4 yields -4ℓ - 8d = -49.8. Adding this to 4ℓ + d = 19.42 results in -7d = -30.38. Dividing both sides by -7 gives d = 4.34. Therefore, the cost of 1 dozen eggs is 4.34."
  },
  {
    "id": 704,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "y = 2x + 10 and y = 2x - 1 At how many points do the graphs of the given equations intersect in the xy-plane?",
    "answer": "Zero",
    "explanation": "A system of two linear equations in two variables x and y has zero points of intersection if the lines are parallel and distinct. The given equations y = 2x + 10 and y = 2x - 1 have the same slope m = 2, but different y-intercepts (10 and -1). Since the slopes are equal but intercepts are different, the lines are parallel and distinct, meaning they never intersect."
  },
  {
    "id": 705,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "y = -1/9 x, y = 1/2 x The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of x?",
    "answer": "0",
    "explanation": "The first equation states y = -1/9 x. Substituting this into the second equation y = 1/2 x results in -1/9 x = 1/2 x. Multiplying both sides by 18 simplifies to -2x = 9x. Adding 2x to both sides results in 0 = 11x. Dividing by 11 gives x = 0."
  },
  {
    "id": 706,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A bus traveled on the highway and on local roads to complete a trip of 160 miles. The trip took 4 hours. The bus traveled at an average speed of 55 mph on the highway and 25 mph on local roads. If x is the time, in hours, the bus traveled on the highway and y is the time, in hours, it traveled on local roads, which system of equations represents this situation?",
    "answer": "55x + 25y = 160, x + y = 4",
    "explanation": "The total distance equation is 55x + 25y = 160 (speed × time = distance). The total time equation is x + y = 4 (since the trip took 4 hours). Therefore, the correct system is 55x + 25y = 160, x + y = 4."
  },
  {
    "id": 707,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "x + 3 = -2y + 5, x - 3 = 2y + 7 The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of 2x?",
    "answer": "12",
    "explanation": "Adding the two given equations: (x + 3) + (x - 3) = (-2y + 5) + (2y + 7) simplifies to 2x = 12. Thus, the value of 2x is 12."
  },
  {
    "id": 708,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "The combined original price for a mirror and a vase is $60. After a 25% discount to the mirror and a 45% discount to the vase, the combined sale price is $39. Which system of equations gives the original price m, in dollars, of the mirror and v, in dollars, of the vase?",
    "answer": "m + v = 60, 0.75m + 0.55v = 39",
    "explanation": "The total price equation is m + v = 60. The mirror’s discounted price is 0.75m (since it retains 75% of its price after a 25% discount). The vase’s discounted price is 0.55v (since it retains 55% of its price after a 45% discount). The final equation is 0.75m + 0.55v = 39."
  },
  {
    "id": 709,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "4x + 5y = 100, 5x + 4y = 62 If the system of equations above has solution (x, y), what is the value of x + y?",
    "answer": "18",
    "explanation": "Adding both equations results in 9x + 9y = 162. Dividing both sides by 9 gives x + y = 18."
  },
  {
    "id": 710,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A wire with a length of 106 inches is cut into two parts. One part has a length of x inches, and the other part has a length of y inches. The value of x is 6 more than 4 times the value of y. What is the value of x?",
    "answer": "86",
    "explanation": "It's given that a wire with a length of 106 inches is cut into two parts. It's also given that one part has a length of x inches and the other part has a length of y inches. This can be represented by the equation x + y = 106. It's also given that the value of x is 6 more than 4 times the value of y. This can be represented by the equation x = 4y + 6. Substituting 4y + 6 for x in the equation x + y = 106 yields 4y + 6 + y = 106, or 5y + 6 = 106. Subtracting 6 from each side of this equation yields 5y = 100. Dividing each side of this equation by 5 yields y = 20. Substituting 20 for y in the equation x = 4y + 6 yields x = 4(20) + 6, or x = 86."
  },
  {
    "id": 711,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "-15x + 25y = 65 One of the two equations in a system of linear equations is given. The system has infinitely many solutions. Which of the following could be the second equation in the system?",
    "answer": "-12x + 20y = 52",
    "explanation": "It's given that the system has infinitely many solutions. A system of two linear equations has infinitely many solutions when the two linear equations are equivalent. Dividing both sides of the given equation by 5 yields -3x + 5y = 13. Dividing both sides of choice C by 4 also yields -3x + 5y = 13, so choice C is equivalent to the given equation. Thus, choice C could be the second equation in the system."
  },
  {
    "id": 712,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "x + 2y = 6, x - 2y = 4 The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of x?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Adding the first equation to the second equation in the given system yields (x + 2y) + (x - 2y) = 6 + 4, or (x + x) + (2y - 2y) = 10. Combining like terms in this equation yields 2x = 10. Dividing both sides of this equation by 2 yields x = 5. Thus, the value of x is 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 713,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "y - 9x = 13, 5x = 2y What is the solution (x, y) to the given system of equations?",
    "answer": "(-2, -5)",
    "explanation": "Adding 9x to both sides of the first equation in the given system yields y = 9x + 13. Substituting the expression 9x + 13 for y in the second equation in the given system yields 5x = 2(9x + 13). Distributing the 2 on the right-hand side of this equation yields 5x = 18x + 26. Subtracting 18x from both sides of this equation yields -13x = 26. Dividing both sides of this equation by -13 yields x = -2. Substituting -2 for x in the equation y = 9x + 13 yields y = 9(-2) + 13, or y = -5. Therefore, the solution (x, y) to the given system of equations is (-2, -5)."
  },
  {
    "id": 714,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "The score on a trivia game is obtained by subtracting the number of incorrect answers from twice the number of correct answers. If a player answered 40 questions and obtained a score of 50, how many questions did the player answer correctly?",
    "answer": "30",
    "explanation": "Let x represent the number of correct answers from the player and y represent the number of incorrect answers from the player. Since the player answered 40 questions in total, the equation x + y = 40 represents this situation. Also, since the score is found by subtracting the number of incorrect answers from twice the number of correct answers and the player received a score of 50, the equation 2x - y = 50 represents this situation. Adding the equations in the system of two equations together yields (x + y) + (2x - y) = 40 + 50. This can be rewritten as 3x = 90. Finally, solving for x by dividing both sides of the equation by 3 yields x = 30."
  },
  {
    "id": 715,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "y = (-1/5)x, y = (1/7)x The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of x?",
    "answer": "0",
    "explanation": "It's given by the first equation in the system that y = -1/5 x. Substituting -1/5 x for y in the second equation in the system, y = 1/7 x, yields -1/5 x = 1/7 x. Adding -1/5 x to both sides of this equation yields 0 = 1/7 x + 1/5 x, which is equivalent to 0 = 5/35 x + 7/35 x, or 0 = 12/35 x. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 35/12 yields 0 = x. Therefore, the value of x is 0."
  },
  {
    "id": 716,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "In the xy-plane, the graph of y = x + 3 intersects the graph of y = 2x - 6 at the point (a, b). What is the value of a?",
    "answer": "9",
    "explanation": "Since the graph of y = x + 3 intersects the graph of y = 2x - 6 at the point (a, b), the ordered pair (a, b) is the solution to the system of linear equations consisting of y = x + 3 and y = 2x - 6, and the value of a is the value of x in the solution of this system. Since both x + 3 and 2x - 6 are equal to y, it follows that x + 3 = 2x - 6. Subtracting x from both sides of the equation and adding 6 to both sides yields 9 = x. Therefore, the value of a is 9."
  },
  {
    "id": 717,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "8x + y = 5, y = 9x + 1. The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of x?",
    "answer": "2025-04-17 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "The second equation in the given system is y = 9x + 1. Substituting 9x + 1 for y in the first equation in the given system yields 8x + 9x + 1 = 5, which is equivalent to 17x + 1 = 5. Subtracting 1 from both sides of this equation yields 17x = 4. Dividing both sides of this equation by 17 yields x = 4/17."
  },
  {
    "id": 718,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A proposal for a new library was included on an election ballot. A radio show stated that 3 times as many people voted in favor of the proposal as people who voted against it. A social media post reported that 15,000 more people voted in favor of the proposal than voted against it. Based on these data, how many people voted against the proposal?",
    "answer": "7500",
    "explanation": "It's given that a radio show stated that 3 times as many people voted in favor of the proposal as people who voted against the proposal. It follows that 3x is the number of people who voted in favor of the proposal and 3x - x, or 2x, is how many more people voted in favor of the proposal than voted against it. It's also given that a social media post reported that 15,000 more people voted in favor of the proposal than voted against it. Thus, 2x = 15,000. Since 2x = 15,000, the value of x must be half of 15,000, or 7,500. Therefore, 7,500 people voted against the proposal."
  },
  {
    "id": 719,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "y = (1/3)x - 14, y = -x + 18. The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of x?",
    "answer": "24",
    "explanation": "The given system of equations can be solved by the substitution method. The first equation in the given system of equations is y = (1/3)x - 14. Substituting (1/3)x - 14 for y in the second equation in the given system yields (1/3)x - 14 = -x + 18. Adding 14 to both sides of this equation yields (1/3)x = -x + 32. Adding x to both sides of this equation yields (4/3)x = 32. Multiplying both sides of this equation by (3/4) yields x = 24."
  },
  {
    "id": 720,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "y = 2x - 3, 3y = 5x. In the solution to the system of equations above, what is the value of y?",
    "answer": "15",
    "explanation": "Multiplying both sides of y = 2x - 3 by 5 results in 5y = 10x - 15. Multiplying both sides of 3y = 5x by 2 results in 6y = 10x. Subtracting the resulting equations yields 5y - 6y = (10x - 15) - (10x), which simplifies to -y = -15. Dividing both sides of -y = -15 by -1 results in y = 15."
  },
  {
    "id": 721,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "x + 3y = 29, 3y = 11. The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of x?",
    "answer": "18",
    "explanation": "It's given by the second equation in the system that 3y = 11. Substituting 11 for 3y in the first equation in the system, x + 3y = 29, yields x + 11 = 29. Subtracting 11 from both sides of this equation yields x = 18."
  },
  {
    "id": 722,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "5x + 3y = 38, x + 3y = 10. In the solution (x, y) to the system of equations above, what is the value of x?",
    "answer": "7",
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 7. Subtracting the second equation from the first equation eliminates the variable y. 5x + 3y = 38, -(x + 3y = 10), 4x = 28. Dividing both sides of the resulting equation by 4 yields x = 7."
  },
  {
    "id": 723,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "-x + y = -3.5, x + 3y = 9.5 If (x, y) satisfies the system of equations above, what is the value of y?",
    "answer": "2025-03-02 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "One method for solving the system of equations for y is to add corresponding sides of the two equations. Adding the left-hand sides gives (-x + y) + (x + 3y), or 4y. Adding the right-hand sides yields -3.5 + 9.5 = 6. It follows that 4y = 6. Finally, dividing both sides of 4y = 6 by 4 yields y = 6/4 or 3/2. Note that 3/2 and 1.5 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 724,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "(3/2)y - (1/4)x = (2/3) - (3/2)y, (1/2)x + 3/2 = py + 9/2 In the given system of equations, p is a constant. If the system has no solution, what is the value of p?",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "A system of two linear equations in two variables, x and y, has no solution if the lines represented by the equations in the xy-plane are parallel and distinct. Lines represented by equations in standard form, Ax + By = C and Dx + Ey = F, are parallel if the coefficients for x and y in one equation are proportional to the corresponding coefficients in the other equation, meaning D/A = E/B, and the lines are distinct if the constants are not proportional, meaning F/C is not equal to D/A or E/B. The first equation in the given system is 3/2 y - 1/4 x = 2/3 - 3/2 y. Multiplying each side of this equation by 12 yields 18y - 3x = 8 - 18y. Adding 18y to each side of this equation yields 36y - 3x = 8, or -3x + 36y = 8. The second equation in the given system is 1/2 x + 3/2 = py + 9/2. Multiplying each side of this equation by 2 yields x + 3 = 2py + 9. Subtracting 2py from each side of this equation yields x + 3 - 2py = 9. Subtracting 3 from each side of this equation yields x - 2py = 6. Therefore, the two equations in the given system, written in standard form, are -3x + 36y = 8 and x - 2py = 6. As previously stated, if this system has no solution, the lines represented by the equations in the xy-plane are parallel and distinct, meaning the proportion 1/-3 = -2p/36, or -1/3 = -p/18, is true and the proportion 6/8 = 1/-3 is not true. Multiplying each side of the true proportion, -1/3 = -p/18, by -18 yields 6 = p. Therefore, if the system has no solution, then the value of p is 6."
  },
  {
    "id": 725,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "ax + by = 72, 6x + 2by = 56 In the given system of equations, a and b are constants. The graphs of these equations in the xy-plane intersect at the point (4, y). What is the value of a?",
    "answer": "14",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the graphs of the given system of equations intersect at the point (4, y). Therefore, (4, y) is the solution to the given system. Multiplying the first equation in the given system by -2 yields -2ax - 2by = -144. Adding this equation to the second equation in the system yields (-2a + 6)x + (-2b + 2b)y = (-144 + 56), or (-2a + 6)x = -88. Since (4, y) is the solution to the system, the value of a can be found by substituting 4 for x in this equation, which yields (-2a + 6)(4) = -88. Dividing both sides of this equation by 4 yields -2a + 6 = -22. Subtracting 6 from both sides of this equation yields -2a = -28. Dividing both sides of this equation by -2 yields a = 14."
  },
  {
    "id": 726,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "-12x + 14y = 36, -6x + 7y = -18 How many solutions does the given system of equations have?",
    "answer": "Zero",
    "explanation": "A system of two linear equations in two variables, x and y, has zero solutions if the lines representing the equations in the xy-plane are distinct and parallel. Two lines are distinct and parallel if they have the same slope but different y-intercepts. Each equation in the given system can be written in slope-intercept form y = mx + b, where m is the slope of the line representing the equation in the xy-plane and (0, b) is the y-intercept. Adding 12x to both sides of the first equation in the given system of equations, -12x + 14y = 36, yields 14y = 12x + 36. Dividing both sides of this equation by 14 yields y = (6/7)x + 18/7. It follows that the first equation in the given system of equations has a slope of 6/7 and a y-intercept of (0, 18/7). Adding 6x to both sides of the second equation in the given system of equations, -6x + 7y = -18, yields 7y = 6x - 18. Dividing both sides of this equation by 7 yields y = (6/7)x - 18/7. It follows that the second equation in the given system of equations has a slope of 6/7 and a y-intercept of (0, -18/7). Since the slopes of these lines are the same and the y-intercepts are different, it follows that the given system of equations has zero solutions."
  },
  {
    "id": 727,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "48x - 64y = 48y + 24, ry = 1/8 - 12x In the given system of equations, r is a constant. If the system has no solution, what is the value of r?",
    "answer": "-28",
    "explanation": "A system of two linear equations in two variables, x and y, has no solution if the lines represented by the equations in the xy-plane are distinct and parallel. The first equation in the given system, 48x - 64y = 48y + 24, can be written in the form Ax + By = C by subtracting 48y from both sides of the equation to yield 48x - 112y = 24. The second equation in the given system, ry = 1/8 - 12x, can be written in the form Ax + By = C by adding 12x to both sides of the equation to yield 12x + ry = 1/8. The coefficient of x in the second equation is 1/4 times the coefficient of x in the first equation. That is, 48(1/4) = 12. For the lines to be parallel, the coefficient of y in the second equation must also be 1/4 times the coefficient of y in the first equation. Therefore, -112(1/4) = r, or -28 = r. Thus, if the given system has no solution, the value of r is -28."
  },
  {
    "id": 728,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "4x - 6y = 10y + 2ty = 1/2 + 2x In the given system of equations, t is a constant. If the system has no solution, what is the value of t?",
    "answer": "8",
    "explanation": "The given system of equations can be solved using the elimination method. Multiplying both sides of the second equation in the given system by -2 yields -2ty = -1 - 4x, or -1 - 4x = -2ty. Adding this equation to the first equation in the given system, 4x - 6y = 10y + 2, yields (4x - 6y) + (-1 - 4x) = (10y + 2) + (-2ty), or -1 - 6y = 10y - 2ty + 2. Subtracting 10y from both sides of this equation yields (-1 - 6y) - (10y) = (10y - 2ty + 2) - (10y), or -1 - 16y = -2ty + 2. If the given system has no solution, then the equation -1 - 16y = -2ty + 2 has no solution. If this equation has no solution, the coefficients of y on each side of the equation, -16 and -2t, must be equal, which yields the equation -16 = -2t. Dividing both sides of this equation by -2 yields 8 = t. Thus, if the system has no solution, the value of t is 8. Alternate approach: A system of two linear equations in two variables, x and y, has no solution if the lines represented by the equations in the xy-plane are parallel and distinct. Lines represented by equations in the form Ax + By = C, where A, B, and C are constant terms, are parallel if the ratio of the x-coefficients is equal to the ratio of the y-coefficients, and distinct if the ratio of the x-coefficients is not equal to the ratio of the constant terms. Subtracting 10y from both sides of the first equation in the given system yields (4x - 6y) - (10y) = (10y + 2) - (10y), or 4x - 16y = 2. Subtracting 2x from both sides of the second equation in the given system yields (ty) - (2x) = (1/2 + 2x) - (2x), or -2x + ty = 1/2. The ratio of the x-coefficients for these equations is -2/4, or -1/2. The ratio of the y-coefficients for these equations is -16/2, or -t/16. The ratio of the constant terms for these equations is 1/2/2, or 1/4. Since the ratio of the x-coefficients, -1/2, is not equal to the ratio of the constants, 1/4, the lines represented by the equations are distinct. Setting the ratio of the x-coefficients equal to the ratio of the y-coefficients yields -1/2 = -t/16. Multiplying both sides of this equation by -16 yields (-1/2)(-16) = (-t/16)(-16), or t = 8. Therefore, when t = 8, the lines represented by these equations are parallel. Thus, if the system has no solution, the value of t is 8."
  },
  {
    "id": 729,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "7x - 5y = 4, 4x - 8y = 9 If (x, y) is the solution to the system of equations above, what is the value of 3x + 3y?",
    "answer": "-5",
    "explanation": "Subtracting the second equation, 4x - 8y = 9, from the first equation, 7x - 5y = 4, results in (7x - 5y) - (4x - 8y) = 4 - 9, or 7x - 5y - 4x + 8y = -5. Combining like terms on the left-hand side of this equation yields 3x + 3y = -5."
  },
  {
    "id": 730,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A sample of a certain alloy has a total mass of 50.0 grams and is 50.0% silicon by mass. The sample was created by combining two pieces of different alloys. The first piece was 30.0% silicon by mass and the second piece was 80.0% silicon by mass. What was the mass, in grams, of the silicon in the second piece?",
    "answer": "16",
    "explanation": "Let x represent the total mass, in grams, of the first piece, and let y represent the total mass, in grams, of the second piece. It's given that the sample has a total mass of 50.0 grams. Therefore, the equation x + y = 50.0 represents this situation. It's also given that the sample is 50.0% silicon by mass. Therefore, the total mass of the silicon in the sample is 0.500(50.0), or 25.0 grams. It's also given that the first piece was 30.0% silicon by mass and the second piece was 80.0% silicon by mass. Therefore, the masses, in grams, of the silicon in the first and second pieces can be represented by the expressions 0.300x and 0.800y, respectively. Since the sample was created by combining the first and second pieces, and the total mass of the silicon in the sample is 25.0 grams, the equation 0.300x + 0.800y = 25.0 represents this situation. Subtracting y from both sides of the equation x + y = 50.0 yields x = 50.0 - y. Substituting 50.0 - y for x in the equation 0.300x + 0.800y = 25.0 yields 0.300(50.0 - y) + 0.800y = 25.0. Distributing 0.300 on the left-hand side of this equation yields 15.0 - 0.300y + 0.800y = 25.0. Combining like terms on the left-hand side of this equation yields 15.0 + 0.500y = 25.0. Subtracting 15.0 from both sides of this equation yields 0.500y = 10.0. Dividing both sides of this equation by 0.500 yields y = 20.0. Substituting 20.0 for y in the expression representing the mass, in grams, of the silicon in the second piece, 0.800y, yields 0.800(20.0), or 16.0. Therefore, the mass, in grams, of the silicon in the second piece is 16.0."
  },
  {
    "id": 731,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "48x - 72y = 30y + 24, ry = 1/6 - 16x In the given system of equations, r is a constant. If the system has no solution, what is the value of r?",
    "answer": "-34",
    "explanation": "A system of two linear equations in two variables, x and y, has no solution if the lines represented by the equations in the xy-plane are distinct and parallel. The first equation in the given system can be written in standard form by subtracting 30y from both sides of the equation to yield 48x - 102y = 24. The second equation in the given system can be written in standard form by adding 16x to both sides of the equation to yield 16x + ry = 1/6. The coefficient of x in this second equation, 16, is 1/3 times the coefficient of x in the first equation, 48. For the lines to be parallel, the coefficient of y in the second equation, r, must also be 1/3 times the coefficient of y in the first equation, -102. Thus, r = 1/3 (-102), or r = -34. Therefore, if the given system has no solution, the value of r is -34."
  },
  {
    "id": 732,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "During a month, Morgan ran r miles at 5 miles per hour and biked b miles at 10 miles per hour. She ran and biked a total of 200 miles that month, and she biked for twice as many hours as she ran. What is the total number of miles that Morgan biked during the month?",
    "answer": "160",
    "explanation": "The number of hours Morgan spent running or biking can be calculated by dividing the distance she traveled during that activity by her speed, in miles per hour, for that activity. So the number of hours she ran can be represented by the expression r/5, and the number of hours she biked can be represented by the expression b/10. It’s given that she biked for twice as many hours as she ran, so this can be represented by the equation (b/10) = 2(r/5), which can be rewritten as b = 4r. It’s also given that she ran r miles and biked b miles, and that she ran and biked a total of 200 miles. This can be represented by the equation r + b = 200. Substituting 4r for b in this equation yields r + 4r = 200, or 5r = 200. Solving for r yields r = 40. Determining the number of miles she biked, b, can be found by substituting 40 for r in r + b = 200, which yields 40 + b = 200. Solving for b yields b = 160.\n"
  },
  {
    "id": 733,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "(1/2)x + (1/3)y = 1/6, ax + y = c In the system of equations below, a and c are constants. If the system of equations has an infinite number of solutions (x,y), what is the value of a?",
    "answer": "2025-03-02 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "A system of two linear equations has infinitely many solutions if one equation is equivalent to the other. This means that when the two equations are written in the same form, each coefficient or constant in one equation is equal to the corresponding coefficient or constant in the other equation multiplied by the same number. The equations in the given system of equations are written in the same form, with x and y on the left-hand side and a constant on the right-hand side of the equation. The coefficient of y in the second equation is equal to the coefficient of y in the first equation multiplied by 3. Therefore, a, the coefficient of x in the second equation, must be equal to 3 times the coefficient of x in the first equation: a = (1/2)(3), or a = 3/2."
  },
  {
    "id": 734,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "y = 4x + 1, 4y = 15x - 8 The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of x - y?",
    "answer": "35",
    "explanation": "The first equation in the given system of equations defines y as 4x + 1. Substituting 4x + 1 for y in the second equation in the given system of equations yields 4(4x + 1) = 15x - 8. Applying the distributive property on the left-hand side of this equation yields 16x + 4 = 15x - 8. Subtracting 15x from each side of this equation yields x + 4 = -8. Subtracting 4 from each side of this equation yields x = -12. Substituting -12 for x in the first equation of the given system of equations yields y = 4(-12) + 1, or y = -47. Substituting -12 for x and -47 for y into the expression x - y yields -12 - (-47), or 35."
  },
  {
    "id": 735,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "24x + y = 48, 6x + y = 72 The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of y?",
    "answer": "80",
    "explanation": "Subtracting the second equation in the given system from the first equation yields (24x + y) - (6x + y) = 48 - 72, which is equivalent to 24x - 6x + y - y = -24, or 18x = -24. Dividing each side of this equation by 3 yields 6x = -8. Substituting -8 for 6x in the second equation yields -8 + y = 72. Adding 8 to both sides of this equation yields y = 80. Alternate approach: Multiplying each side of the second equation in the given system by 4 yields 24x + 4y = 288. Subtracting the first equation in the given system from this equation yields (24x + 4y) - (24x + y) = 288 - 48, which is equivalent to 24x - 24x + 4y - y = 240, or 3y = 240. Dividing each side of this equation by 3 yields y = 80."
  },
  {
    "id": 736,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A movie theater sells two types of tickets, adult tickets for $12 and child tickets for $8. If the theater sold 30 tickets for a total of $300, how much, in dollars, was spent on adult tickets? (Disregard the $ sign when gridding your answer.)",
    "answer": "180",
    "explanation": "Let a be the number of adult tickets sold and c be the number of child tickets sold. Since the theater sold a total of 30 tickets, a + c = 30. The price per adult ticket is $12, and the price per child ticket is $8. Since the theater received a total of $300 for the 30 tickets sold, it follows that 12a + 8c = 300. To eliminate c, the first equation can be multiplied by 8 and then subtracted from the second equation: (12a + 8c = 300) - (-8a - 8c = -240) = (4a + 0c = 60) Because the question asks for the amount spent on adult tickets, which is 12a dollars, the resulting equation can be multiplied by 3 to give 3(4a) = 3(60) = 180. Therefore, $180 was spent on adult tickets. Alternate approach: If all the 30 tickets sold were child tickets, their total price would be 30($8) = $240. Since the actual total price of the 30 tickets was $300, the extra $60 indicates that a certain number of adult tickets, a, were sold. Since the price of each adult ticket is $4 more than each child ticket, 4a = 60, and it follows that 12a = 180."
  },
  {
    "id": 737,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "6 + 7r = pw, 7r - 5w = 5w + 11 In the given system of equations, p is a constant. If the system has no solution, what is the value of p?",
    "answer": "10",
    "explanation": "Solving by substitution, the given system of equations, where p is a constant, can be written so that the left-hand side of each equation is equal to 7r. Subtracting 6 from each side of the first equation in the given system, 6 + 7r = pw, yields 7r = pw - 6. Adding 5w to each side of the second equation in the given system, 7r - 5w = 5w + 11, yields 7r = 10w + 11. Since the left-hand side of each equation is equal to 7r, setting the right-hand sides of the equations equal to each other yields pw - 6 = 10w + 11. A linear equation in one variable, w, has no solution if and only if the equation is false; that is, when there's no value of w that produces a true statement. For the equation pw - 6 = 10w + 11, there's no value of w that produces a true statement when pw = 10w. Therefore, for the equation pw - 6 = 10w + 11, there's no value of w that produces a true statement when the value of p is 10. It follows that in the given system of equations, the system has no solution when the value of p is 10."
  },
  {
    "id": 738,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "5x + 14y = 45, 10x + 7y = 27 The solution to the given system of equations is (x, y). What is the value of xy?",
    "answer": "1.8, 9/5",
    "explanation": "Multiplying the first equation in the given system by 2 yields 10x + 28y = 90. Subtracting the second equation in the given system, 10x + 7y = 27, from 10x + 28y = 90 yields (10x + 28y) - (10x + 7y) = 90 - 27, which is equivalent to 10x + 28y - 10x - 7y = 63, or 21y = 63. Dividing both sides of this equation by 21 yields y = 3. The value of x can be found by substituting 3 for y in either of the two given equations. Substituting 3 for y in the equation 10x + 7y = 27 yields 10x + 7(3) = 27, or 10x + 21 = 27. Subtracting 21 from both sides of this equation yields 10x = 6. Dividing both sides of this equation by 10 yields x = 6/10, or x = 3/5. Therefore, the value of xy is (3/5)(3), or 9/5. Note that 9/5 and 1.8 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 739,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "y = (1/2)x + 8, y = cx + 10 In the system of equations above, c is a constant. If the system has no solution, what is the value of c?",
    "answer": "2025-01-02 00:00:00",
    "explanation": "A system of two linear equations has no solution when the graphs of the equations have the same slope and different y-intercepts. Each of the given linear equations is written in the slope-intercept form, y = mx + b, where m is the slope and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the graph of the equation. For these two linear equations, the y-intercepts are (0,8) and (0,10). Thus, if the system of equations has no solution, the slopes of the graphs of the two linear equations must be the same. The slope of the graph of the first linear equation is 1/2. Therefore, for the system of equations to have no solution, the value of c must be 1/2. Note that 1/2 and 0.5 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 740,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "y = 2x + 1, y = ax - 8 In the system of equations above, a is a constant. If the system of equations has no solution, what is the value of a?",
    "answer": "2",
    "explanation": "A system of two linear equations has no solution when the graphs of the equations have the same slope and different y-coordinates of the y-intercepts. Each of the given equations is written in the slope-intercept form of a linear equation, y = mx + b, where m is the slope and b is the y-coordinate of the y-intercept of the graph of the equation. For these two linear equations, the y-coordinates of the y-intercepts are different: 1 and -8. Thus, if the system of equations has no solution, the slopes of the two linear equations must be the same. The slope of the first linear equation is 2. Therefore, for the system of equations to have no solution, the value of a must be 2."
  },
  {
    "id": 741,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "8x + 7y = 9, 24x + 21y = 27 For each real number r, which of the following points lies on the graph of each equation in the xy-plane for the given system?",
    "answer": "(r, -8r/7 + 9/7)",
    "explanation": "Dividing both sides of the second equation in the given system by 3 yields 8x + 7y = 9, which is the first equation in the given system. Therefore, the first and second equations represent the same line in the xy-plane. If the x- and y-coordinates of a point satisfy an equation, the point lies on the graph of the equation in the xy-plane. Choice A is a point with x-coordinate r and y-coordinate -8r/7 + 9/7. Substituting r for x and -8r/7 + 9/7 for y in the equation 8x + 7y = 9 yields 8r + 7(-8r/7 + 9/7) = 9. Applying the distributive property to the left-hand side of this equation yields 8r - 8r + 9 = 9. Combining like terms on the left-hand side of this equation yields 9 = 9, so the coordinates of the point (r, -8r/7 + 9/7) satisfy both equations in the given system. Therefore, for each real number r, the point (r, -8r/7 + 9/7) lies on the graph of each equation in the xy-plane for the given system."
  },
  {
    "id": 742,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "Store A sells raspberries for $5.50 per pint and blackberries for $3.00 per pint. Store B sells raspberries for $6.50 per pint and blackberries for $8.00 per pint. A certain purchase of raspberries and blackberries would cost $37.00 at Store A or $66.00 at Store B. How many pints of blackberries are in this purchase?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "It’s given that store A sells raspberries for $5.50 per pint and blackberries for $3.00 per pint, and a certain purchase of raspberries and blackberries at store A would cost $37.00. It’s also given that store B sells raspberries for $6.50 per pint and blackberries for $8.00 per pint, and this purchase of raspberries and blackberries at store B would cost $66.00. Let r represent the number of pints of raspberries and b represent the number of pints of blackberries in this purchase. The equation 5.50r + 3.00b = 37.00 represents this purchase of raspberries and blackberries from store A and the equation 6.50r + 8.00b = 66.00 represents this purchase of raspberries and blackberries from store B. Solving the system of equations by elimination gives the value of r and the value of b that make the system of equations true. Multiplying both sides of the equation for store A by 6.5 yields (5.50r)(6.5) + (3.00b)(6.5) = (37.00)(6.5), or 35.75r + 19.5b = 240.5. Multiplying both sides of the equation for store B by 5.5 yields (6.50r)(5.5) + (8.00b)(5.5) = (66.00)(5.5), or 35.75r + 44b = 363. Subtracting both sides of the equation for store A, 35.75r + 19.5b = 240.5, from the corresponding sides of the equation for store B, 35.75r + 44b = 363, yields (35.75r - 35.75r) + (44b - 19.5b) = (363 - 240.5), or 24.5b = 122.5. Dividing both sides of this equation by 24.5 yields b = 5. Thus, 5 pints of blackberries are in this purchase. ​"
  },
  {
    "id": 743,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "2x + 6y = 10 The system has no solution. Which of the following could be the other equation in the system?",
    "answer": "x + 3y = -20",
    "explanation": "A system of two linear equations written in standard form has no solution when the equations are distinct and the ratio of the x-coefficient to the y-coefficient for one equation is equivalent to the ratio of the x-coefficient to the y-coefficient for the other equation. This ratio for the given equation is 2 to 6, or 1 to 3. Only choice B is an equation that isn’t equivalent to the given equation and whose ratio of the x-coefficient to the y-coefficient is 1 to 3."
  },
  {
    "id": 744,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "A piece of wire with a length of 32 inches is cut into two parts. One part has a length of x inches, and the other part has a length of y inches. The value of x is 4 more than 3 times the value of y. What is the value of x?",
    "answer": "25",
    "explanation": "It’s given that a piece of wire has a length of 32 inches and is cut into two parts. It’s also given that one part has a length of x inches and the other part has a length of y inches. It follows that the equation x + y = 32 represents this situation. It’s also given that the value of x is 4 more than 3 times the value of y, or x = 3y + 4. Substituting 3y + 4 for x in the equation x + y = 32 yields 3y + 4 + y = 32. Combining like terms on the left-hand side of this equation yields 4y + 4 = 32. Subtracting 4 from both sides of this equation yields 4y = 28. Dividing both sides of this equation by 4 yields y = 7. Substituting 7 for y in the equation x = 3y + 4 yields x = 3(7) + 4, or x = 25. Therefore, the value of x is 25."
  },
  {
    "id": 745,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "4x - 9y = 9y + 5, hy = 2 + 4x In the given system of equations, h is a constant. If the system has no solution, what is the value of h?",
    "answer": "18",
    "explanation": "A system of two linear equations in two variables, x and y, has no solution if the lines represented by the equations in the xy-plane are distinct and parallel. The graphs of two lines in the xy-plane represented by equations in the form Ax + By = C, where A, B, and C are constants, are parallel if the coefficients for x and y in one equation are proportional to the corresponding coefficients in the other equation. The first equation in the given system can be written in the form Ax + By = C by subtracting 9y from both sides of the equation to yield 4x - 18y = 5. The second equation in the given system can be written in the form Ax + By = C by subtracting 4x from both sides of the equation to yield -4x + hy = 2. The coefficient of x in this second equation, -4, is -1 times the coefficient of x in the first equation, 4. For the lines to be parallel, the coefficient of y in the second equation, h, must also be -1 times the coefficient of y in the first equation, -18. Thus, h = -1(-18), or h = 18. Therefore, if the given system has no solution, the value of h is 18."
  },
  {
    "id": 746,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "7/8 y - 5/8 x = 4/7 - 7/8 y, 5/4 x + 7/4 = py + 15/4 In the given system of equations, p is a constant. If the system has no solution, what is the value of p?",
    "answer": "3.5, 7/2",
    "explanation": "A system of two linear equations in two variables, x and y, has no solution if the lines represented by the equations in the xy-plane are distinct and parallel. Two lines represented by equations in standard form Ax + By = C, where A, B, and C are constants, are parallel if the coefficients for x and y in one equation are proportional to the corresponding coefficients in the other equation. The first equation in the given system, 7/8 y - 5/8 x = 4/7 - 7/8 y, can be written in standard form by adding 7/8 y to both sides of the equation, which yields 14/8 y - 5/8 x = 4/7, or -5/8 x + 14/8 y = 4/7. Multiplying each term in this equation by -8 yields 5x - 14y = -32/7. The second equation in the given system, 5/4 x - py = 8/4, can be written in standard form by subtracting 7/4 and py from both sides of the equation, which yields 5/4 x - py = 8/4. Multiplying each term in this equation by 4 yields 5x - 4py = 8. The coefficient of x in the first equation, 5x - 14y = -32/7, is equal to the coefficient of x in the second equation, 5x - 4py = 8. For the lines to be parallel, and for the coefficients for x and y in one equation to be proportional to the corresponding coefficients in the other equation, the coefficient of y in the second equation must also be equal to the coefficient of y in the first equation. Therefore, -14 = -4p. Dividing both sides of this equation by -4 yields -14/-4 = p, or p = 7/2. Therefore, if the given system of equations has no solution, the value of p is 7/2. Note that 7/2 and 3.5 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 747,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "5y=10x+11,-5y=5x-21The solution to the given system of equations is(x,y).What is the value of 30x?",
    "answer": "20",
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 20. Adding the first equation to the second equation in the given system yields 5y-5y=10x+5x+11-21,or 0=15x-10. Adding 10 to both sides of this equation yields 10=15x. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 2 yields 20=30x. Therefore, the value of 30x is 20."
  },
  {
    "id": 748,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "y=6x+18 One of the equations in a system of two linear equations is given.The system has no solution.Which equation could be the second equation in the system?",
    "answer": "-6x+y=22",
    "explanation": "A system of two linear equations in two variables,x and y,has no solution if the lines represented by the equations in the xy-plane are parallel and distinct. Lines represented by equations in standard form,Ax+By=C and Dx+Ey=F,are parallel if the coefficients for x and y in one equation are proportional to the corresponding coefficients in the other equation,meaning D/A=E/B,and the lines are distinct if the constants are not proportional,meaning F/C≠D/A. The given equation,y=6x+18,can be written in standard form by subtracting 6x from both sides of the equation to yield -6x+y=18.Therefore,the given equation can be written in the form Ax+By=C,where A=-6,B=1,and C=18. The equation in choice B,-6x+y=22,is written in the form Dx+Ey=F,where D=-6,E=1,and F=22. Therefore,D/A=-6/-6=1,which can be rewritten as D/A=1,E/B=1,and F/C=22/18=11/9. Since D/A=1,E/B=1,but F/C≠1,it follows that a system of two linear equations consisting of the given equation and the equation -6x+y=22 are parallel and distinct.Therefore,the equation in choice B could be the second equation in the system."
  },
  {
    "id": 749,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "2x+3y=7,10x+15y=35 For each real number r,which of the following points lies on the graph of each equation in the xy-plane for the given system?",
    "answer": "(-3r/2+7/2,r)",
    "explanation": "The two given equations are equivalent because the second equation can be obtained from the first equation by multiplying each side of the equation by 5. Thus,the graphs of the equations are coincident,so if a point lies on the graph of one of the equations,it also lies on the graph of the other equation. A point(x,y)lies on the graph of an equation in the xy-plane if and only if this point represents a solution to the equation. It is sufficient,therefore,to find the point that represents a solution to the first given equation. Substituting the x-and y-coordinates of choice B,-3r/2+7/2,r,for x and y,respectively,in the first equation yields 2(-3r/2+7/2)+3r=7,which is equivalent to -3r+7+3r=7. Therefore,the point (-3r/2+7/2,r)represents a solution to the first equation and thus lies on the graph of each equation in the xy-plane for the given system."
  },
  {
    "id": 750,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Systems of two linear equations in two variables",
    "question": "(x-2)-4(y+7)=117,(x-2)+4(y+7)=442The solution to the given system of equations is(x,y).What is the value of 6(x-2)?",
    "answer": "1677",
    "explanation": "Adding the first equation to the second equation in the given system yields (x-2)+(x-2)+(-4)(y+7)+4(y+7)=117+442,or 2(x-2)=559. Multiplying both sides of this equation by 3 yields 6(x-2)=1677. Therefore,the value of 6(x-2) is 1677."
  },
  {
    "id": 751,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "The point (8, 2) in the xy-plane is a solution to which of the following systems of inequalities?",
    "answer": "x > 0, y > 0",
    "explanation": "The given point, (8, 2), is located in the first quadrant in the xy-plane. The system of inequalities in choice A represents all the points in the first quadrant in the xy-plane. Therefore, (8, 2) is a solution to the system of inequalities in choice A. Substituting 8 for x in the first inequality in choice A, x > 0, yields 8 > 0, which is true. Substituting 2 for y in the second inequality in choice A, y > 0, yields 2 > 0, which is true. Since the coordinates of the point (8, 2) make the inequalities x > 0 and y > 0 true, the point (8, 2) is a solution to the system of inequalities consisting of x > 0 and y > 0."
  },
  {
    "id": 752,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "During a portion of a flight, a small airplane's cruising speed varied between 150 miles per hour and 170 miles per hour. Which inequality best represents this situation, where s is the cruising speed, in miles per hour, during this portion of the flight?",
    "answer": "150 ≤ s ≤ 170",
    "explanation": "It's given that during a portion of a flight, a small airplane's cruising speed varied between 150 miles per hour and 170 miles per hour. It's also given that s represents the cruising speed, in miles per hour, during this portion of the flight. It follows that the airplane's cruising speed, in miles per hour, was at least 150, which means s ≥ 150, and was at most 170, which means s ≤ 170. Therefore, the inequality that best represents this situation is 150 ≤ s ≤ 170."
  },
  {
    "id": 753,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "Valentina bought two containers of beads. In the first container, 30% of the beads are red, and in the second container, 70% of the beads are red. Together, the containers have at least 400 red beads. Which inequality shows this relationship, where x is the total number of beads in the first container and y is the total number of beads in the second container?",
    "answer": "0.3x + 0.7y ≥ 400",
    "explanation": "It is given that x is the total number of beads in the first container and that 30% of those beads are red; therefore, the expression 0.3x represents the number of red beads in the first container. It is given that y is the total number of beads in the second container and that 70% of those beads are red; therefore, the expression 0.7y represents the number of red beads in the second container. It is also given that, together, the containers have at least 400 red beads, so the inequality that shows this relationship is 0.3x + 0.7y ≥ 400."
  },
  {
    "id": 754,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "Ty set a goal to walk at least 24 kilometers every day to prepare for a multiday hike. On a certain day, Ty plans to walk at an average speed of 4 kilometers per hour. What is the minimum number of hours Ty must walk on that day to fulfill the daily goal?",
    "answer": "6",
    "explanation": "It's given that Ty plans to walk at an average speed of 4 kilometers per hour. The number of kilometers Ty will walk is determined by the expression 4s, where s is the number of hours Ty walks. The given goal of at least 24 kilometers means that the inequality 4s ≥ 24 represents the situation. Dividing both sides of this inequality by 4 gives s ≥ 6, which corresponds to a minimum of 6 hours Ty must walk."
  },
  {
    "id": 755,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A bakery sells trays of cookies. Each tray contains at least 50 cookies but no more than 60. Which of the following could be the total number of cookies on 4 trays of cookies?",
    "answer": "205",
    "explanation": "If each tray contains the least number of cookies possible, 50 cookies, then the least number of cookies possible on 4 trays is 50 × 4 = 200 cookies. If each tray contains the greatest number of cookies possible, 60 cookies, then the greatest number of cookies possible on 4 trays is 60 × 4 = 240 cookies. If the least number of cookies on 4 trays is 200 and the greatest number of cookies is 240, then 205 could be the total number of cookies on these 4 trays of cookies because 200 ≤ 205 ≤ 240."
  },
  {
    "id": 756,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "On a car trip, Rhett and Jessica each drove for part of the trip, and the total distance they drove was under 220 miles. Rhett drove at an average speed of 35 miles per hour (mph), and Jessica drove at an average speed of 40 mph. Which of the following inequalities represents this situation, where r is the number of hours Rhett drove and j is the number of hours Jessica drove?",
    "answer": "35r + 40j < 220",
    "explanation": "It's given that Rhett drove at an average speed of 35 miles per hour and that he drove for r hours. Multiplying 35 miles per hour by r hours yields 35r miles, or the distance that Rhett drove. It’s also given that Jessica drove at an average speed of 40 miles per hour and that she drove for j hours. Multiplying 40 miles per hour by j hours yields 40j miles, or the distance that Jessica drove. The total distance, in miles, that Rhett and Jessica drove can be represented by the expression 35r + 40j. It's given that the total distance they drove was under 220 miles. Therefore, the inequality 35r + 40j < 220 represents this situation."
  },
  {
    "id": 757,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "The total cost, in dollars, to rent a surfboard consists of a $25 service fee and a $10 per hour rental fee. A person rents a surfboard for t hours and intends to spend a maximum of $75 to rent the surfboard. Which inequality represents this situation?",
    "answer": "25 + 10t ≤ 75",
    "explanation": "The cost of the rental fee depends on the number of hours the surfboard is rented. Multiplying t hours by 10 dollars per hour yields a rental fee of 10t dollars. The total cost of the rental consists of the rental fee plus the 25-dollar service fee, which yields a total cost of 25 + 10t dollars. Since the person intends to spend a maximum of 75 dollars to rent the surfboard, the total cost must be at most 75 dollars. Therefore, the inequality 25 + 10t ≤ 75 represents this situation."
  },
  {
    "id": 758,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "For a party, 50 dinner rolls are needed. Dinner rolls are sold in packages of 12. What is the minimum number of packages that should be bought for the party?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Let p represent the number of packages of dinner rolls that should be bought for the party. It's given that dinner rolls are sold in packages of 12. Therefore, 12p represents the number of dinner rolls that should be bought for the party. It's also given that 50 dinner rolls are needed; therefore, 12p ≥ 50. Dividing both sides of this inequality by 12 yields p ≥ 50/12, or approximately p ≥ 4.17. Since the number of packages of dinner rolls must be a whole number, the minimum number of packages that should be bought for the party is 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 759,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "During spring migration, a dragonfly traveled a minimum of 1,510 miles and a maximum of 4,130 miles between stopover locations. Which inequality represents this situation, where d is a possible distance, in miles, this dragonfly traveled between stopover locations during spring migration?",
    "answer": "1,510 ≤ d ≤ 4,130",
    "explanation": "It's given that during spring migration, a dragonfly traveled a minimum of 1,510 miles and a maximum of 4,130 miles between stopover locations. It's also given that d represents a possible distance, in miles, this dragonfly traveled between stopover locations. It follows that the inequality 1,510 ≤ d ≤ 4,130 represents this situation."
  },
  {
    "id": 760,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "Tom scored 85, 78, and 98 on his first three exams in history class. Solving which inequality gives the score, G, on Tom’s fourth exam that will result in a mean score on all four exams of at least 90?",
    "answer": "(G + 85 + 78 + 98) / 4 ≥ 90",
    "explanation": "The mean of the four scores (G, 85, 78, and 98) can be expressed as (G + 85 + 78 + 98) / 4. The inequality that expresses the condition that the mean score is at least 90 can therefore be written as (G + 85 + 78 + 98) / 4 ≥ 90."
  },
  {
    "id": 761,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A geologist needs to collect at least 67 samples of lava from a volcano. If the geologist has already collected 63 samples from the volcano, what is the minimum number of additional samples the geologist needs to collect?",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "It's given that the geologist has already collected 63 samples from the volcano. Let x represent the number of additional samples the geologist needs to collect. After collecting x additional samples, the geologist will have collected a total of 63 + x samples. It's given that the geologist needs to collect at least 67 samples. Therefore, 63 + x ≥ 67. Subtracting 63 from each side of this inequality yields the inequality x ≥ 4. Thus, the geologist needs to collect a minimum of 4 additional samples."
  },
  {
    "id": 762,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "An elementary school teacher is ordering x workbooks and y sets of flash cards for a math class. The teacher must order at least 20 items, but the total cost of the order must not be over $80. If the workbooks cost $3 each and the flash cards cost $4 per set, which of the following systems of inequalities models this situation?",
    "answer": "x + y ≥ 20, 3x + 4y ≤ 80",
    "explanation": "The total number of workbooks and sets of flash cards ordered is represented by x + y. Since the teacher must order at least 20 items, it must be true that x + y ≥ 20. Each workbook costs $3; therefore, 3x represents the cost, in dollars, of x workbooks. Each set of flashcards costs $4; therefore, 4y represents the cost, in dollars, of y sets of flashcards. It follows that the total cost for x workbooks and y sets of flashcards is 3x + 4y. Since the total cost of the order must not be over $80, it must also be true that 3x + 4y ≤ 80. Of the choices given, these inequalities are shown only in choice A."
  },
  {
    "id": 763,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A clothing store is having a sale on shirts and pants. During the sale, the cost of each shirt is $15 and the cost of each pair of pants is $25. Geoff can spend at most $120 at the store. If Geoff buys s shirts and p pairs of pants, which of the following must be true?",
    "answer": "15s + 25p ≤ 120",
    "explanation": "Since the cost of each shirt is $15 and Geoff buys s shirts, the expression 15s represents the amount Geoff spends on shirts. Since the cost of each pair of pants is $25 and Geoff buys p pairs of pants, the expression 25p represents the amount Geoff spends on pants. Therefore, the sum 15s + 25p represents the total amount Geoff spends at the store. Since Geoff can spend at most $120 at the store, the total amount he spends must be less than or equal to 120. Thus, 15s + 25p ≤ 120."
  },
  {
    "id": 764,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "Normal body temperature for an adult is between 97.8°F and 99°F, inclusive. If Kevin, an adult male, has a body temperature that is considered to be normal, which of the following could be his body temperature?",
    "answer": "97.9°F",
    "explanation": "Normal body temperature must be greater than or equal to 97.8°F but less than or equal to 99°F. Of the given choices, 97.9°F is the only temperature that fits these restrictions. ​"
  },
  {
    "id": 765,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A cleaning service that cleans both offices and homes can clean at most 14 places per day. Which inequality represents this situation, where f is the number of offices and h is the number of homes?",
    "answer": "f + h ≤ 14",
    "explanation": "It's given that the cleaning service cleans both offices and homes, where f is the number of offices and h is the number of homes the cleaning service can clean per day. Therefore, the expression f + h represents the number of places the cleaning service can clean per day. It's also given that the cleaning service can clean at most 14 places per day. Since f + h represents the number of places the cleaning service can clean per day and the service can clean at most 14 places per day, it follows that the inequality f + h ≤ 14 represents this situation."
  },
  {
    "id": 766,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "Monarch butterflies can fly only with a body temperature of at least 55.0 degrees Fahrenheit (°F). If a monarch butterfly's body temperature is 51.3°F, what is the minimum increase needed in its body temperature, in °F, so that it can fly?",
    "answer": "3.7",
    "explanation": "It's given that monarch butterflies can fly only with a body temperature of at least 55.0 degrees Fahrenheit (°F). Let x represent the minimum increase needed in the monarch butterfly's body temperature to fly. If the monarch butterfly's body temperature is 51.3°F, the inequality 51.3 + x ≥ 55.0 represents this situation. Subtracting 51.3 from both sides of this inequality yields x ≥ 3.7. Therefore, if the monarch butterfly's body temperature is 51.3°F, the minimum increase needed in its body temperature, in °F, so that it can fly is 3.7."
  },
  {
    "id": 767,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "Maria plans to rent a boat. The boat rental costs $60 per hour, and she will also have to pay for a water safety course that costs $10. Maria wants to spend no more than $280 for the rental and the course. If the boat rental is available only for a whole number of hours, what is the maximum number of hours for which Maria can rent the boat?",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "The equation 60h + 10 ≤ 280, where h is the number of hours the boat has been rented, can be written to represent the situation. Subtracting 10 from both sides and then dividing by 60 yields h ≤ 4.5. Since the boat can be rented only for whole numbers of hours, the maximum number of hours for which Maria can rent the boat is 4."
  },
  {
    "id": 768,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A cargo helicopter delivers only 100-pound packages and 120-pound packages. For each delivery trip, the helicopter must carry at least 10 packages, and the total weight of the packages can be at most 1,100 pounds. What is the maximum number of 120-pound packages that the helicopter can carry per trip?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Let a equal the number of 120-pound packages, and let b equal the number of 100-pound packages. It’s given that the total weight of the packages can be at most 1,100 pounds: the inequality 120a + 100b ≤ 1,100 represents this situation. It’s also given that the helicopter must carry at least 10 packages: the inequality a + b ≥ 10 represents this situation. Values of a and b that satisfy these two inequalities represent the allowable numbers of 120-pound packages and 100-pound packages the helicopter can transport. To maximize the number of 120-pound packages, a, in the helicopter, the number of 100-pound packages, b, in the helicopter needs to be minimized. Expressing b in terms of a in the second inequality yields b ≥ 10 - a, so the minimum value of b is equal to 10 - a. Substituting 10 - a for b in the first inequality results in 120a + 100(10 - a) ≤ 1,100. Using the distributive property to rewrite this inequality yields 120a + 1,000 - 100a ≤ 1,100, or 20a + 1,000 ≤ 1,100. Subtracting 1,000 from both sides of this inequality yields 20a ≤ 100. Dividing both sides of this inequality by 20 results in a ≤ 5. This means that the maximum number of 120-pound packages that the helicopter can carry per trip is 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 769,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "Marisa needs to hire at least 10 staff members for an upcoming project. The staff members will be made up of junior directors, who will be paid $640 per week, and senior directors, who will be paid $880 per week. Her budget for paying the staff members is no more than $9,700 per week. She must hire at least 3 junior directors and at least 1 senior director. Which of the following systems of inequalities represents the conditions described if x is the number of junior directors and y is the number of senior directors?",
    "answer": "640x + 880y ≤ 9,700, x + y ≥ 10, x ≥ 3, y ≥ 1",
    "explanation": "Marisa will hire x junior directors and y senior directors. Since she needs to hire at least 10 staff members, x + y ≥ 10. Each junior director will be paid $640 per week, and each senior director will be paid $880 per week. Marisa’s budget for paying the new staff is no more than $9,700 per week; in terms of x and y, this condition is 640x + 880y ≤ 9,700. Since Marisa must hire at least 3 junior directors and at least 1 senior director, it follows that x ≥ 3 and y ≥ 1. All four of these conditions are represented correctly in choice B."
  },
  {
    "id": 770,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "For a snowstorm in a certain town, the minimum rate of snowfall recorded was 0.6 inches per hour, and the maximum rate of snowfall recorded was 1.8 inches per hour. Which inequality is true for all values of s, where s represents a rate of snowfall, in inches per hour, recorded for this snowstorm?",
    "answer": "0.6 ≤ s ≤ 1.8",
    "explanation": "It's given that for a snowstorm in a certain town, the minimum rate of snowfall recorded was 0.6 inches per hour, the maximum rate of snowfall recorded was 1.8 inches per hour, and s represents a rate of snowfall, in inches per hour, recorded for this snowstorm. It follows that the inequality 0.6 ≤ s ≤ 1.8 is true for all values of s."
  },
  {
    "id": 771,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "y < -4x + 4 Which point (x, y) is a solution to the given inequality in the xy-plane?",
    "answer": "(-4, 0)",
    "explanation": "For a point (x, y) to be a solution to the given inequality in the xy-plane, the value of the point’s y-coordinate must be less than the value of -4x + 4, where x is the value of the x-coordinate of the point. This is true of the point (-4, 0) because 0 < -4(-4) + 4, or 0 < 20. Therefore, the point (-4, 0) is a solution to the given inequality."
  },
  {
    "id": 772,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A truck can haul a maximum weight of 5,630 pounds. During one trip, the truck will be used to haul a 190-pound piece of equipment as well as several crates. Some of these crates weigh 25 pounds each and the others weigh 62 pounds each. Which inequality represents the possible combinations of the number of 25-pound crates, x, and the number of 62-pound crates, y, the truck can haul during one trip if only the piece of equipment and the crates are being hauled?",
    "answer": "25x + 62y ≤ 5,440",
    "explanation": "It's given that a truck can haul a maximum of 5,630 pounds. It's also given that during one trip, the truck will be used to haul a 190-pound piece of equipment as well as several crates. It follows that the truck can haul at most 5,630 - 190, or 5,440, pounds of crates. Since x represents the number of 25-pound crates, the expression 25x represents the weight of the 25-pound crates. Since y represents the number of 62-pound crates, 62y represents the weight of the 62-pound crates. Therefore, 25x + 62y represents the total weight of the crates the truck can haul. Since the truck can haul at most 5,440 pounds of crates, the total weight of the crates must be less than or equal to 5,440 pounds, or 25x + 62y ≤ 5,440."
  },
  {
    "id": 773,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "y ≤ x and y ≤ -x Which of the following ordered pairs (x, y) is a solution to the system of inequalities above?",
    "answer": "(0,-1)",
    "explanation": "The solutions to the given system of inequalities is the set of all ordered pairs (x, y) that satisfy both inequalities in the system. For an ordered pair to satisfy the inequality y ≤ x, the value of the ordered pair’s y-coordinate must be less than or equal to the value of the ordered pair’s x-coordinate. This is true of the ordered pair (0, -1), because -1 ≤ 0. To satisfy the inequality y ≤ -x, the value of the ordered pair’s y-coordinate must be less than or equal to the value of the additive inverse of the ordered pair’s x-coordinate. This is also true of the ordered pair (0, -1). Because 0 is its own additive inverse, -1 ≤ -0 is the same as -1 ≤ 0. Therefore, the ordered pair (0, -1) is a solution to the given system of inequalities."
  },
  {
    "id": 774,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "In North America, the standard width of a parking space is at least 7.5 feet and no more than 9.0 feet. A restaurant owner recently resurfaced the restaurant’s parking lot and wants to determine the number of parking spaces, n, in the parking lot that could be placed perpendicular to a curb that is 135 feet long, based on the standard width of a parking space. Which of the following describes all the possible values of n?",
    "answer": "15 ≤ n ≤ 18",
    "explanation": "Placing the parking spaces with the minimum width of 7.5 feet gives the maximum possible number of parking spaces. Thus, the maximum number that can be placed perpendicular to a 135-foot-long curb is 135 ÷ 7.5 = 18. Placing the parking spaces with the maximum width of 9 feet gives the minimum number of parking spaces. Thus, the minimum number that can be placed perpendicular to a 135-foot-long curb is 135 ÷ 9 = 15. Therefore, if n is the number of parking spaces in the lot, the range of possible values for n is 15 ≤ n ≤ 18."
  },
  {
    "id": 775,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A certain elephant weighs 200 pounds at birth and gains more than 2 but less than 3 pounds per day during its first year. Which of the following inequalities represents all possible weights w, in pounds, for the elephant 365 days after birth?",
    "answer": "930 < w < 1,295",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the elephant weighs 200 pounds at birth and gains more than 2 pounds but less than 3 pounds per day during its first year. The inequality 200 + 2d < w < 200 + 3d represents this situation, where d is the number of days after birth. Substituting 365 for d in the inequality gives 200 + 2(365) < w < 200 + 3(365), or 930 < w < 1,295."
  },
  {
    "id": 776,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "The Karvonen formula above shows the relationship between Alice’s target heart rate H, in beats per minute (bpm), and the intensity level p of different activities. When p = 0, Alice has a resting heart rate. When p = 1, Alice has her maximum heart rate. It is recommended that p be between 0.5 and 0.85 for Alice when she trains. Which of the following inequalities describes Alice’s target training heart rate?",
    "answer": "120 ≤ H ≤ 162",
    "explanation": "When Alice trains, it’s recommended that p be between 0.5 and 0.85. Therefore, her target training heart rate is represented by the values of H corresponding to 0.5 ≤ p ≤ 0.85. When p = 0.5, H = 120(0.5) + 60, or H = 120. When p = 0.85, H = 120(0.85) + 60, or H = 162. Therefore, the inequality that describes Alice’s target training heart rate is 120 ≤ H ≤ 162."
  },
  {
    "id": 777,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A number x is at most 17 less than 5 times the value of y. If the value of y is 3, what is the greatest possible value of x?",
    "answer": "-2",
    "explanation": "It's given that a number x is at most 17 less than 5 times the value of y, or x ≤ 5y - 17. Substituting 3 for y in this inequality yields x ≤ 5(3) - 17, or x ≤ -2. Thus, if the value of y is 3, the greatest possible value of x is -2."
  },
  {
    "id": 778,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "The point (x, 53) is a solution to the system of inequalities in the xy-plane. Which of the following could be the value of x?",
    "answer": "-9",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the point (x, 53) is a solution to the given system of inequalities in the xy-plane. This means that the coordinates of the point, when substituted for the variables x and y, make both of the inequalities in the system true. Substituting 53 for y in the inequality y > 14 yields 53 > 14, which is true. Substituting 53 for y in the inequality 4x + y < 18 yields 4x + 53 < 18. Subtracting 53 from both sides of this inequality yields 4x < -35. Dividing both sides of this inequality by 4 yields x < -8.75. Therefore, x must be a value less than -8.75. Of the given choices, only -9 is less than -8.75."
  },
  {
    "id": 779,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "For a party, 50 dinner rolls are needed. Dinner rolls are sold in packages of 12. What is the minimum number of packages that should be bought for the party?",
    "answer": "5",
    "explanation": "Let p represent the number of packages of dinner rolls that should be bought for the party. It's given that dinner rolls are sold in packages of 12. Therefore, 12p represents the number of dinner rolls that should be bought for the party. It's also given that 50 dinner rolls are needed; therefore, 12p ≥ 50. Dividing both sides of this inequality by 12 yields p ≥ 50/12, or approximately p ≥ 4.17. Since the number of packages of dinner rolls must be a whole number, the minimum number of packages that should be bought for the party is 5."
  },
  {
    "id": 780,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "During spring migration, a dragonfly traveled a minimum of 1,510 miles and a maximum of 4,130 miles between stopover locations. Which inequality represents this situation, where d is a possible distance, in miles, this dragonfly traveled between stopover locations during spring migration?",
    "answer": "1,510 ≤ d ≤ 4,130",
    "explanation": "It's given that during spring migration, a dragonfly traveled a minimum of 1,510 miles and a maximum of 4,130 miles between stopover locations. It's also given that d represents a possible distance, in miles, this dragonfly traveled between stopover locations. It follows that the inequality 1,510 ≤ d ≤ 4,130 represents this situation."
  },
  {
    "id": 781,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "Tom scored 85, 78, and 98 on his first three exams in history class. Solving which inequality gives the score, G, on Tom’s fourth exam that will result in a mean score on all four exams of at least 90?",
    "answer": "(G + 85 + 78 + 98) / 4 ≥ 90",
    "explanation": "The mean of the four scores (G, 85, 78, and 98) can be expressed as: (G + 85 + 78 + 98) ÷ 4 The inequality that expresses the condition that the mean score is at least 90 can therefore be written as: (G + 85 + 78 + 98) ÷ 4 ≥ 90"
  },
  {
    "id": 782,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A geologist needs to collect at least 67 samples of lava from a volcano. If the geologist has already collected 63 samples from the volcano, what is the minimum number of additional samples the geologist needs to collect?",
    "answer": "4",
    "explanation": "It's given that the geologist has already collected 63 samples from the volcano. Let x represent the number of additional samples the geologist needs to collect. After collecting x additional samples, the geologist will have collected a total of 63 + x samples. It's given that the geologist needs to collect at least 67 samples. Therefore, 63 + x ≥ 67. Subtracting 63 from each side of this inequality yields x ≥ 4. Thus, the geologist needs to collect a minimum of 4 additional samples."
  },
  {
    "id": 783,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "y ≤ 3x + 1, x - y > 1 Which of the following ordered pairs (x, y) satisfies the system of inequalities above?",
    "answer": "(2, -1)",
    "explanation": "Any point (x, y) that is a solution to the given system of inequalities must satisfy both inequalities in the system. The second inequality in the system can be rewritten as x > y + 1. Of the given answer choices, only choice D satisfies this inequality, because inequality 2 > -1 + 1 is a true statement. The point (2, -1) also satisfies the first inequality. Alternate approach: Substituting (2, -1) into the first inequality gives -1 ≤ 3(2) + 1, or -1 ≤ 7, which is a true statement. Substituting (2, -1) into the second inequality gives 2 - (-1) > 1, or 3 > 1, which is a true statement. Therefore, since (2, -1) satisfies both inequalities, it is a solution to the system."
  },
  {
    "id": 784,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "The minimum value of x is 12 less than 6 times another number n. Which inequality shows the possible values of x?",
    "answer": "x ≥ 6n - 12",
    "explanation": "It’s given that the minimum value of x is 12 less than 6 times another number n. Therefore, the possible values of x are all greater than or equal to the value of 12 less than 6 times n. The value of 6 times n is given by the expression 6n. The value of 12 less than 6n is given by the expression 6n - 12. Therefore, the possible values of x are all greater than or equal to 6n - 12. This can be shown by the inequality x ≥ 6n - 12."
  },
  {
    "id": 785,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "The average annual energy cost for a certain home is 4,334 dollars. The homeowner plans to spend 25,000 dollars to install a geothermal heating system. The homeowner estimates that the average annual energy cost will then be 2,712 dollars. Which of the following inequalities can be solved to find t, the number of years after installation at which the total amount of energy cost savings will exceed the installation cost?",
    "answer": "25,000 < (4,334 - 2,712)t",
    "explanation": "The savings each year from installing the geothermal heating system will be the average annual energy cost for the home before the geothermal heating system installation minus the average annual energy cost after the geothermal heating system installation, which is (4,334 - 2,712) dollars. In t years, the savings will be (4,334 - 2,712)t dollars. Therefore, the inequality that can be solved to find the number of years after installation at which the total amount of energy cost savings will exceed (be greater than) the installation cost, 25,000 dollars, is 25,000 < (4,334 - 2,712)t."
  },
  {
    "id": 786,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A local transit company sells a monthly pass for $95 that allows an unlimited number of trips of any length. Tickets for individual trips cost $1.50, $2.50, or $3.50, depending on the length of the trip. What is the minimum number of trips per month for which a monthly pass could cost less than purchasing individual tickets for trips?",
    "answer": "28",
    "explanation": "The minimum number of individual trips for which the cost of the monthly pass is less than the cost of individual tickets can be found by assuming the maximum cost of the individual tickets, $3.50. If n tickets costing $3.50 each are purchased in one month, the inequality 95 < 3.50n represents this situation. Dividing both sides of the inequality by 3.50 yields 27.14 < n, which is equivalent to n > 27.14. Since only a whole number of tickets can be purchased, it follows that 28 is the minimum number of trips."
  },
  {
    "id": 787,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A laundry service is buying detergent and fabric softener from its supplier. The supplier will deliver no more than 300 pounds in a shipment. Each container of detergent weighs 7.35 pounds, and each container of fabric softener weighs 6.2 pounds. The service wants to buy at least twice as many containers of detergent as containers of fabric softener. Let d represent the number of containers of detergent, and let s represent the number of containers of fabric softener, where d and s are nonnegative integers. Which of the following systems of inequalities best represents this situation?",
    "answer": "7.35d + 6.2s ≤ 300, d ≥ 2s",
    "explanation": "The number of containers in a shipment must have a weight less than or equal to 300 pounds. The total weight, in pounds, of detergent and fabric softener that the supplier delivers can be expressed as the weight of each container multiplied by the number of each type of container, which is 7.35d + 6.2s. Since this total cannot exceed 300 pounds, it follows that 7.35d + 6.2s ≤ 300. Also, since the laundry service wants to buy at least twice as many containers of detergent as containers of fabric softener, the number of containers of detergent should be greater than or equal to two times the number of containers of fabric softener. This can be expressed by the inequality d ≥ 2s."
  },
  {
    "id": 788,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "Adam’s school is a 20-minute walk or a 5-minute bus ride away from his house. The bus runs once every 30 minutes, and the number of minutes, w, that Adam waits for the bus varies between 0 and 30. Which of the following inequalities gives the values of w for which it would be faster for Adam to walk to school?",
    "answer": "w + 5 > 20",
    "explanation": "It is given that w is the number of minutes that Adam waits for the bus. The total time it takes Adam to get to school on a day he takes the bus is the sum of the minutes, w, he waits for the bus and the 5 minutes the bus ride takes; thus, this time, in minutes, is w + 5. It is also given that the total amount of time it takes Adam to get to school on a day that he walks is 20 minutes. Therefore, w + 5 > 20 gives the values of w for which it would be faster for Adam to walk to school."
  },
  {
    "id": 789,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "y ≤ x + 7, y ≥ -2x - 1 Which point (x, y) is a solution to the given system of inequalities in the xy-plane?",
    "answer": "(14, 0)",
    "explanation": "A point (x, y) is a solution to a system of inequalities in the xy-plane if substituting the x-coordinate and the y-coordinate of the point for x and y, respectively, in each inequality makes both of the inequalities true. Substituting the x-coordinate and the y-coordinate of choice D, 14 and 0, for x and y, respectively, in the first inequality in the given system, y ≤ x + 7, yields 0 ≤ 14 + 7, or 0 ≤ 21, which is true. Substituting 14 for x and 0 for y in the second inequality in the given system, y ≥ -2x - 1, yields 0 ≥ -2(14) - 1, or 0 ≥ -29, which is true. Therefore, the point (14, 0) is a solution to the given system of inequalities in the xy-plane."
  },
  {
    "id": 790,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A number x is at most 2 less than 3 times the value of y. If the value of y is -4, what is the greatest possible value of x?",
    "answer": "-14",
    "explanation": "The correct answer is -14. It's given that a number x is at most 2 less than 3 times the value of y. Therefore, x is less than or equal to 2 less than 3 times the value of y. The expression 3y represents 3 times the value of y. The expression 3y - 2 represents 2 less than 3 times the value of y. Therefore, x is less than or equal to 3y - 2. This can be shown by the inequality x ≤ 3y - 2. Substituting y = -4 in this inequality yields x ≤ 3(-4) - 2, or x ≤ -14. Therefore, if the value of y is -4, the greatest possible value of x is -14."
  },
  {
    "id": 791,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A salesperson’s total earnings consist of a base salary of x dollars per year, plus commission earnings of 11% of the total sales the salesperson makes during the year. This year, the salesperson has a goal for the total earnings to be at least 3 times and at most 4 times the base salary. Which of the following inequalities represents all possible values of total sales s, in dollars, the salesperson can make this year in order to meet that goal?",
    "answer": "(2/0.11)x ≤ s ≤ (3/0.11)x",
    "explanation": "It’s given that a salesperson's total earnings consist of a base salary of x dollars per year plus commission earnings of 11% of the total sales the salesperson makes during the year. If the salesperson makes s dollars in total sales this year, the salesperson’s total earnings can be represented by the expression x + 0.11s. It’s also given that the salesperson has a goal for the total earnings to be at least 3 times and at most 4 times the base salary, which can be represented by the expressions 3x and 4x, respectively. Therefore, this situation can be represented by the inequality 3x ≤ x + 0.11s ≤ 4x. Subtracting x from each part of this inequality yields 2x ≤ 0.11s ≤ 3x. Dividing each part of this inequality by 0.11 yields (2/0.11)x ≤ s ≤ (3/0.11)x. Therefore, the inequality (2/0.11)x ≤ s ≤ (3/0.11)x represents all possible values of total sales s, in dollars, the salesperson can make this year in order to meet their goal."
  },
  {
    "id": 792,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A psychologist set up an experiment to study the tendency of a person to select the first item when presented with a series of items. In the experiment, 300 people were presented with a set of five pictures arranged in random order. Each person was asked to choose the most appealing picture. Of the first 150 participants, 36 chose the first picture in the set. Among the remaining 150 participants, p people chose the first picture in the set. If more than 20% of all participants chose the first picture in the set, which of the following inequalities best describes the possible values of p?",
    "answer": "p + 36 > 0.20(300), where p ≤ 150",
    "explanation": "Of the first 150 participants, 36 chose the first picture in the set, and of the 150 remaining participants, p chose the first picture in the set. Hence, the proportion of the participants who chose the first picture in the set is (36 + p)/300. Since more than 20% of all the participants chose the first picture, it follows that (36 + p)/300 > 0.20. This inequality can be rewritten as p + 36 > 0.20(300). Since p is a number of people among the remaining 150 participants, p ≤ 150."
  },
  {
    "id": 793,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A small business owner budgets $2,200 to purchase candles. The owner must purchase a minimum of 200 candles to maintain the discounted pricing. If the owner pays $4.90 per candle to purchase small candles and $11.60 per candle to purchase large candles, what is the maximum number of large candles the owner can purchase to stay within the budget and maintain the discounted pricing?",
    "answer": "182",
    "explanation": "Let s represent the number of small candles the owner can purchase, and let l represent the number of large candles the owner can purchase. It’s given that the owner pays $4.90 per candle to purchase small candles and $11.60 per candle to purchase large candles. Therefore, the owner pays 4.90s dollars for s small candles and 11.60l dollars for l large candles, which means the owner pays a total of 4.90s + 11.60l dollars to purchase candles. It’s given that the owner budgets $2,200 to purchase candles. Therefore, 4.90s + 11.60l ≤ 2,200. It’s also given that the owner must purchase a minimum of 200 candles. Therefore, s + l ≥ 200. The inequalities 4.90s + 11.60l ≤ 2,200 and s + l ≥ 200 can be combined into one compound inequality by rewriting the second inequality so that its left-hand side is equivalent to the left-hand side of the first inequality. Subtracting l from both sides of the inequality s + l ≥ 200 yields s ≥ 200 - l. Multiplying both sides of this inequality by 4.90 yields 4.90s ≥ 4.90(200 - l), or 4.90s ≥ 980 - 4.90l. Adding 11.60l to both sides of this inequality yields 4.90s + 11.60l ≥ 980 - 4.90l + 11.60l, or 4.90s + 11.60l ≥ 980 + 6.70l. This inequality can be combined with the inequality 4.90s + 11.60l ≤ 2,200, which yields the compound inequality 980 + 6.70l ≤ 4.90s + 11.60l ≤ 2,200. It follows that 980 + 6.70l ≤ 2,200. Subtracting 980 from both sides of this inequality yields 6.70l ≤ 2,200 - 980. Dividing both sides of this inequality by 6.70 yields approximately l ≤ 182.09. Since the number of large candles the owner purchases must be a whole number, the maximum number of large candles the owner can purchase is the largest whole number less than 182.09, which is 182."
  },
  {
    "id": 794,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A business owner plans to purchase the same model of chair for each of the 81 employees. The total budget to spend on these chairs is $14,000, which includes a 7% sales tax. Which of the following is closest to the maximum possible price per chair, before sales tax, the business owner could pay based on this budget?",
    "answer": "161.53",
    "explanation": "It’s given that a business owner plans to purchase 81 chairs. If p is the price per chair, the total price of purchasing 81 chairs is 81p. It’s also given that 7% sales tax is included, which is equivalent to 81p multiplied by 1.07, or 81(1.07)p. Since the total budget is $14,000, the inequality representing the situation is given by 81(1.07)p ≤ 14,000. Dividing both sides of this inequality by 81(1.07) and rounding the result to two decimal places gives p ≤ 161.53. To not exceed the budget, the maximum possible price per chair is $161.53."
  },
  {
    "id": 795,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "A shipping service restricts the dimensions of the boxes it will ship for a certain type of service. The restriction states that for boxes shaped like rectangular prisms, the sum of the perimeter of the base of the box and the height of the box cannot exceed 130 inches. The perimeter of the base is determined using the width and length of the box. If a box has a height of 60 inches and its length is 2.5 times the width, which inequality shows the allowable width x, in inches, of the box?",
    "answer": "0 < x ≤ 10",
    "explanation": "If x is the width, in inches, of the box, then the length of the box is 2.5x inches. It follows that the perimeter of the base is 2(2.5x + x), or 7x inches. The height of the box is given to be 60 inches. According to the restriction, the sum of the perimeter of the base and the height of the box should not exceed 130 inches. Algebraically, this can be represented by 7x + 60 ≤ 130, or 7x ≤ 70. Dividing both sides of the inequality by 7 gives x ≤ 10. Since x represents the width of the box, x must also be a positive number. Therefore, the inequality 0 < x ≤ 10 represents all the allowable values of x that satisfy the given conditions."
  },
  {
    "id": 796,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "The formula above is Ohm’s law for an electric circuit with current I, in amperes, potential difference V, in volts, and resistance R, in ohms. A circuit has a resistance of 500 ohms, and its potential difference will be generated by n six-volt batteries that produce a total potential difference of 6n volts. If the circuit is to have a current of no more than 0.25 ampere, what is the greatest number, n, of six-volt batteries that can be used?",
    "answer": "20",
    "explanation": "For the given circuit, the resistance R is 500 ohms, and the total potential difference V generated by n batteries is 6n volts. It’s also given that the circuit is to have a current of no more than 0.25 ampere, which can be expressed as I < 0.25. Since Ohm’s law says that I = V/R, the given values for V and R can be substituted for I in this inequality, which yields 6n/500 < 0.25. Multiplying both sides of this inequality by 500 yields 6n < 125, and dividing both sides of this inequality by 6 yields n < 20.833. Since the number of batteries must be a whole number less than 20.833, the greatest number of batteries that can be used in this circuit is 20."
  },
  {
    "id": 797,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "The triangle inequality theorem states that the sum of any two sides of a triangle must be greater than the length of the third side. If a triangle has side lengths of 6 and 12, which inequality represents the possible lengths, x, of the third side of the triangle?",
    "answer": "6 < x < 18",
    "explanation": "It’s given that a triangle has side lengths of 6 and 12, and x represents the length of the third side of the triangle. It’s also given that the triangle inequality theorem states that the sum of any two sides of a triangle must be greater than the length of the third side. Therefore, the inequalities 6 + x > 12, 6 + 12 > x, and 12 + x > 6 represent all possible values of x. Subtracting 6 from both sides of the inequality 6 + x > 12 yields x > 12 - 6, or x > 6. Adding 6 and 12 in the inequality 6 + 12 > x yields 18 > x, or x < 18. Subtracting 12 from both sides of the inequality 12 + x > 6 yields x > 6 - 12, or x > -6. Since all x-values that satisfy the inequality x > 6 also satisfy the inequality x > -6, it follows that the inequalities x > 6 and x < 18 represent the possible values of x. Therefore, the inequality 6 < x < 18 represents the possible lengths, x, of the third side of the triangle."
  },
  {
    "id": 798,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "y > 2x - 1, 2x > 5 Which of the following consists of the y-coordinates of all the points that satisfy the system of inequalities above?",
    "answer": "y > 4",
    "explanation": "Subtracting the same number from each side of an inequality gives an equivalent inequality. Hence, subtracting 1 from each side of the inequality 2x > 5 gives 2x - 1 > 4. So the given system of inequalities is equivalent to the system of inequalities y > 2x - 1 and 2x - 1 > 4, which can be rewritten as y > 2x - 1 > 4. Using the transitive property of inequalities, it follows that y > 4."
  },
  {
    "id": 799,
    "domain": "Algebra",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "skill": "Linear inequalities in one or two variables",
    "question": "Ken is working this summer as part of a crew on a farm. He earned $8 per hour for the first 10 hours he worked this week. Because of his performance, his crew leader raised his salary to $10 per hour for the rest of the week. Ken saves 90% of his earnings from each week. What is the least number of hours he must work the rest of the week to save at least $270 for the week?",
    "answer": "22",
    "explanation": "Ken earned $8 per hour for the first 10 hours he worked, so he earned a total of $80 for the first 10 hours he worked. For the rest of the week, Ken was paid at the rate of $10 per hour. Let x be the number of hours he will work for the rest of the week. The total of Ken’s earnings, in dollars, for the week will be 10x + 80. He saves 90% of his earnings each week, so this week he will save 0.9(10x + 80) dollars. The inequality 0.9(10x + 80) ≥ 270 represents the condition that he will save at least $270 for the week. Factoring 10 out of the expression 10x + 80 gives 10(x + 8). The product of 10 and 0.9 is 9, so the inequality can be rewritten as 9(x + 8) ≥ 270. Dividing both sides of this inequality by 9 yields x + 8 ≥ 30, so x ≥ 22. Therefore, the least number of hours Ken must work the rest of the week to save at least $270 for the week is 22."
  }
]